Mayank: I don't think they would, so let's start.
Mayank: Yes.
Mayank: Great, so I think we should be good to begin. What's the agenda we are going to understand about?
Mayank: all the things… Which has already kind of been…
Mayank: Like, you know, complicated. But anyways, let's start, so let me close the other tabs.
Mayank: So, we covered on the video audio generation yesterday.
Mayank: Cool.
Mayank: Thanks.
Mayank: Anyone would like to see how we mastered AI yesterday?
Mayank: So let me show you one of the songs that you created.
Audio shared by Mayank: Subaru.
Mayank: Nicol.
Audio shared by Mayank: We're in business.
Audio shared by Mayank: Ciao e qui pealiza da caca la dono nece muerang te me peati, ciao se ho…
Mayank: Great. So, let's then begin, everyone. So, yesterday, we did discuss about Pydantic, and I think we have covered the same in lots of depth. So, let me quickly help you revise the same. And one more thing, so…
Mayank: If all of you remember, So, I have given you these links yesterday, everyone.
Mayank: So just let me quickly open craft as well at my end. So just quickly.
Mayank: Yeah, so that was the AI-generated song, I taught that yesterday.
Mayank: So now, when I go to class 3 pedantic and Agentic AI basics.
Mayank: So, first thing, I have fixed each and everything in here, if you will see, so that class thing and issue is kind of been fixed, okay? That actually came up because…
Mayank: Like, there was something like classes also there in HTML versus we were trying to write classes in code as well, so that was the reason everyone, the reason it came up. So yesterday we discussed, I think, a lot in depth about Pydantic. Now, some people are saying that they are not able to open the link.
Mayank: I'm sharing this home link, okay? Try to open this, and it will surely get open, okay? For anyone who is saying that, hey, we missed out on the recordings on yesterday's class, well, on the yesterday's class, or this is my… you will be able to follow.
Mayank: But again, highly suggested.
Mayank: to please be active, okay? We are going to discuss about how to create agents in Python today, and around the AI call and everything, as well as on the topics, overall. So, this link will get open in every browser and everything, if you are directly trying to open this.
Mayank: It should also get open, to be very honest, okay? So just try to see this, and let me know.
Mayank: Now, unless you're on an office laptop, This will also open.
Mayank: Let's quickly understand. So we discussed about Pydantic and how it is helpful. What is the use case of Pydantic? The use case comes up because there is no way of doing type or data validation in Python. For the same, we learned that how there is a base model on top of which we can define our class.
Mayank: Class is then used to make sure that we are able to generate any type of object, right? So if I want to now generate user model, rather than it being a simple class, I will use this approach overall, okay? Then, of course, creating instances, cohesions, required versus optional.
Mayank: And serialization of model dumping and everything. So let me quickly go down then. Then field constraints and custom validators. We understood that how we can have fields like this, where we can tell it should be GT greater than or less than equal to.
Mayank: Then, along with that, everyone, just give me a minute.
Mayank: Yeah, then along with that, we understood two ways. So, now, many people write like this, annotated way of doing this, versus the earlier way, right? So, should be not a problem.
Mayank: Then a few of the special types built in, just like email string, secret string, any URL or HTTP URL. Then I told you that how you can easily just go
Mayank: on any AI and ask that, hey, what are the other built-in types in Pydantic? Or, if you want, I think you can just go on Pydantic.
Mayank: built in validators.
Mayank: This will give you the Pythonic official documentation, so I am very…
Mayank: Happy to read the documentation.
Mayank: If in case you are not, then you can ask AI for the same, but I feel that you should know how to read documentation, because AI is also giving after that.
Mayank: Now, again, after that, we understood that if, in case, Amy…
Mayank: validation which I have to do on data, right? If that is not covered by my
Mayank: Overall, Pydantic, and that would be the case a lot, how we discussed about the Infosys and that logic.
Mayank: All the code and everything, again, is properly, properly mentioned and given here.
Mayank: I think I've given the same on… GitHub as well.
Mayank: And on this collab as well, everyone, all the code is given. So if you will go and see, everything which we have done is given from scratch on here.
Mayank: Then next, after understanding this, we went on to understand the model validator as well. Coming to model validator majorly, the whole idea becomes that how you can handle or access multiple fields because till field validator.
Mayank: Only a single field was being accessible.
Mayank: This mode was left, which I will explain after today's class, like, after half of today's class. But overall, then you can do these questions, etc.
Mayank: And last was around the computed field, which we discussed around the computed field. And how can we compute the field of the go? Then on the nested models.
Mayank: That how there can be models within a model. And then these are some advanced things which you can read about, honestly, okay? But I will cover them in future when we will be using them directly. So this was the first part, everyone.
Mayank: Second was this awesome, awesome link.
Mayank: Where we were discussing about the different, different technologies. So, the number one is large language model, which I think we kind of discussed yesterday. So, I think we should be good with that.
Mayank: Right?
Mayank: So, anyone has any issues before I move forward?
Mayank: Let me know quickly.
Mayank: All good?
Mayank: Decorators, you know all of them. How do you remember? I don't know all of them. I genuinely either search or see how we have to use it. Okay, everyone, let me
Mayank: Tell you one thing, it should be very, very straightforward and clear to you.
Mayank: You never remember code.
Mayank: Okay?
Mayank: What do you never remember?
Mayank: Code.
Mayank: Like, I don't remember code ever.
Mayank: Syntax, etc, I also see…
Mayank: Thanks to AI now, it's very, very simple, okay? To be very honest, thanks to AI now, it's very, very simple.
Mayank: you never remember the code, you just understand the concepts, okay? Cool, so I think then we can move forward, everyone, without wasting the time, right?
Mayank: We have to make sure that, We are…
Mayank: Just give me a minute.
Mayank: We are now masking them, so… just a second, okay, let me just open… yeah, cool. So, now when we talk about this, everyone, we discussed around the large language model, and I told you that how large language model… and I will do one more thing, so let me move it to a new window.
Mayank: Okay, let me go back.
Mayank: Thank you, Pinto.
Mayank: Beautiful. Thank you.
Mayank: Cool. So, we were discussing this thing.
Mayank: And I think, yeah.
Mayank: We are here. So let me quickly just start with this terms quickly. And first one and a half hours, we will cover these terms.
Mayank: large language models.
Mayank: Look at the chart, apparently.
Mayank: Great. Can you add some practice question as well in the website, like for field validators, so that we can practice? A bit of honesty, I would not like that you practice pedantic question, to be very honest. Okay, so in that case, it would be much better that you don't practice it. That should be done.
Mayank: Good.
Mayank: Shalom. Let's now move forward, everyone. So, again, the link and everything is exactly the same. All the links and everything, you know that where you will get.
Mayank: If you're an office laptop, these links will not work. Extremely sorry. But I don't think any solution is there because Netlify is a trusted source. Craft.do, it's also a trusted source. There is nothing wrong in those websites. So it should work. Like, I cannot think of anything.
Mayank: Let me still check, mail to me once, or maybe I will save it and try to see, okay? So, Farang, yes, if it is not working, the craft link.
Mayank: Can you please try to open the same on your personal laptop? It will surely work, okay? Are you able to access all the links which I'm giving you with respect to Kraft and Netlify?
Mayank: Because lots of them will be coming in future, so that you can learn a lot yourself.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: Great.
Mayank: Cool. Both are trusted. HTTPS source.
Mayank: And the benefit which I get with Kraft is this thing, that I can add any file, any link.
Mayank: And it shows. So that is why I go with it, not with any Google Doc or something, because then I will not be able to provide you any file, etc, like this, right? Any screenshot, any file. So that is the whole problem. Office laptop will block. Again, I told in the starting that why or how. Office laptop is not the right way, okay? So look.
Mayank: Let's quickly, quickly revise everyone. Large language model, I told you, and this is a very, very good thing for that.
Mayank: It's like a friend who has read every book, every website, every conversation ever published, but nobody ever explained to them without any of it means.
Mayank: They have simply seen the phrase. Abhinav, can you please stop? Like, okay, okay, let's see. Everyone, for the next 15 minutes, I will teach, okay? I think all the links I have given you already.
Mayank: Each and everything is there.
Mayank: Don't spam the chat, that's the first thing. Second, if you will go in here, all the links are present. I think that all of you are now smart, this much smart, that you can go in here, see that we are in the class 3 or class 4,
Mayank: And we have all the links in here, right?
Mayank: So please stop spamming the chat, and please make sure that if I've given you one link where all the links are present, you are in the habit of accessing it, rather than me asking, what is this link? Give me this link.
Mayank: I think we all are that smart. Yes or no, everyone?
Mayank: Are we that smart that we can easily, easily just go and see the same?
Mayank: Great. Now I want that all of you study properly, properly focus on studying.
Mayank: People are asking questions regarding what is the difference between Agentic AI engineer and AI engineer. I will not tell it right now.
Mayank: Okay? Please, please focus. Great.
Mayank: Now, let's quickly jump back to large language model, everyone. This very, very awesome definition kind of sums it up.
Mayank: And, as I told yesterday as well.
Mayank: What I'm going to do, I'm going to just make sure that I give you an overview of these terms. We are going to master these terms in depth over the course.
Mayank: But…
Mayank: It is actually just an overview so that no matter from which background you are, no matter if it has been 10 years, 15 years, 20 years of experience, no matter that you last touched coding five years back.
Mayank: When you are in a meeting room, when you are in a corporate event, when you are talking with someone.
Mayank: Or normally as well, when you are discussing something and let's say try to read something around AI.
Mayank: You would understand that, okay, what exactly these terms are.
Mayank: Because…
Mayank: I don't feel that to learn these terms, which will happen gradually over the 3-4 months, like all the terms which we will master.
Mayank: You need to unnecessarily wait.
Mayank: And of course, on top of that.
Mayank: It is very, very important that all these terms should be clear or known to you. So that is the whole idea, not that.
Mayank: This is how we are going to just cover RAG. So don't worry, we are going to cover RAG in a lot of depth.
Mayank: But in here, I just need to give you an idea so you're not afraid of any of these things.
Mayank: Now, let's understand again. Large Diamond Mojo, we discussed yesterday.
Mayank: And I told you that how ChatGPT,
Mayank: is the best example. Now, you will see that whenever I am explaining you about AI, I will always, I always refer to ChatGPT. There is a line which I always write.
Mayank: ChatGPT is to AI what Google is to Internet. So even though Claude and other AIs are getting a lot famous and everything today, we all know that it was all started with ChatGPT. And we all, many people must have not used Claude.
Mayank: But ChatGPT, for sure, each and every one of us have used, okay?
Mayank: The best part? It doesn't matter.
Mayank: Concept-wise, ChatGPT, Claude, Gemini, All of them are nothing but your LLM models, okay?
Mayank: So… now… We can… Easily give it an input.
Mayank: And by predicting the next token or word, it gives us with the
Mayank: Output. So, simple, simple thing. Where output is nothing but next, token predictor.
Mayank: So, this is the whole idea, everyone. Now, I remember that many people were getting
Mayank: confused on this word, which is token, which is our next word in the chain. So, large language model, which has been trained and have all the understanding, each and everything.
Mayank: Ask a model the capital of France is.
Mayank: And it isn't looking up a fact in a table.
Mayank: It's calculating that Paris is, by an enormous margin, the most statistically likely next word given everything it's ever read. So when you ask it these things.
Mayank: And this is the reason many LLMs are bad in calculation, because now we have provided them with tools, which I will also clear in a bit.
Mayank: But by design, They are just…
Mayank: Trying to predict the next word based on their training, so if you see any biases.
Mayank: any languages, any issues, and I think I showed that yesterday when I asked you if I say Virat, what is the next word which comes into your mind? And I can actually kind of maybe showcase this as well, let me check if this works.
Mayank: So, let me say Virat.
Mayank: And see.
Mayank: It was very, very fast, that's the very first thing.
Mayank: And it kind of understood that, hey, I might be referring to Virat K
Mayank: Now, this is happening, not because your LLM is very smart, it can read your mind, no.
Mayank: The reason is the way it has been trained.
Mayank: The way it has been trained.
Mayank: It is just trying to follow the patterns. So, if we do something wrong, it will also do something wrong, okay? So, with that, let's move forward.
Mayank: And let's move on to the next one, everyone.
Mayank: The second term is token.
Mayank: When we talk with our AI, whenever we are talking with our AI,
Mayank: It tries to understand the input and output in terms of tokens, not in terms of words. So, I can show you the same again. If we go…
Mayank: There is a tokenizer.
Mayank: Tokenizer.
Mayank: From?
Mayank: OpenAI.
Mayank: When you enter anything in here, let's take an example from the document only.
Mayank: So, unbelievable things happen.
Mayank: It is 5 tokens. As we are able to see, unbelievable things happen. So, 5 tokens
Mayank: Are kind of being going inside.
Mayank: And let me make it a little bit more clear to you.
Mayank: When we say as LLM, right?
Mayank: When we see us.
Mayank: LLM, because everything will run around a LLM only, so let me make that thing up.
Mayank: Let me dig this diagram, okay?
Mayank: So… As of now, your LLM has been trained.
Mayank: Now, it breaks the same on basis of some algorithm. Now, these tokenization and everything, they are basics of NLP, so if you're interested in what are the different algorithms, no, no, tell me everything.
Mayank: Well, no worries. You can read about it. You can ask my GPT as well.
Mayank: But, for the timing, what I want you to understand is that Tokens are divided.
Mayank: Sorry, words are divided into tokens.
Mayank: And AI.
Mayank: Just understand this token stuff. So now when you give it this particular thing.
Mayank: And let me take a screenshot of this awesome thing, so that you can understand.
Mayank: Now, when you give it this.
Mayank: The input will be 5 tokens, so in here, everyone.
Mayank: Input is 5 tokens.
Mayank: And output can be anything, but it 2 will be.
Mayank: buy tokens. So, that is just a basic, basic idea, and I discussed, and yesterday I kind of explained that how
Mayank: Always.
Mayank: Output tokens would be Expensive.
Mayank: Then, input tokens.
Mayank: I hope this thing is also clear to each and every one of you.
Mayank: This thing is also clear to each and every one of you, like the output. How many of you are clear on this thing?
Mayank: Good.
Mayank: So…
Mayank: Now, many people are asking me what is the algorithm and all these things. They are inbuilt. There are many algorithms, like GPD 5.x and O1x3.
Mayank: So, this is something which they are using. So, again, CGPT3, it was 6 tokens.
Mayank: It is 5 tokens, it is 5 tokens, so there are these algorithms which are already made, you don't have to worry about them, okay? They are not… you don't have to worry about
Mayank: both input and output tokens are charged, which I will show you separately in a bit, that how exactly are they charged and everything, okay? That will be very, very easy to showcase via a much better approach. So, with respect to that.
Mayank: I also told you that how tokens are the currency, because we are charged based on input and output tokens. So, if I go on chat GPT models.
Mayank: And I go to models.
Mayank: let me pick up and show you this GPT 5.5 model. So, this is a model inside ChatGPT, everyone.
Mayank: Not the ChatGPT web, so that I will also clear up ChatGPT web and ChatGPT API.
Mayank: it is having $5 input tokens per million, and $1.30 of per output tokens, okay? So, if you give it 1 million token.
Mayank: It will charge you $5.
Mayank: If you give it… if it gives you 1 million tokens out, it will charge you $1.30.
Mayank: So, again, let me just make it as a ChatGPT icon.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: And… I would just quickly… Copy this magazine.
Mayank: And this is ChatGPT.
Mayank: 5.5 monetizing.
Mayank: As we can see here, Output?
Mayank: Output pricing.
Mayank: Rising.
Mayank: is… 6 times the… input.
Mayank: And you will see that how, if I go back, everyone.
Mayank: In all of them, output price is more. It is per million tokens. So.
Mayank: If it gives you a million tokens, this is the charge which it will basically give you.
Mayank: So, the reason is very, very simple, I discussed that yesterday as well.
Mayank: When I say… so let me open a new chat.
Mayank: When I say hi, Hello?
Mayank: How are you?
Mayank: Can you tell me… Or give me.
Mayank: Reply in same number of words.
Mayank: Or let me say, tokens, or words.
Mayank: As my reply, as my input.
Mayank: So, in here, everyone, what I'm doing, pay a lot of attention
Mayank: I am asking ChatGPT that, hey, can you give me reply in same number of tokens or word as my input? So I hope all of you understand that how output and input token now will be same.
Mayank: Yes or no?
Mayank: Great.
Mayank: Now, do you think that ChatGPT will have to spend some effort? So, if I'm sending it 10 tokens, just as an example, if I'm sending it 10 tok
Mayank: For the 10 tokens which ChatGPT will give me, it might have to think hard.
Mayank: So there is a thinking mode in ChatGPT, so let me do this thinking.
Mayank: Right?
Mayank: Do you think that it will have to spend some energy?
Mayank: Or not.
Mayank: Right? So, don't you think that, of course, it would be higher?
Mayank: Don't you think that by that virtue signaling only that it should be higher, that if it is actually
Mayank: Spending a effort.
Mayank: Right? If it is actually spending an effort. So, I'm saying to you that, hey.
Mayank: So let's take it like this. I'm saying that, hey, let's both of us talk in 10 words.
Mayank: When I say 10 words, you are listening those 10 words. Your brain is processing that and then giving out the answer. So don't you think that everyone saying the 10 words.
Mayank: Plus… That energy.
Mayank: That is something which will be charged. Processing fee or anything, you can think about it.
Mayank: Now, the second I give it, it thinned and then gave me an answer.
Mayank: So…
Mayank: If you will see, it is exactly the same, but this will be charged more. This will always and always be charged more, okay?
Mayank: So, in that case, everyone, the whole idea becomes that, yes, anytime we discuss about tokens.
Mayank: Output orders will be more, that's the very first thing. And next very important thing.
Mayank: Tokens are currency of Yeah, yeah.
Mayank: So, now, if you think about this, and I gave an awesome example of talk time yesterday in this, that more you talk, right.
Mayank: The more expensive it will get, and this is the reason if you keep on chatting with ChatGPT or Claude.
Mayank: after some time, they gives you an error. And I will prove it very, very nicely, because this is a very important concept. If I go on my plot, there is an awesome, awesome… this thing which it shows.
Mayank: If I start up a new chat, let me start it up in incognito mode, okay?
Mayank: You will see that how it is saying that, hey man, in this session, you can use 3 million tokens.
Mayank: So, the second I said hi.
Mayank: The second I said hi, pay attention.
Mayank: Some 4,000 tokens kind of got used.
Mayank: And I used around 1% of my… roughly 1% of my limit.
Mayank: Because each and everything in here will be kind of measured in tokens only.
Mayank: So basically, just like how money is our thing, tokens are all the things. Okay, but yesterday you said input token cost more, right? I would have never said that, Sai.
Mayank: That would never be the case.
Mayank: Always and always, output tokens will cost more. Input tokens. For the same number of tokens.
Mayank: Output will always be high, and I've given you the logic as well.
Mayank: I have given you the logic as well, okay?
Mayank: Because it has to think.
Mayank: And then give you the answer. So, just tell me this thing.
Mayank: Again.
Mayank: Whenever I'm giving it an input, it gives you an output which is a lot smarter, which it has to put the brain and everything. So that is the reason, everyone.
Mayank: That it is required, okay? So, let's move forward, and I will prove it a little bit more in depth, so don't worry on that.
Mayank: Next comes in vector or embedding everyone. This thing is totally, totally free of your LLM or anything. So let me ask you this thing.
Mayank: Vector has nothing to do with LLMs.
Mayank: Okay? Let me repeat this line.
Mayank: Like, again, from a very high side.
Mayank: Vector has nothing.
Mayank: to do with AI, okay? It's a normal technology, it's a normal thing.
Mayank: Token or anything doesn't have a role to play here. I hope I'm clear on this, everyone.
Mayank: Because many people were having this doubt.
Mayank: Victor has nothing to do with AI as such.
Mayank: If I give you a word.
Mayank: You could change that word into some mathematical numbers.
Mayank: And then, you could just try to have that word Somewhere on a graph.
Mayank: So no AI, nothing is coming into picture as of now here.
Mayank: I hope that makes a lot of sense, what I just said.
Mayank: Right?
Mayank: There are different, different vector or embedding models. It is a concept of NLP again, if you actually search.
Mayank: Vector Embedding, NLP.
Mayank: Like, again, before all these things.
Mayank: So, vector embeddings are numerical representation of text.
Mayank: Word, sentence, or document that captures semantic meaning. So before AI as well, this was present. So I think you can think of it, right, everyone? I hope all of you can understand the same then.
Mayank: That before AI as well, this was created.
Mayank: So, embeddings, or vector embeddings, I know that there will be some good image. Pay attention. Yeah.
Mayank: See, this is a very good example, like, again, because people have moved to AI unnecessarily, but this is how it happens.
Mayank: There is some algorithm, some logic, you don't have to worry about that. You give it a word, it gives you some numbers. Because again, we cannot work with words. Computers only understand maths.
Mayank: Then you can think that how it can be used to create these words, sorry, these embeddings.
Mayank: Telling which are nearer to which. For example, football, golf, and tennis, it is nearer to one another because our vector embedding model says so.
Mayank: If the model will be bad, it can give it randomly as well. If the model will be good, it will give it very close to each other, the words which are actually close to each other. So I hope this also makes a lot of sense, everyone. Yes or no?
Mayank: Right?
Mayank: And many people are asking them, vectors are after scalar and all these things. Well, that is the reason. There was a prerequisite in this course, okay? That was the reason. So now, if you have not done that prerequisite, or if you have never heard, because
Mayank: I have seen so many people, what they do, and again, totally not anything or not on them, I always love to understand things in depth.
Mayank: So… Normally, they will have zero knowledge.
Mayank: But if they want to now learn something, suddenly they would say that I now want to learn complete 100%. Okay, don't give me a shortcut.
Mayank: I want to learn complete 100%. Well, there is no problem in that, just that in this course, my main idea is to teach you the practical side of things more. Plus, these are kind of the prerequisite, and already kind of done, so these all things take easily around 2-3 months to cover.
Mayank: But I think that you don't need to actually master them, okay? So, in here, even if you will see.
Mayank: In here, if you will see, each and every word can be given some mathematical number.
Mayank: And it depends on this model. So if your model will be bad, it will give any number. So I can have a model which is very, very bad, which gives the same thing to every number. So 111. Then it's a
Mayank: Bad model.
Mayank: If, on the other hand, my model is very, very smart, it will give different and very far off numbers to the words so that the closer ones are actually the ones which are close in meaning as well. Clear, everyone?
Mayank: I hope this thing is clear.
Mayank: So, vectorization of words, it's a basic concept in NLP, nothing to do with AI and everything. It is used in AI, because NLP is the basic of AI.
Mayank: So that is the whole idea with vectorization, everyone. Same kind of a thing I have mentioned here. Once text is broken into tokens, okay, now you can just think that, okay, word and tokens can be used very interchangeably in the world of AI.
Mayank: Each one gets converted into long list of numbers, a vector. That captured its meaning as a location in space.
Mayank: Word that means similar thing end up in near each other in that space.
Mayank: Unrelated word and a far apart. So I hope this thing is clear to each and every one of you.
Mayank: That you are just… You are just…
Mayank: Providing numbers to your words. Genuinely, you are doing this thing. First, is this image clear to each and every one of you? Forget everything. Is this image clear?
Mayank: Right?
Mayank: Now, many people are asking me, how will you know a model is good or bad? Well, I will try to see if it is giving
Mayank: Apple or banana, if it is giving very close to them.
Mayank: then it is better. If it is not, then it's a very bad thing. So I will take up some examples and test the same out, okay?
Mayank: So now there are lots of embedding models, everyone, which we actually now use in RAG, et cetera, as well. But for the time being, you just have to understand the process of vectorization of thing.
Mayank: And this is a very good definition. And this is the exact definition which I'm referring to.
Mayank: In AI, of course, it is getting a lot further used, which we will talk about, but for the time being.
Mayank: The vectorization which I am talking to… talking about, sorry.
Mayank: This is the exact one here.
Mayank: Numerical representation of words, or text.
Mayank: And they are mapped so that we can understand the same.
Mayank: And in future, of course, they are helpful. Rather, they are very helpful in training our models as well. So the reason it is important
Mayank: We would see RAG where this kind of an approach is followed.
Mayank: So, it is, like, the basics of that
Mayank: Plus, in training of your models also, this thing is very, very important, okay?
Mayank: So, great, now let's move forward.
Mayank: And let's see the next topic, everyone, which is context window. Now, on top of that, I think all of you would remember that I showed you yesterday
Mayank: This very good diagram.
Mayank: Embedding projector.
Mayank: So, all it is having, everyone.
Mayank: No AI, nothing, it is just showing you that, hey, this is how I'm having it here. So in the being part, see all these things which are near to it?
Mayank: And I can select any word. Magic. So, magical is near to it, gathering is near to it.
Mayank: dark, occult, all of these things are near to it, okay? Now, don't confuse these things as of now. As I said, if your basics are not clear, just listen to me and I will clear these things out.
Mayank: Just vectorization is just this process, which is helpful in training of AI and AI concept as well.
Mayank: Let's move forward to the next one.
Mayank: Which is context window.
Mayank: Okay? This is very, very important. Okay?
Mayank: Cool. So, 2 minutes late for me.
Mayank: Quick doubts, if anyone has any?
Mayank: The ingestion matrix is used to see if words are closed or not. You can Okay.
Mayank: I'm having a cursor plan for $20, but when I see usage, it's multiple millions of tokens that I will explain, don
Mayank: Are we using GitHub Copilot and Claude and provide access to company Git repo and generating code? No, that would not be the case. Is there that these LLM brain taking out all these code across companies and saving in kind of central repository? Let me clear it out, okay?
Mayank: Why input tokens are charged? Why would they not be?
Mayank: When you were in a call.
Mayank: It used to get charged, right? If you're giving a PDF to ChatGPT as an input, it will charge you.
Mayank: These are query to LLM converts into vector.
Mayank: Oh!
Mayank: Like, it's a different process, but not really. Then, it is where, actually, your transformer architecture comes into picture.
Mayank: So that is the case, okay? What is the difference between vector and embedding? Ideally, nothing, because that is the reason they are written in vector and embedding.
Mayank: So, if you're thinking of embedding of RAG, hold your horses, because that is different. My token size is not always the same.
Mayank: Didn't get it. Like, what is the question? Okay.
Mayank: Could you please explain the content size too? I will come to that, don't worry. Are LLM model and embedding model the same? No, they are not
Mayank: What is cosine similarity where it is used? A very good question for my GPT. Please go and ask to it. It is just used to check that if two things are nearer to each other or not. We check them by cosine similarity. Okay.
Mayank: How did you use 30,000 tokens when high should be 1 token? That I will also explain, Roshan. I think I already ping
Mayank: Any other main thing?
Mayank: Name equal to main, I will explain when we will be deep into coding, don't worry.
Mayank: So, in an interview, Will they allow us to use?
Mayank: To Google syntax? More or less, yes. Today's world, I don't think anyone will be charging you on the part of that. But anyway, still, you don't have to understand, remember coding, okay? You don't have to understand coding. Sorry, remember the code.
Mayank: Best embedding model, depending on the use case, there is nothing nor never the best thing.
Mayank: Okay, this is a good one for LLM visualization. But this will be very… so I know this thing, Ashutosh, but it will be very, very difficult, right?
Mayank: Well, let's think about it. This is actually very difficult. This is, transformer architecture, so I have a better diagram.
Mayank: This is good, but very, very difficult.
Mayank: Audience is there, so they have little less idea. So let me make it in that manner, okay? But yeah, thanks for it.
Mayank: You know.
Mayank: Cool, let's jump onto context, everyone.
Mayank: Let's jump onto context. If you are not able to copy the URL for the…
Mayank: Thousand time, I believe, right?
Mayank: For the thousandth time, this is the URL, master of all URL, where you will find every URL, okay?
Mayank: So please make sure that you do this. Let's move forward now.
Mayank: And I will do… Common AI… Doves?
Mayank: Now, if you don't know these terms, and if I start with AI, it will be a grave mistake at my end. Grave, grave mistake. So that's why I want to make things clear.
Mayank: Now, for the next 15 minutes, I want all of you to focus a lot.
Mayank: For the next 15 minutes, I want all of you to focus.
Mayank: Can you write in the chat what I want all of you to do?
Mayank: Can you write in the chat? Also, there are many questions which are very basic. People are asking me what is the best AI model and all these things.
Mayank: Believe me, this is the reason I've given you access to MindGP
Mayank: Because, of course, many people are asking totally questions which are a little bit out of scope of what we are covering, but no worries.
Mayank: I highly, highly suggest that you go and
Mayank: ask this question to my GPT. This person is very good in that. If not, you know that how I wait till the very end. Like, I'm closing your dog for 3-3 hours.
Mayank: It's just that I don't want to disturb the flow of the class. Cool? So let's move forward.
Mayank: Great! So, now let me make things clear to you.
Mayank: Which is going to be very, very helpful again, and just let me give you a link as well, because that's a very, very awesome
Mayank: So, mint handling these links are very, very difficult, but then it helps all of you to teach.
Mayank: Surya, Harija, copy from chat is disabled by Zoom only, so extremely sorry for that, but I have given you a link where all the links are given, so please open that, okay?
Mayank: Channel.
Mayank: Next topic is something which is very, very important again, everyone, which is something which is known as,
Mayank: context window, okay? So, overall, in a very simple sense, the definition is pretty good, but again, since I want my students to be very smart.
Mayank: And at least their basic should always be right.
Mayank: First, let's try to see this.
Mayank: Everything a model can see at once, your message, its own earlier replies, any document you have shared, has a hard limit.
Mayank: Once that limit is hit, the oldest content quietly falls off to make room for new content.
Mayank: Just like how you have 3 hours of context window, just as an example I'm taking.
Mayank: Anything beyond that 3 hours, you will…
Mayank: Kind of forget the first thing which we do.
Mayank: So, like the whiteboard, everyone, but let's see this. Still, I will make it more clear.
Mayank: So your AI, let's say, for example, can remember 5 messages.
Mayank: After that, if we move forward, the message will kept go on anything. Is this very basic idea? Clear the whiteboard analogy and everything.
Mayank: Is this very basic idea clear?
Mayank: Cool, cool, cool. Now, though this thing should be clear to many of you, but let me ask this thing.
Mayank: And I know so many people will make a mistake in here, but if you make a mistake in here, I cannot teach you LangChain LangGraph, because it will be like I'm making you
Mayank: So, advanced things before the basics is clear.
Mayank: When I say LLM or AI calls, are stateless.
Mayank: How many of you understand this thing?
Mayank: How many of you understand this one line?
Mayank: So, no memory. Many people are giving no memory and stuff. Let me try to ask this thing, then.
Mayank: Hi, ChatGPT.
Mayank: Can you please reply?
Mayank: to me in… Same number of tokens.
Mayank: As I give you… the input.
Mayank: Okay, so I'm just giving it a message, and let's So it is giving this.
Mayank: Now, everyone, how many messages am I having with ChatGPT as of now?
Mayank: How many messages am I having with ChatGPT as of now?
Mayank: Two, I think, because first is mine, second is ChatGPT's.
Mayank: So, can I say that this is… User message?
Mayank: And this is… Assistant message.
Mayank: If I say that ChatGPT is my assistant.
Mayank: Can I say it like this, everyone, yes or no?
Mayank: Anyone has any doubt in this?
Mayank: So, can I say this is the user message, and please focus, please, please focus.
Mayank: It is very, very difficult, like it's an easy concept, but still I'm making sure that everyone understands because I know many people don't understand this concept.
Mayank: But before that, I don't want to move forward
Mayank: And again, I will be drawing and using lots of these tools, because of the muscle memory and everything, so please focus, okay? Don't…
Mayank: Watch me as a Netflix movie or
Mayank: Next 10 minutes only I will take to explain these things, okay?
Mayank: Now, when I ask what… okay, first, first, let's try to understand what would have happened here.
Mayank: Do you think even that I would have?
Mayank: Copied this message.
Mayank: This message is something which would have gone to ChatGPT, which, let's say, is sitting somewhere on a server.
Mayank: So, on a server, this brain of ChatGPT will be sitting, so I can just mention it as…
Mayank: See? Chat.
Mayank: GPT Brain.
Mayank: And then it would have given me the answer back.
Mayank: How many of you think this is what would have actually happened, Mayank?
Mayank: Okay, so people who are happy now, okay, people who are happy, who agree with me.
Mayank: All stay silent, okay? Give yourself rest.
Mayank: People who have any doubt, tell me quickly in the chat. So, if you are happy, if you agree, if you're like, yes, Mayank, I
Mayank: If you don't, then tell me. It may store it as a cache, yes, but that doesn't change the fact that this is what happened.
Mayank: Okay?
Mayank: I am… again, I am asking you a question, if this… what happened? Cash and anything is not for me now.
Mayank: So, I hope each and every one of you, every single one, agree that this happened.
Mayank: Every single, no, don't, don't say yes, don't say yes, don't say yes. Anyone would disagree. So, okay, everyone, for the next 30 minutes, people who disagree with me, only they
Mayank: People who disagree with me only, they will mention that what's the problem.
Mayank: Don't, don't state the obvious, don't write yes or no, don't do
Mayank: Okay, if you don't agree, tell me the problem. So, Jagdish, if you're not agreeing.
Mayank: Ravi Kiran, Jagdish, tell me why. I want to understand your reasoning for the same.
Mayank: Then why? Then what happened? If this didn't happen, then what happened?
Mayank: Again, now, if people are going forward, and if you want to be very smart, that, hey, Mayank, it will be converted, there will be previous message, there will be system message. Still, this doesn't change the fact that my message went to ChatGPT and I got a reply.
Mayank: Is this thing clear to you or not?
Mayank: Now people are going way, way ahead. There will be caching. This will be converted. I don't care. Still, this will happen.
Mayank: However, ChatGPT is handling its problem, it's a black box.
Mayank: This message went to ChatGPT, and I got a reply back, okay?
Mayank: If you disagree, tell me the strong reason, or else I'm moving forward.
Mayank: If you are like, no, no, no, man, I am very smart, there will be system message, it will be changed, there will be transformer array, but it still doesn't change the fact.
Mayank: You are just going into depth.
Mayank: I am just saying that it's a black box. I am keeping it as a simple knowledge. Okay? Cool. So I know that no one will be able to disagree, so I'm moving forward.
Mayank: Next, everyone, when I send this message.
Mayank: Can you tell me what I asked first?
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: First thing, and I want everyone… if you disagree, then only say something, okay? If you disagree, then only say something.
Mayank: There is still ChatGPT brain sitting on the internet.
Mayank: where my this message will go, okay? There is still ChatGPT brain sitting on the internet, where my this message will go.
Mayank: Anyone has any problem, tell me.
Mayank: If you have a problem, then only tell me. Don't write no or anything. Don't write no or anything. If you have any problem, then just tell me.
Mayank: If you have any, any problem, then just tell me.
Mayank: When I press enter, the message will go to ChatGPT.
Mayank: server, chat, GPT, brain, black box, whatever you think of it. Okay? Good. No one has any problem.
Mayank: Now, very important question.
Mayank: When I send this message, when I send this message.
Mayank: You have to tell, so I'm just replying this.
Mayank: VIN?
Mayank: I send a new message.
Mayank: How many messages will be sent?
Mayank: 2.
Mayank: ChatGPT.
Mayank: One.
Mayank: 2.
Mayank: 3. Tell me down therapy.
Mayank: So when I send this message, the second I press enter, how many messages will be sent to ChatGPT?
Mayank: Or the brain, or the black box, or anything. If you don't like ChatGPT, you can think of it like a friend or someone, okay?
Mayank: So I'm getting all, 1, 2, 3, I'm getting all the answers. I'm getting all the answers
Mayank: Okay? I'm getting all the different, different answers.
Mayank: Cool. So, let's not stretch it. Let's not stretch it. People who are being smart by system prompt and everything, well, there is a reason I'm not unnecessarily making it complex. Please focus on what is in front of you, okay? System prompt, for the timing, we can make it inside of it, okay? Chalo.
Mayank: Cool.
Mayank: The right answer, everyone, is 3. The right answer is 3.
Mayank: So, when I send this message to ChatGPT, 3 of my messages will be sent. I don't care about system message, anything, for the time being.
Mayank: I will be sending this.
Mayank: And I will be also sending this.
Mayank: All of them will go to my ChatGPT print.
Mayank: And then it will give me the answer.
Mayank: Anyone who disagree with this?
Mayank: Anyone would disagree with this.
Mayank: Anyone who disagree with this? Yes, Y3 message.
Mayank: Okay, so now there comes an approach, okay? Now there comes an approach of that line which I said.
Mayank: LLM calls are stateless.
Mayank: LLM calls are stateless, okay? What does this mean, everyone?
Mayank: This is a very good example of explaining this. Pay attention.
Mayank: Let's say with Google, I asked, Who is Vinod Kohli?
Mayank: So everyone, will Google give me the answer now?
Mayank: If I ask this, who is Virat Kohli and everything? Yes or no Right?
Mayank: No?
Mayank: If I open this Google Chat, and if I tell it.
Mayank: Can you tell me how many?
Mayank: How many?
Mayank: Runs, he hit.
Mayank: Do you think that Google will have a context of whom I'm talking about in a new chat?
Mayank: Do you think that Google will have any context that I'm talking about Virat Kohli?
Mayank: No, right?
Mayank: No, right? 100% no. Everyone agree with this? Now, don't say that, man, Google is also having a history, Google is very smart, memory… basic like that. Don't… let's not overcomplicate things.
Mayank: If we overcomplicate things, then you will never be able to learn anything. Okay.
Mayank: But I think I'm right here anyways, okay?
Mayank: So, can we say that each Google chat is a new chat? It has no, no idea about what happened previously.
Mayank: It has no idea about what happened previously.
Mayank: If I ask it, if I ask it, what was the last question I asked?
Mayank: I hope all of you agree that it will not have any context, it will not remember anything.
Mayank: Right?
Mayank: Totally, but I agree.
Mayank: Everyone agreed?
Mayank: Everyone agrees? No, anyone who is very smarter than me? No, no, no, Google maintains the chat history, you are being illogical, I don't agree with you, extremely sorry, I will go home.
Mayank: No, it will not event.
Mayank: If you still have problem, open any Cognito tab, try it out.
Mayank: It will not remember.
Mayank: Same is the case with AI. Same is the case with AI.
Mayank: AI, LLM, ChatGPT, Claude, everyone other for that matter.
Mayank: Every time. Every. Thing. Single time.
Mayank: You give it an input, and it just gives you the output. It doesn't remember anything.
Mayank: You give it an input, and you just get an output. It doesn't remember anything.
Mayank: It generally doesn't remember anything.
Mayank: Am I clear on this, everyone?
Mayank: That your AI doesn't remember anything.
Mayank: Okay?
Mayank: So, that means that it is not maintaining any state. It is not maintaining any state. It doesn't know where it is, where… what happened previously, what was the last message, it doesn't remember anything.
Mayank: Hence, the term LLM or AI calls are stateless.
Mayank: So, whenever you are chatting with ChatGPT,
Mayank: For real, it doesn't remember anything about you. It is just like a black box, just like Google.
Mayank: So, if it needs to tell me what was the first message I asked.
Mayank: I will have to actually spend all the messages, and this is what happens.
Mayank: These 3 messages are sent, everyone.
Mayank: It will go to ChatGPT, And ChatGPT will give me the reply.
Mayank: Okay? So, when I ask this thing…
Mayank: So, see, it is able to give me the answer.
Mayank: I hope this complete thing was clear to each and every one of you. If it is clear, don't say anything. If you have doubts, or if you don't understand, logical doubts.
Mayank: Don't say that there is a system thing or no logical doubts. Tell me quickly.
Mayank: How to verify? Well, I will see all 3 messages in request URL or something, I will show that
Mayank: Okay, is there a concept of memory? We'll come to that advanced topic.
Mayank: So, more you have the conversation, the more token it consumes, since it will send all previous messages. Very good demand, very smart UI, yes.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: But if it was stateless, how it remembers? It doesn't remember anything, Shikha. It doesn't remember anything, okay?
Mayank: Everyone, again, you are moving away, you are moving away.
Mayank: I am asking question in this approach, like, is anyone having problem in this thing, okay?
Mayank: Is anyone having problem in this thing?
Mayank: So, actually, I sent all these messages. I sent all the three messages. Now, how many of you have seen, how many of you have seen that as your chat progresses, your LLMs start becoming slow.
Mayank: and everything.
Mayank: How many of you have seen that?
Mayank: Right?
Mayank: Now pay attention, I will… I will…
Mayank: Prove that to you as well.
Mayank: Let's go to Cla
Mayank: Now, I am having an extension here, I am having an extension here, which will make things a lot easier, okay? Cool. Just like ChatGPT, Claude is also a box. Just like ChatGPT, Claude is also a box. A black box, okay?
Mayank: When you send any message to Claude, everyone.
Mayank: In a very, very simple sense, it replies you the message back.
Mayank: Just there is one small thing which you have to also understand. Just there is one small thing which you have to understand.
Mayank: Now, when I will ask something to Claude, don't you think that it tries to give you with a
Mayank: reply based on some instructions, so it is already having some instructions that, hey, don't give my insight, don't give any of my prompts or anything. Don't you think that it is having those level of things set up?
Mayank: So ChatGPT will have something set up that, hey, behave like a helpful assistant, make sure that whenever user answers the question, you follow the request and then give the answer and everything, right?
Mayank: So this is something which is known as system prompt everyone.
Mayank: So, this is something which is known as system prompt.
Mayank: Okay?
Mayank: No?
Mayank: When I send a simple hi message.
Mayank: You will see that how it is 4169 tokens.
Mayank: Are you able to see this 4169 tokens, everyone?
Mayank: And now the length became?
Mayank: 35,000 tokens.
Mayank: Now, why did it gain 35,000 tokens when I just sent a hike?
Mayank: And it was just sent like this. Well, the problem is.
Mayank: that internally, I'm sending lots of things. System message, things about my MCP servers, lots of things I'm sending. So it has to understand each and everything in here. Okay, so that is why, even though I sent a single token.
Mayank: it went ahead and made it 35K tokens. This is actually how AI works in depth, okay?
Mayank: Now, if I ask it, pay attention everyone, now if I ask it.
Mayank: Or rather, if I give it a document, and pay a lot of attention, because this will clear many things, which so many people have a problem, because before that, you cannot actually start.
Mayank: Now, what I'm doing, pay attention.
Mayank: I'm giving it this document, everyone. I'm giving it this pretty long document, okay?
Mayank: I will drag and drop this, and just see.
Mayank: Go through the same.
Mayank: Now, I think all of you will agree this will be somewhere around 2,000, 3,000 things, 2,000, 3,000 tokens, this document.
Mayank: Right, everyone?
Mayank: So the second I send this message.
Mayank: See messages left. Pay attention to here, messages left.
Mayank: Just focus on these messages left.
Mayank: It is asking me, so let me say, use it to negotiate.
Mayank: Just a chat reply.
Mayank: So, it is now thinking and putting in the brain. So, I gave it an input, it is putting in the brain and everything, okay? So, it is asking me a few questions as
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: So, I… say I want all these things.
Mayank: You see everyone, how these messages are reducing, 53.7, How they're reducing?
Mayank: Pay attention.
Mayank: Yes.
Mayank: Pay a lot of attention.
Mayank: So, see?
Mayank: What happened in here, it has given me lots of things.
Mayank: You will see that how now the context window is around 36-7000.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: somewhere around 36… 37,000.
Mayank: If I similarly ask it for more, Can you give… Me up.
Mayank: more complete PDF after searching about this Whole process.
Mayank: Or how can I do it myself as well?
Mayank: So now I am asking it more questions, and pay attention, like, this is very, very important, okay? Very, very important. Just focus on these numbers.
Mayank: You see how these messages are reducing everyone?
Mayank: Do you see how these messages are reducing?
Mayank: Okay, so let me just give it some things.
Mayank: So again, I'm giving it multiple things. And now you will notice a few things. What exactly will happen? ChatGPT is doing lots of this research. It is looking up and doing all this thing. But let's demystify how things are happening. It's Surge and got all these things in it.
Mayank: And now you will see that how this session thing will keep on increasing. This session approach will keep on increasing.
Mayank: Because so many, so many things it is taking in its sight. So many things it is taking in its sight. And let it complete. Let it create a complete document.
Mayank: And then you will see that how the session limit also increased, and the messages will decrease drastically.
Mayank: Why the messages has increased? Again, based on the extension, normally it will decrease only, don't worry. Don't worry, it will decrease only. This is also not very… it is not a Claude extension, okay? It is not a Cl
Mayank: So, it is some third-party extension.
Mayank: See, it is creating a file, everyone.
Mayank: It is actually creating a complete file for you, so lots of code.
Mayank: Let it complete quickly, and then you will see that how this length and everything will increase. So, let it just quickly complete. Do I have any other chat as well?
Mayank: And I can showcase with this.
Mayank: I think I can show you here as well, you know, but you'll have to understand.
Mayank: This is the Fable one, which I wrote contra, so it should be fine here.
Mayank: Sorry to work quickly, everyone.
Mayank: And you will see that as it keeps on working,
Mayank: All these chat will come into the part of your.
Mayank: context. All these chats will come into the part of context.
Mayank: So I think this is no longer a structured document, so I'll build a markdown file first and convert it
Mayank: Let me write an HTML and everything. So it is doing a lot of work. Do you see the session is increasing, everyone?
Mayank: From 3 to… it went to 6%.
Mayank: From 3, it went to 6%, and now it has given me this complete thing.
Mayank: How many messages are now left?
Mayank: 15.
Mayank: It went to 42K tokens. It went to 42K tokens. So why are these messages decreasing then? Why are these decreasing? Because pay attention. Now if I ask it.
Mayank: What was… or let me ask it.
Mayank: Can you summarize
Mayank: To me, the complete chat. Now, don't you think when I ask this question, everyone, it will be sending all of these messages? So if I ask it for a summarization, pay attention.
Mayank: Now you will see that the limits will get more quickly, like seven, it came, now it will come a lot more quickly. And this teaches you more about context handling than any tool will ever. Okay, so now it has given this, okay, I think it is increasing, like it is facing some issues.
Mayank: Let me ask it. Great.
Mayank: Go through the process.
Mayank: Again, okay, so it is like a little bit, it is failing, but it will reduce. Just give me a minute.
Mayank: So, it is asking me some question, I will just quickly select anything.
Mayank: And you will see that how this session limit will keep on increasing. And this length of token will also keep on increasing.
Mayank: So let me select anything.
Mayank: this length of tokens, it will keep on increasing with the complete chat. So this is actually what happens in the backend, everyone, whenever we are working. So this is kind of hallucinating, don't worry. It will get fixed up
Mayank: So… It will quickly, quickly just get fixed up, so don't worry about that.
Mayank: Let it first complete, the whole thing.
Mayank: And then we will see the whole approach.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: So… Great.
Mayank: Why is it not decreasing? Normally it decreases that quickly.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: Can you tell me… The first message of mine.
Mayank: Now, when I ask it for the first message, everyone, it went all the way, and it will try to give me that what was the first message I sent. So, it is saying your first message of this chat was hi, okay?
Mayank: Now, think about what happened. Think about what happened. And for this, I have given a very, very good link. Very, very good link in your approach, okay? So, pay attention now, everyone.
Mayank: This is something which I've given you.
Mayank: Now there is a concept of context window. Just like how you can remember something, your AI can also remember few things. Okay?
Mayank: Let me make this context window say.
Mayank: 40 tokens. So I'm just… this is a very, very dummy AI which I've created. Context window is 40 tokens.
Mayank: If I ask it, great.
Mayank: Can you now summarize?
Mayank: summarize the whole process for me.
Mayank: And if I send the same as a user?
Mayank: And now ChatGPT says, pay attention now, ChatGPT says Great. I can summarize The same for you.
Mayank: And set as A.
Mayank: Do you see, everyone, this first one got out of sync? Because we already have around…
Mayank: If we have this, it will be more than 40 tokens. Do you see that the first one got grayed out
Mayank: Are you able to see that the first one got grayed out?
Mayank: Right?
Mayank: Because my chat, my, this AI, this small AI which I have created and you will get the link as well.
Mayank: It has forgotten this message. It has forgotten this message.
Mayank: Now, if I asked it, What I like… to play.
Mayank: Do you think it will be able to give you the answer?
Mayank: Yes or no. It will not be able to give you the answer. Why?
Mayank: Because this thing is out of context. Just, we are maintaining this much context.
Mayank: So, in a similar manner, everyone, and we already kind of understood that how we send all the messages and everything. So, when I ask this question.
Mayank: These four messages will be sent as input. These four messages will be sent as input. Do you see any football mentioned here? Do you see anything related to football here?
Mayank: No, right? So your ChatGPT will also not tell you, or AI will also not tell you. Now do you understand that why?
Mayank: When your chat becomes longer, your output becomes bad. When your chat becomes longer, when you are chatting for a lot of time, it becomes slow. It forgets the initial things. So if you ask that, hey, make sure that you always refer to me as Mayank.
Mayank: It might not refer to you as Mayank after some time. So I hope the idea is clear now even why it happens.
Mayank: With this small thing, the idea is clear.
Mayank: Right?
Mayank: And as you know, keep on…
Mayank: Telling. As you now keep on asking, please
Mayank: Make sure that you go through.
Mayank: My previous… Previous messages as well. And if you send the same as user, see?
Mayank: Now, because this was a longer message, and I think now you will be able to join everyone, when you give a very, very big PDF to your ChatGPT.
Mayank: It takes a lot of time.
Mayank: And it forgets all the previous things.
Mayank: Right, everyone?
Mayank: I hope you're able to understand this.
Mayank: Yes or no?
Mayank: Because every time, then it will send… try to send all the messages, so that it can give you the best answer.
Mayank: But, because it is having a context window, because every model is having a context window, it forgets.
Mayank: So I hope it makes sense, everyone. With smaller window, it is easier to see, because normally now your AIs are having very, very big context window, like in millions or in 200K, 400K.
Mayank: But I hope, with respect to the smaller window, it is clear.
Mayank: And if we go on models, if I go on ChatGPT models, let's take… Gbd 5.5.
Mayank: It is having 1 million context window.
Mayank: It is having 1 million context window. So, if you are on… if your chat is very long.
Mayank: It will try to remember 1 million round tokens. So, 5.4 mini.
Mayank: It is having 400K context window, 400K tokens.
Mayank: Why it is not limited? Because chalky, then it will be very expensive, right? All these things works with the mathematical model in electricity. So yeah, scientists are trying to increase it, but it cannot be limited.
Mayank: And this is the reason, everyone, This is the reason that.
Mayank: Your models behave bad when it moves ahead.
Mayank: When you give it very, very long files, all these things.
Mayank: And if it is right now, if I just ask… Great.
Mayank: Give me the complete DIY process. So, don't understand what is that. Not sure why this is hallucinating. Normally, this extension works pretty well.
Mayank: So…
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: So, if I ask it for a chat reply, it will now try to see all the messages. So, in this message, when I send this single message, 44K tokens went inside. So, actually, 44K tokens
Mayank: went inside to my Claude.
Mayank: And then it gave me the answer. So that is why you will see that as we move ahead, I will have less and less messages, okay?
Mayank: I will have less and less messages, everyone.
Mayank: And, it will… Forget the previous one as well.
Mayank: So, now it is giving me the complete thing. In a bit, we will see that how this session limit will get a lot quickly over now.
Mayank: This session event, it will… once it completes, let it complete quickly.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: So, why is Claude being so good with the limits?
Mayank: So, now the messages will also decrease a lot, right? Messages will also decrease a lot. The reason is very, very simple.
Mayank: All these chats will be sent here. All of these complete chats will be sent here.
Mayank: So, when all the chat will be sent in every call, don't you think you will be using AI a lot?
Mayank: Don't you think that now, in your next message.
Mayank: there will be 46K token as an input. So, when you call your Claude, everyone, This thing will…
Mayank: Go. Your input token will become 46K.
Mayank: your input token will become 46K, and you will then get the output. So I hope now you're able to understand why ChatGPT and all these behaves the way it does, and why it tells that, hey, start a new chat. Why it sometimes tells that, hey, start a new chat rather than wasting time here.
Mayank: Because this chat will start with the new context.
Mayank: So I hope this thing is clear, everyone.
Mayank: I hope this thing is clear that how context window works. So your chat history, your chat history.
Mayank: Kind of vents every time. So this is a very, very good tool which I've created everyone. This is a very, very good tool which you can remember and always use.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: Clear?
Mayank: I hope now you are… so that is the reason, very, very big files. Yeah, in the free Claude account, they don't give you lots of tokens.
Mayank: So when you chat for a little bit, if you will open a new chat always, it will still run longer. But if your chat is longer, then it will get over quickly.
Mayank: So I hope this makes sense, everyone, yes or no?
Mayank: I hope this makes a lot of sense.
Mayank: Okay?
Mayank: And context window is dependent on the chat, not on the session.
Mayank: Longer your chat, longer it will be for the same, okay? Longer the chat, longer it will be.
Mayank: So you can try the same out, everyone. You can just quickly try to send the message and everything. We will discuss about these memory types and everything and all that, but I think for the time being, this is what context window entail. This is how you have to understand the same, okay?
Mayank: So, in the whiteboard sense, as well, you can understand, in the whiteboard sense, it should also be pretty good.
Mayank: Now, let's move on to the next one. Now, let's move on to the next part, which is par
Mayank: Now, let's come to parameters everyone see. When we discuss about ChatGPT, when we discuss about ChatGPT,
Mayank: Don't you think it's an algorithm or something which is working If I say chat GPTs, parameters.
Mayank: If you're going to meet us See this.
Mayank: So it is saying that GPT-3 was somewhere around 175 billion. GPT-4 is 1 billion.
Mayank: Now, think about this, everyone, and be very, very honest. When I send this message, when I send this message.
Mayank: ChatGPT will be taking it as an input.
Mayank: And then, it will be having some…
Mayank: Weights on which it is treated.
Mayank: And then it will be having some weights on which it is trained, which is in billions or trillions rather now.
Mayank: This message will go through your complete thing, it will try to go through all of these weights and stuff.
Mayank: And then, finally, you will get the output.
Mayank: So, do you feel that in these algorithms, there will be something which ChatGPT has kind of learned by training?
Mayank: Do you think that would be the case, everyone, yes or no
Mayank: And when you train ChatGPT, these small, small parameters inside gets tuned, so they get a value.
Mayank: So these values, everyone, the value which it is getting, These values and everything.
Mayank: This is what parameters are. Now, in the latest ChatGPT and Claude models, they are in trillions.
Mayank: We are genuinely in trillions.
Mayank: Right?
Mayank: more the parameter, More learning capability of the model.
Mayank: So chat… parameters, you can just think about that as well.
Mayank: So… We have neurons in brains. Neurons in brain.
Mayank: So everyone in our brain, we are having these neuron structure. As we grow, it also increases. So more parameters than we can store and we can learn more.
Mayank: So baby in babies, this development happens very fast, right? So that is why their brain expands, their body grows. Brain takes a lot of energy because it is trying to learn things, tune those parameters.
Mayank: So, these are what parameters are, everyone, very, very important. Parameters are internal values tuned during training.
Mayank: The model's actual city.
Mayank: No single parameters mean anything on its own.
Mayank: Capability emerges from the combined position of billions of them.
Mayank: So if you have learned about neural networks, if you have a little bit idea about neural network, like they all get trained and their values come into picture.
Mayank: So I hope this is clear, people.
Mayank: I hope this is clear.
Mayank: Okay?
Mayank: Pretty simple.
Mayank: Jagan and everyone, for this… for this discussion, parameters, weight, everything are same only, so don't… let's not make it complex. For this discussion, they are same only.
Mayank: Cool.
Mayank: There are just some terms and some values with which my ChatGPT works.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: Like, for as an example, just as an example, for my rack.
Mayank: For my laptop, parameters are RAM, SSD, everything. This is the parameters. For ChatGPT, it is having billions and trillions of parameters. Clear?
Mayank: So ChatGPT and Claude can have same parameters. Again, these parameters are in trillions. They are just small, small values. When they combine, they are able to do lots of things.
Mayank: But… I cannot tell, because they don't open source it.
Mayank: So, Claude… Parameters, let's see.
Mayank: My English parameter remains same once set up, or keep changing more users' parameter chain? No, they remain same. When any new version comes in.
Mayank: That is when they move forward, okay? So I don't think they would have taken it out, but anyways, should be fine, okay?
Mayank: So these parameters remain the same.
Mayank: Now they train ChatGPT, and then they come up with a newer model, so it is having some, again, parameters. So, the easiest way of understanding parameters, just understand about neural networks.
Mayank: So, neural network, everyone?
Mayank: These are these kind of things. These are the basics of AI, again.
Mayank: Each and every dot in here, each and every dot in here is a parameter. It is having a value.
Mayank: And that is how it is treated. That is how it is treated.
Mayank: By itself, this value has nothing to do, but when they interact with each other, they are able to give you answers, predict something, draw something, everything it is able to do. So these are what parameters are.
Mayank: Ideally, you have to think, higher the parameters, better will be the learning capability Okay, everyone?
Mayank: Just that. Don't go into buyer's mate. You are unnecessary trying to complex it.
Mayank: Parameter is just directly proportional to the learning ability, nothing else.
Mayank: Clear?
Mayank: And the reason it becomes simple because tomorrow we will be using smaller and larger model. Smaller models generally have lower parameters. Larger models have large parameters.
Mayank: So inbuilt algorithm, mill bit numbers, everything you can understand as parameters.
Mayank: Clear, everyone? Let's move forward.
Mayank: Let's quickly move forward.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: Cool. It's hidden, we don't control it. Everything is
Mayank: It's totally, totally hidden. Okay, just tell me one thing, okay? Just, I will tell you what parameters is in an easier way. When you search on Google, everyone, when you search NB on Google.
Mayank: Google gives you this result by searching and everything very quickly.
Mayank: Right?
Mayank: Yes or no?
Mayank: So, Google have this billions of pages.
Mayank: kind of param… like, Google has these billions of pages, kind of created a database and everything.
Mayank: Right?
Mayank: So these are parameters of Google. Now, we don't control it. We don't own it. We don't actually know even how it works. Google can control it. Google can make it better. Google can expand it as well. But this is how we get an answer.
Mayank: So, similarly for ChatGPT as well, this is the case. Exactly.
Mayank: So if you know Google, in the backend, you understand that Google will be having billions of pages and everything everywhere?
Mayank: I hope all of you agree with that.
Mayank: that when I search for something on Google, out of those billions of pages, it tries that, hey, which one is nearer and everything? Same thing.
Mayank: Same thing.
Mayank: kind of, ChatGPT also has these parameters, okay? It has been trained and everything. Now, there are transformers, neural network, all these different, different, difficult things, which we don't need to, as of now, go
Mayank: And the reason I'm not going in depth, because that is not required in this course. But knowing the term is very, very important. Okay? So don't hate me that, why are you teaching us this thing not in depth? Well, that is not required.
Mayank: But still, I want that you know these things, because
Mayank: Tomorrow, when I say that, hey, let's use this model 5.4 mini instead of 5.4, it will be a problem.
Mayank: Cool. So, with that, let's see what are the next terms, everyone. Attention, transformer, fine-tuning. Let me see if any important term is needed as of now.
Mayank: Else, I think we will move forward with a quick approach first.
Mayank: Great. So now let me clear out one very important thing again.
Mayank: Okay, now let me clear out. I will be giving break after at 9.35.
Mayank: I will give break after 9.35, okay?
Mayank: Would.
Mayank: Cool. So, let's take example of ChatGPT, or Claude again.
Mayank: So I'm taking… And explaining you a little bit about one very important concept.
Mayank: How many of you have ever been to a restaurant?
Mayank: How many of you have ever been outside to restaurant?
Mayank: You know the best part about teaching this like this? There's always one person who would say, no way, I've never been to a restaurant.
Mayank: Like, I will generally get no mic, I've never been to a restaurant. I either live in a box, okay? Cool.
Mayank: They give you two offerings. They give you two offerings.
Mayank: VIP?
Mayank: And API.
Mayank: Okay? They give you two offerings, web and API.
Mayank: Web is like a control buffet.
Mayank: Control buffet.
Mayank: API is like ala cate.
Mayank: Okay? How many of you are able to understand these two things?
Mayank: So… Let me make it clear. Can you use this ChatGPT inside your application?
Mayank: Can you use this chatgpt.com inside your application?
Mayank: No, right? How will you use it?
Mayank: How will you use it?
Mayank: No, you cannot. You cannot use this ChatGPT.com inside your application.
Mayank: If you have created an application, if you have created an application.
Mayank: Will you say to your app that, hey, always have a computer open, Go to ChatGPT.
Mayank: Okay? Search for the reply, and then copy it and go back.
Mayank: You cannot do that, right?
Mayank: I hope that makes sense.
Mayank: that…
Mayank: If you are having… so, just let me take an example of Krishnai.in. So, we have created a chatbot here, right?
Mayank: See.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: There is a chatbot.
Mayank: When I will ask it anything, when I will ask it anything, let's say hi.
Mayank: No!
Mayank: Do you think that in the backend, it is going to chatgpt.com?
Mayank: Searching height.
Mayank: And then giving me back the reply, copying from the ChatGPT.
Mayank: Do you feel it is doing that?
Mayank: No, right?
Mayank: That means that there are 2 ways for sure for using AI or the brain.
Mayank: First is web, which is like a control buffet. Now, where do I mean by control buffet?
Mayank: So pay attention, everyone. Again, I will show you one more thing, and it will make a lot of sense. When I go on my cloud.
Mayank: When I go on my cloud again.
Mayank: I used 10% of the limit, and it is some 3 million, it is saying. It is saying that it is 3 million limits, okay?
Mayank: But… If I used even 300K, okay, then I should have a bill of around $5, $7.
Mayank: Because last, we discussed… Claude API pricing, it was very, very high.
Mayank: If I am using Sonnet model, yeah.
Mayank: So pay attention, everyone, see.
Mayank: If I am using model of Sonnet.
Mayank: Output is $10 per million token.
Mayank: But, for my cloud, I just paid $20.
Mayank: For my cloud, I just paid $20.
Mayank: And… Purchase this pro subscription.
Mayank: And I'm able to use it a lot more. So I'm able to use it a lot more because these companies, they are generally having a loss when they give you these things on web.
Mayank: Because they know that they will be able to cover this thing in API.
Mayank: So I will again explain this with a very easy example. When you take a buffet.
Mayank: Can you take a buffet?
Mayank: You pay, let's say, 1000 for a buffet, and you can eat as
Mayank: But in a controlled manner. It should not that you are saying that, hey, give me all these things which have been created, I'm taking
Mayank: So, in a similar manner, ChatGPT and Claude and others, every AI,
Mayank: In their web version, they give you a limit kind of a thing that, hey, you can use it, but in a controlled manner. So, for
Mayank: 4 hours, you can use up to 3 lakh tokens. If you use more than that, we will not let you do. So, like a control buffer, okay?
Mayank: But in API, you are charged for each and every single token.
Mayank: So I hope this is clear, everyone.
Mayank: The API versus the web thing.
Mayank: The API versus the web thing, is it clear or not?
Mayank: Web is a control buffet.
Mayank: Where they say that, hey, you use it, you get hooked to it. We are following the geo model. We will give you a complete application which will use our model.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: APIs are separate.
Mayank: Okay? Clear?
Mayank: Then why they mention token charges in web? They can only mention only for API key. So Chalky, actually, they never mention token charges. They just say usage.
Mayank: They never see any token charges. They are never even charging me token.
Mayank: Okay? They never charge you by token on web.
Mayank: Yes, in the backend, of course, tokens are kind of playing a role, but they never see that Please.
Mayank: Okay, I hope that is clear as well, everyone.
Mayank: Why they do this? Because they want that more and more people get
Mayank: The power of their models via web.
Mayank: But, did you know that companies will be having To use APIs only.
Mayank: companies will be happy to use APIs only, right?
Mayank: And rather, I can show you.
Mayank: Once your web usage gets over.
Mayank: So it is a control buffet. They are seeing that, hey, I have actually spent extra as well. So this I will showcase. This I will showcase. Pay attention.
Mayank: I will use OpenRouter. How many of you have used this OpenRouter
Mayank: How many of you have users open out a thing?
Mayank: You've never used it? Okay.
Mayank: So, what I will do, everyone, pay a lot of attention.
Mayank: What I will do?
Mayank: OpenRouter is a space where you have all these different, different LLMs. All the LLMs from ChatGPT, from Anthropic.
Mayank: Rather, from all the different, different companies.
Mayank: You find, at a single place, if you want to search for Gemini.
Mayank: You will get all the models of Gemini from Google.
Mayank: If you want to search for ChatGPT, okay, I think Open
Mayank: You will get all the models from OpenAI.
Mayank: If you search for Anthropic, You will get all the anthropic models, okay? So yeah, seem like
Mayank: Hugging face, yeah.
Mayank: Exactly.
Mayank: Then you can create a key of event, so I can go on profile.
Mayank: And I can create an API key.
Mayank: period.
Mayank: Let me delete this.
Mayank: Elite? Elite?
Mayank: So don't worry, you will be able to… you don't have to follow as of now for… with me, you just have to understand, okay? So it is already in minus .05 dollars. No worries.
Mayank: Let me get a new API key.
Mayank: And see? Show… EA EBIT.
Mayank: API gift.
Mayank: I will expire it in one hour.
Mayank: Created.
Mayank: And copy this. Okay, so now I have a API key.
Mayank: Now what I will do, everyone, pay attention. Now what I will do.
Mayank: I can go on the same collab link yesterday as I was. I can go on the same collab link.
Mayank: I can make this have lots of codes.
Mayank: I will ask you to generate a quote.
Mayank: Generate… Oh, good.
Mayank: So that… I… can… Hit Open Router API.
Mayank: on a model.
Mayank: So I'm just asking that, hey, ChatGPT or G Give me the code.
Mayank: Via which?
Mayank: I can… hit this API. So, you will pay attention here, everyone.
Mayank: Let me… Say, accept. So, I have some code.
Mayank: Now, I will just change my key in here. So, I've just changed my key in here, everyone. So, I'm now using the open router key. So, open router knows it is me who is calling it.
Mayank: This is the URL.
Mayank: I'm specifying a model, and then I'm asking it, what is the capital of France?
Mayank: Let me ask this question.
Mayank: And let's see how it will work.
Mayank: So, let it quickly connect just… and in 2 minutes, once I explain this, I will give you an… Did you pay for the key on OpenRouter? Openrouter gives you
Mayank: Free access.
Mayank: Up to some limit, so I'm not paid as of now.
Mayank: So, it is saying that the API key is not correct. It is saying that the API key is not correct. How can that happen? We have just copied it.
Mayank: Okay, it is saying that no endpoint found, so no worries, I can make it solve, don't worry. Let me go to models.
Mayank: Let me use OpenAI only.
Mayank: Yep.
Mayank: Let me go back to Claude.
Mayank: Because I think this model might be out of… $15.
Mayank: So it requires most credits, a request up to, but can only be afforded to increase.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: Let me show you with the free model once. Let me show you with the free model.
Mayank: So which model is free?
Mayank: Let's put this.
Mayank: So, it is not… again, I'm not having some credits in here, so it is saying that, hey, why are you using it if you're not having
Mayank: See, the capital of Paris, France, is Paris. Step-by-step explanation, the capital of France is Paris, okay?
Mayank: Now let's go back to Open
Mayank: Let me go back, see the activity.
Mayank: You see, everyone, that how I hit this thing?
Mayank: Do you see that, how I was able to hit a model?
Mayank: Where this is my complete.
Mayank: Token breakdown as well.
Mayank: So, quickly tell me, I think I must have sent just 7 or 8 tokens in here?
Mayank: I must have sent some 7 or 8 tokens in here.
Mayank: Yes or no?
Mayank: 7 or 8 tokens?
Mayank: This is the answer, and this is then some explanation, like the reasoning part and everything.
Mayank: So, this is just the token which I have used. This is just the token which I have used.
Mayank: And I can actually see this, that token volume 342, one request.
Mayank: Total spent zero, because this was a free model.
Mayank: So I hope you're able to understand that how I can use AI with APIs as well.
Mayank: I hope all of you are able to see that how we are able to use AI with APIs as well.
Mayank: Right?
Mayank: Pretty simple.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: Pretty, pretty simple.
Mayank: And, again, I hope all of you understand that, how it is maintaining the tokens.
Mayank: Because it is going to charge me. As of now, I've used the free… as of now, I have used the free token, free model.
Mayank: Once you come back from Braille, I will show you the paid model as well, okay? Once you come back from Braille, I will show you the paid model as well. No system problem, nothing was sent here, okay? So let me give you a break, think on what I've taught.
Mayank: And then we will.
Mayank: Thank you.
Mayank: Great, everyone. So, I think Rajeeb…
Mayank: Rajeev, I think you just mentioned, so see, I just want to make sure that when we are learning things, there is a flow. There are many questions which comes which can unnecessarily derail the flow, and I try to take a few of them, which are still relevant.
Mayank: Of course, towards the end, I think for the last 2-3 classes… last… all the classes, I have been sitting for 3-4 hours to clear your doubts.
Mayank: If I actually just start clearing doubts, and just think about it, there are more than a thousand people.
Mayank: If even…
Mayank: 50 people are asking a doubt regarding a question, or regarding something, it will take me ages. Like, I will just explain about something, even if I would say that, hey, this is API, this is the full form, I know people will have doubts on that. So in that way, of course, there would be
Mayank: case where I'm taking just the relevant questions.
Mayank: And I'm totally fine with that.
Mayank: I stay till the very end to clear each and every question one by one. One on one, I clear each and every question, right? So, highly, highly suggested that if there is something which I missed, if my GPT is also not able to answer it, you ask the same. Because when in the stream of answers, of course, becomes difficult, and I want to make sure that I cover what all I have.
Mayank: Have on that, okay? So with that, everyone, I hope all of you are fine with the speed and everything.
Mayank: Because again, people are asking the questions that are always skipped. It is never the case. I think I sit after every class and make sure that all the doubts are clear.
Mayank: So, I cannot genuinely do
Mayank: I'd rather have done more than that. I've given you my NGPT and everything is well there. So, yeah, in that case, it should be pretty helpful, okay
Mayank: Cool! Let's start, everyone, then. Let's continue with the understanding. Let me provide you with a thing which many people are asking.
Mayank: Coulard extension.
Mayank: For Chrome.
Mayank: So…
Mayank: Claude usage extension. I'm not sure if it works on free or not, but you can try this out. I will try to create this extension from scratch as well.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: Can you please teach for first, second, second hour, and then take question one hour topic-wise? No, I will teach for 3 hours.
Mayank: And then I will do it. And right now as well, speed is, according to me, it's still slow, but no worries. Cool. Let's now move back, everyone. First thing, many people, I hope all of you are clear with APIs, right?
Mayank: So, I… I'm hitting an API here, someone was asking around that.
Mayank: I hope each and every one of you are clear with APIs.
Mayank: Yes?
Mayank: Am I wrong in that, or am I good with that? That assumption that you know what an API is.
Mayank: Because it's a tech course at the end of the day. We will be doing much more than that, okay?
Mayank: Rajeev, that is the point. If you are… if I'm teaching you open router and everything, and if you are asking question about light LLM, so, again, that is the problem. See, if you will be asking a question, if I'm teaching something.
Mayank: And you are asking me if Light LLM uses this thing.
Mayank: I will never take this question while I'm teaching. This is a complete deroute.
Mayank: I am telling you about… I'm not even teaching you OpenDaughter. I am telling you about API versus web.
Mayank: And you are saying that, man, this is the question I'm answering. That's totally wrong. It's like if I'm teaching you how to eat, you are asking, man, which is the best restaurant in New York? Of course, I will not take it. I will clear it out towards the end. But I saw this question, and I genuinely skipped it.
Mayank: Because I want to make sure that the flow doesn't get disturbed.
Mayank: So I hope I am fine in that, Rajit, right?
Mayank: So, if you are saying… I asked a question whether LightLLM uses OpenAuto internally or not
Mayank: I am not teaching you open router. I am just teaching that how you can hit APIs.
Mayank: This question will unnecessarily derail the complete flow. So that is why I didn't take it. Okay.
Mayank: Cool. So let's move forward, everyone. I think, again, it's pretty simple and everything.
Mayank: We were understanding about web and API difference. I think it is very, very clear that the way you use things on web
Mayank: Versus the way we use things on the API are different.
Mayank: I hope each and every one is clear with this understanding.
Mayank: I hope each and everything, everyone is clear with this understanding.
Mayank: Right?
Mayank: Cool.
Mayank: So, now many people were asking that, Mayank, why is that the case? Well, again.
Mayank: Chad, GPT, Claude, and other, all the AIs for that matter, they say that, hey, we will give you two ways. First, to experience it out and do all your common works.
Mayank: And second, to integrate in our applications. In our application, the pricing is different.
Mayank: In our web, the pricing will be different. So I hope this makes a lot of sense, everyone, that how they are doing the same.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: In it, we have different, different models.
Mayank: We can have lots and lots of models, okay? How can I show you that?
Mayank: When I was going to this ChatGPT page every time.
Mayank: And if I go and view more models, and again, I think we are fine with all the ChatGPT Claude I will use interchangeably, but overall, do you see how we are having so many different, different ChatGPT models?
Mayank: Right?
Mayank: Some for good use case, some for easy use case. So we have ChatGPT 5.5, 5.5 Pro, 5.4 Mini, 5.4 Nano, and all of them are having separate pricing.
Mayank: So, 5.4 mini is input 0.75, output 4.5.
Mayank: 5.5 is…
Mayank: Input $5, output $30. So I hope it is clear that it's a far better model. It is going to have much more better answers. All that thing, higher model will have, lower models will not have that. So I hope this also makes a lot of sense, everyone.
Mayank: This also makes a lot of sense. And I think if you are aware about Cloud offerings.
Mayank: Then you will know that how.
Mayank: We say that Opus is very strong.
Mayank: Haiku is weak, and they're right as well. Fastest, most cost-efficient model
Mayank: High performance model for coding and agents.
Mayank: Ideal for complex agentic coding and enterprise work.
Mayank: Next Generation Intelligence. So, Faber and Mythos, I hope you understand, everyone, that how it is going to be very much in-depth and everything, right or
Mayank: So I hope you understand that there can be different, different brains, there can be Mayank, there can be Einstein, there can be
Mayank: Elon Musk, Each and every one will charge based on the brain capability.
Mayank: So, is this thing clear or not?
Mayank: Fable model is supported till 7…
Mayank: July in your thing, but that's not okay, buddy. But I hope you understand that how input is very, very expensive in Fable.
Mayank: Prompt caching we will see afterwards. It just tries to make it overall better with caching some of the information and stuff.
Mayank: Let's, for the time being, focus on this, okay?
Mayank: And then the individual, you just give a fixed thing. So I hope this analogy of buffet versus ala cate is clear, everyone.
Mayank: This analogy of Buffet versus Alakant is clear.
Mayank: To each and every one of you.
Mayank: Okay, cool. So, the very first thing now comes into picture, everyone. This code has already been pushed to GitHub. For people who are not sure where GitHub is, again, go to this link. This is the GitHub link.
Mayank: If you will go inside, there is just this class for 14 minutes ago, just before break.
Mayank: I push some code inside it.
Mayank: So I have put some code inside it, okay?
Mayank: Later. Let's go back and try to first understand. Okay.
Mayank: So, now, with this… Idea clear, everyone.
Mayank: Do you understand that how we can call APIs and this is what we need to master so that we are able to use our AI in our applications? Yes or no?
Mayank: Yes or no?
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: This question I will take, Suhani, so that I can ask… clear it. So, because many people will have their doubts, see. If I flip between Sonnet and Opus in the same chat, will my contest window keep shifting? So let's try to understand how it
Mayank: See. First thing.
Mayank: More or less, we know that how, if I go on Opus here, if I select Opus here, everyone.
Mayank: Does Opus, Sonnet, or any model has any context of my chat?
Mayank: Any of my model has any context? No, right?
Mayank: When I select Opus now.
Mayank: all the messages will be sent, all of these messages will be sent, and it will give me an answer. So my context window effectively has no worries, like, it will be 46K only if I use Opus.
Mayank: If I honestly use even Fable, right?
Mayank: So it is showing you that 46K tokens only, if I even use Haiku.
Mayank: Because I'm starting from scratch only, right? For me, it is all the
Mayank: Cool, everyone, I hope this makes sense.
Mayank: I hope this makes sense, that how it is happening.
Mayank: Great.
Mayank: Now, let me show you OpenAI
Mayank: log in. How many of you have ever logged into OpenAI? OpenAI, not ChatGPT. OpenAI.
Mayank: API platform.
Mayank: See, I hope I have the password here.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: So, ChatGPT is just an offering from OpenAI.
Mayank: I will quickly repeat.
Mayank: ChatGPT is just an offering from OpenAI.
Mayank: Otherwise, along with that, it gives you a complete ecosystem of all the different models which we can use in our application and in our agents as well. So agent is having the most important use case, which is brain. That brain is nothing but your models. Now let's see everyone.
Mayank: First, how many of you have never seen this UI.
Mayank: How many of you have never, ever seen this UI?
Mayank: Okay, so many people are there. Let's again see.
Mayank: since these are just our stepping stones, and I will always say, now, you can, of course, do it at your own end as well, but I will just show you the things which are for use case, okay? And you have to tell me if this is clear or not.
Mayank: On the web, On the web, ChatGPT gives you multiple models which you can access.
Mayank: But, to be very honest, going forward, going forward, okay?
Mayank: You will have to always talk in terms of API in this course.
Mayank: Like, we will see the best part of this, and we will try to build these things up.
Mayank: But we will always be using APIs. We will not be using ChatGPT will come on.
Mayank: Because we… this is a tech course at the end of the day. I hope this thing is clear, everyone.
Mayank: I hope this part is clear. What will we be using going forward?
Mayank: What we will be using going forward?
Mayank: APIs.
Mayank: So, you have to make sure that you understand APIs, okay?
Mayank: As of now, I'm not going to cover API. Reach out to me on my email or something if you want.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: Good.
Mayank: Now, in this, second thing.
Mayank: OpenAI, not ChatGPT this time. OpenAI is having lots and lots of different, different models. So OpenAI can give you different, different models.
Mayank: which are not available in ChatGPT,
Mayank: I hope this point is also clear to each and every one of you.
Mayank: Like, how in a buffet, there are many things which are not available for everyone, right? But in Alakate, they give you everything.
Mayank: So, buffet might not have drinks, might not have hard drinks.
Mayank: But… They give you everything. So that analogy always holds up. So I hope this is also clear, everyone.
Mayank: I hope that analogy is also hold up.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: Rather, if I show you… I think I showed you before as well.
Mayank: This chat latest is the model which ChatGPT uses. Latest instant model used in ChatGPT. So even though it is having a very, very high price, they don't charge you that. They are like that, hey, you use it, not a problem. We are going to make you hooked and we will get the money out of anyways.
Mayank: But otherwise, as well, everyone, there are lots of models. Some small, some nano, some mini.
Mayank: The more idea becomes that how all models, if you will see.
Mayank: If it is a mini model, it's having a less, very less context window, whereas the normal model is having 1 million context window. Of course, better models are better with respect to your reasoning, with respect to your output and everything. So, now if we go back.
Mayank: Okay? When buffet is more cost-effective, then why don't we use it? So, Ashish, that's the problem. Again, everyone, I will make it very, very clear. Can you use
Mayank: Can you use this inside your application? Again, the same question.
Mayank: Again, the very same question.
Mayank: How can you use it? If you feel that you can use it, tell me.
Mayank: If you feel that you can use it, tell me. So tomorrow, as I showed again, if I go on krishnag.
Mayank: And let's say that I want to create a chatbot, okay? Let's say that I want to create a chatbot.
Mayank: Now, this chatbot, everyone.
Mayank: If I want to make it smarter, can I use ChatGPT web here?
Mayank: Tell me a way through which we can use it, and both of us will have a billion dollar startup idea which we will use, okay?
Mayank: I am asking that if you have chatgpt.com, just, just chatgpt.com.
Mayank: Okay? And I want to make this chatbot smart.
Mayank: So, let me ask, what are all the courses being sold?
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: So, it is now telling me each and everything, see?
Mayank: Now, if I want to make sure, understand this in depth, everyone, if I want to make sure that I can have this level of intelligence.
Mayank: Can I use ChatGPT.com there? If you actually feel you can.
Mayank: Believe me, just reach out to me, let's leave the class.
Mayank: And we have a billion dollar idea. It should be this fast, it should be this way.
Mayank: anyone who feels, anyone who feels that, Mayank, you can use ChatGPT, and think of it properly, okay? Think of it properly.
Mayank: Anyone who feels we can use it.
Mayank: Genuinely tell me, no API key, not API key. This is ChatGPT.
Mayank: This ChatGPT. If you feel you can use it.
Mayank: If you feel you can use it, it's a billion dollar idea or rather a trillion dollar idea
Mayank: It's generally a trillion trillion on an idea.
Mayank: Not API, not API. No RPA, no customers model. Using Playwright package, how much time will it take?
Mayank: Again, Same way, same answer.
Mayank: Genuinely, if you can prove me that, Mayank, I
Mayank: If you can prove it. I will leave teaching, I will sit with you.
Mayank: And I will make sure that I am.
Mayank: Properly, having this brilliant online idea with you.
Mayank: I hope that makes sense.
Mayank: So, waiting for all of you, okay?
Mayank: Good.
Mayank: Because we cannot Because we cannot use this, everyone.
Mayank: There is a web approach, which is nothing but OpenAI APIs.
Mayank: So, in the API sector, everyone, it will charge you.
Mayank: And that charges becomes exactly the one which I was showing you as well.
Mayank: So for every model now, there are charges, which we will have to pay if we use it.
Mayank: Now, I hope this is clear to each and every one of you.
Mayank: that the difference between ChatGPT API and ChatGPT Web.
Mayank: And why we will have to use this thing? Because we have to create custom agents and stuff?
Mayank: Right?
Mayank: Good? Sure.
Mayank: Let's now try to see one more page. Now again, I am not going through each and every page of this. Let me go to chat.
Mayank: And I am creating a new chat in here.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: In the tools, or sorry, in the models, do you see so many different, different models every month? Rather, all the 3.5, 4, every model which was ever, almost ever there in existence.
Mayank: If they have not… Decommission it?
Mayank: Do you see that?
Mayank: See?
Mayank: 3.5, 4… Photo.
Mayank: 03, 01, 4.1. You don't get this option in Buffet. You just get this in Alakate.
Mayank: Right?
Mayank: Let me select 5.4 MIDI.
Mayank: Let me select 5.4 million.
Mayank: Now, when I send a message, hi everyone.
Mayank: I send the messages, hi.
Mayank: Assistant is giving me a message.
Mayank: I hope this thing is clear to everyone. This is how ChatGPT works
Mayank: This is how ChatGPT works. Cool.
Mayank: If I tell it, hi, I am Mayank.
Mayank: my end.
Mayank: It is saying, hi man, nice to meet you.
Mayank: If I ask it, who am I?
Mayank: It is saying you are mad because it is maintaining the chat history here, so no worries, let me clear it out.
Mayank: We will have to start a new chat, ideally.
Mayank: I thought that it doesn't maintain it here, so it should be fine. Let me…
Mayank: Delete all these messages, and it makes me new few things in here.
Mayank: See, the very first thing. Can I give it some instructions, everyone?
Mayank: You are, and… AI expert, and a very… Helpful assisted.
Mayank: Make sure that you… Always.
Mayank: Reply in.
Mayank: poetry. Okay? So I'm just telling it this thing.
Mayank: The second I send it a message, Hello, now.
Mayank: See?
Mayank: It understood this instruction, everyone, yes or no?
Mayank: Did it understood the instructions?
Mayank: Now, tell me one thing, and I think a very, very good example is right in front of
Mayank: like, generally, this is a very, very good example. This Mayang GPT which I've given you, do you know how I have trained this, or how I have given it instructions? What instructions I've given it?
Mayank: You just start the chat here.
Mayank: And it behaves in a different manner.
Mayank: It behaves in a different manner, everyone, yes or no?
Mayank: Right?
Mayank: I'll think about this.
Mayank: Don't you think that I am having some system prompt? And similarly, ChatGPT will also be having some system prompt in here, in a similar fashion.
Mayank: I hope that makes sense.
Mayank: that ChatGPT will be saying to its AI that, hey.
Mayank: This is how you have to behave. Make sure that you don't input any internal things. Make sure that you don't give out any adult content or pay heat to any adult.
Mayank: all these things, or any safeguarding information, okay? Now this thing will be clear, which many of you will ask me the question.
Mayank: So now pay attention.
Mayank: When I send it a message, hi, even though it's a single token.
Mayank: How many lengths of tokens are there, everyone?
Mayank: How many tokens did I consume?
Mayank: Even though I just send a one single token message.
Mayank: I consumed around 30,000 or 4,000 or something tokens, okay?
Mayank: Because… Inside it, inside
Mayank: Claude, ChatGPT, Gemini, every of these models have a system messages inside, which always gets sent.
Mayank: I hope that makes sense.
Mayank: Because if my, now pay attention, it is very, very important. This is all what gets transformed into API.
Mayank: If I am sending this message.
Mayank: And I've told and shared with you that how ChatGPT doesn't remember you. It doesn't remember any message of yours
Mayank: This message will always be sent every month.
Mayank: This message will always and always be sent.
Mayank: Right?
Mayank: So, that is where those 4,000 tokens were coming into picture. So, you are sending a single token message high.
Mayank: It takes that 4,000 messages as well.
Mayank: And that is how you get it. I hope that makes sense. This thing is clear about the system message. So this was the concept of system message.
Mayank: I hope this thing is clear.
Mayank: System message thing is clear.
Mayank: Great.
Mayank: Now pay attention. Now let me delete all these messages, and let me show you. So this is a very good understanding for learning it, okay?
Mayank: If I say, now pay attention again, everyone, If I send a message.
Mayank: Hi, I am Mayank, and let it reply, okay?
Mayank: So, it is giving me these messages and everything here, okay?
Mayank: Now, I told you that how, in the next message, pay attention what will happen. In the next message.
Mayank: This is how it will happen.
Mayank: when I send the next new message to my chat GPT, or any API for that matter, I will prove that to you as well, but I think visually this is very, very clear to understand. Okay? Visually this is very, very clear to understand.
Mayank: These all messages will be sent to my next call.
Mayank: I hope you're able to understand this, everyone.
Mayank: When I make the next call to my API, these 3 messages will be sent.
Mayank: If there would have been.
Mayank: lots of to and fro, all those would have been sent. So hopefully, if I ask it, who am I now? Hopefully.
Mayank: It is giving me URL.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: I hope this is making sense.
Mayank: Do you want me to repeat this from scratch once?
Mayank: Do you want me to read this from scratch once?
Mayank: This is how API works. This is exactly how API works.
Mayank: Quickly, I will repeat it, okay? Quickly, I will repeat it. For people who have understood XCMD, just take… it will just take me 5 minutes, because people… it will
Mayank: See everyone, and again, all these things I'm doing, there is a code. So I'm… all these things which I'm doing, there is actually a Python code which I will run afterwards.
Mayank: First thing, there can be a system message. You are a very helpful assistant.
Mayank: You always… Give the answer.
Mayank: In.
Mayank: Poetry.
Mayank: So I hope this thing is clear. Developer and system message is same for the time being, don't worry. Developer and system message is same.
Mayank: Every model which you are using, ChatGPT, Gemini, Claude, they are having a system message. I think I've proved that to you as
Mayank: I hope this thing is clear to each and every one of you.
Mayank: That they are having a system message?
Mayank: Which I just proved to you in Claude as well. Great, let Hi.
Mayank: It replies this message back to me. It replies this message back to me. Okay.
Mayank: it replies the message back to me. This is a normal ChatGPT thing, this is a normal ChatGPT kind of a message, just that I am using GPT 5.4 Mini.
Mayank: Just that I am using GPT 5.4 mini, okay?
Mayank: Cool.
Mayank: Now, pay attention, everyone. Pay a lot of attention. Till now, everything is fine. I asked you to give it some poetry message. It can be more than 4,000 tokens as well.
Mayank: Every time if I use it, then these 4,000 things will be sent. 4,000 tokens and everything will be sent.
Mayank: No!
Mayank: Let me just delete this for the timing and tell it that, hi, I am Mayank. Okay? Hi, I am Mayank.
Mayank: When I ask this next question, who am I? Okay, when I ask this next question, who am I?
Mayank: This message?
Mayank: And these two messages.
Mayank: All of them go to my ChatGPT brain. All of them go to my ChatGPT brain.
Mayank: And I get back the reply.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: Making it a little bit more clear.
Mayank: When I send the next message, all of them go to my chat GPT. Don't forget about caching or something. Everyone first understand the basics. Forget about caching or something.
Mayank: This message will always and always get appended.
Mayank: So, what I can do, I can just move it here.
Mayank: I can just move it in.
Mayank: This way.
Mayank: This is actually what happened, this is how ChatGPT had done it.
Mayank: Now if I delete it, If I ask it, who am I?
Mayank: If I ask it, who am I?
Mayank: See.
Mayank: You are meant, and in that sense, a spark of thought, because this time, all of these messages got sent, everyone.
Mayank: Exactly, this is how your API handles. Rather, if I show you the
Mayank: See, this is the complete, complete code of what all happened.
Mayank: This is the complete, complete goal of what happened.
Mayank: If there were 100 messages, all 100 would be sent when we are asking for 101 questions, yes.
Mayank: That is the bullet point.
Mayank: System message gets sent every time.
Mayank: Dev message and system messages, same for the time being. Don't worry.
Mayank: This developer message, just think of it like system message. Don't worry.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: Now, in the next message, everyone, this is how it will be sent.
Mayank: So user add this.
Mayank: Assistant, ask this.
Mayank: This is the default behavior in API. Close this, close this. See, this is the default behavior.
Mayank: I hope this thing is clear.
Mayank: In normal ChatGPT, where we said developer message, you cannot. ChatGPT OpenAI sent the
Mayank: Okay? ChatGPT sent… OpenAI sent the message for you, you don't send it.
Mayank: Let me go now, let me go back.
Mayank: Let me just create a key. So I'm not showing each and everything here, let me just simply create a key here for the timing, everyone.
Mayank: API usage AI. Let me get the secret key.
Mayank: I will walk you through that, how you can sign up and create the key, but for the timing, let us try to understand this, on what I want to explain here.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: And badly, let me go to OLAP
Mayank: I will have some codes, and I will just ask it to generate.
Mayank: Generate… Oh.
Mayank: Code to send… Message to… Open AI now.
Mayank: And get a reply. Okay? So I'm just asking Gemini to generate a code for me. Since you already are having this collab, I'm doing it on this.
Mayank: Mmhm.
Mayank: also add the key and all imports, so that I can send the sale, okay?
Mayank: So, as of now, it has not imported that. Let it try to have the key and everything.
Mayank: Okay, it made it very, very complex, but it did.
Mayank: This is the community.
Mayank: Send it to the A.
Mayank: Give me the code to call OpenAI API by setting up my key.
Mayank: And then calling.
Mayank: GPT 5.4.
Mayank: mini model.
Mayank: And get an answer, okay? So pay attention, everyone. I think we discussed, we will do everything on VS Code, yes, Anuj, but this is kind of the last thing which I want to show up there, because it is easier to understand.
Mayank: So, that is the case. We see the output is right in front of us, so it should be fine.
Mayank: Okay? Pretty much everyone. So I can accept this.
Mayank: I can accept this, I can close this.
Mayank: All this does, and we will understand how it works quickly, but all this thing is doing, everyone, it is taking up your OpenAPI key.
Mayank: And then calling some model, okay, and you can send up a message as well. So now let's focus on what will happen.
Mayank: I created a key which I can copy, and again, I will have to delete the same as well.
Mayank: I can go to my cloud. Oh, sorry, go to my… this thing.
Mayank: Set my key.
Mayank: Don't use it. Anyway, it is just having very less credits
Mayank: And now, I'm trying to call OpenAI with my… Oh.
Mayank: With the help of APIs. Is this thing clear, everyone?
Mayank: That I am now just using.
Mayank: Open API.
Mayank: ChatGPT 4.0 mini model to call and get the answer.
Mayank: Now, it is saying what is the message. Now, every message, okay? You can send the system message as well, messages to send. This will keep on going, but let me still showcase that, see? I am just sending a simple message, asking.
Mayank: Hi, I am… Mayank?
Mayank: How are you? Okay? Let me send this message, everyone. This is Alakate. Let me hit it, and let's see what is the reply it is giving.
Mayank: Hi, Mayank, I'm just a programmer, but I'm here to ready to help you. How can I assist you today? Let's go back to ChatGPT. Let'
Mayank: Let's go to usage, and let me make it, let me make it just… For today only.
Mayank: Great.
Mayank: Oh… Okay, so let me see if there is any… All API keys, API UCJ.
Mayank: Let it refresh. It will take a little bit of time to get refreshed. Okay, everyone?
Mayank: So, in a bit it will come. In a bit it will come.
Mayank: Now, this is, like, your test.
Mayank: If I now ask the next message.
Mayank: Who am I?
Mayank: Will it tell who am I or not?
Mayank: You can tell yes or no in the chat.
Mayank: Will it tell that I am Mike or not
Mayank: Remember, I am using API, which is Alafate, it is not a buffet.
Mayank: ChatGPTs or AI calls are stateless.
Mayank: Let me run this.
Mayank: Rather, first I want to show you, actually, if I can show you the usage before I run
Mayank: But I think it takes a little bit of time.
Mayank: to… Get that, you see?
Mayank: Because I want to show you that how the total tokens will be very less.
Mayank: So, I want to just use this key.
Mayank: So, this was the reason I actually went with OpenAI… OpenRouter, Yes.
Mayank: Please, please refresh.
Mayank: Sure, look, we will remember what were the input and outputs, so that we can get the… Key. Okay.
Mayank: If I show an API key, it will be, I think, very less, because I've not done anything major here.
Mayank: If I select API usage key, it will get refreshed, but anyways, let's do this.
Mayank: So, I hope people are fine, why it was not able to tell me I'm well.
Mayank: I hope people will find that why it was not able to tell me I am male.
Mayank: No memory, nothing, nothing at all.
Mayank: It doesn't remember anything.
Mayank: Right? System prompt is not a requirement, right?
Mayank: Why should I enter system problem? I can add that.
Mayank: I can add that.
Mayank: But AI calls us stateless. This is what I wanted to prove to you.
Mayank: This is what I want to prove to you.
Mayank: I hope this makes a lot of sense.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: Great. Now you know what are agents, everyone? Now you know what are agents?
Mayank: You know what is… what is an agent?
Mayank: Don't pay attention.
Mayank: Why I was doing all this thing. Can I say that my AI is the brain, everyone?
Mayank: And you will see me using these analogies a lot.
Mayank: And I'm using ChatGPT because everyone understands ChatGP
Mayank: Can I say that my chat AI is a brain implement?
Mayank: Can I see that my AI is the breed?
Mayank: It is a brain, right? It is just a Gajini brain. It is just a brain like this
Mayank: It is just a brain like this. It doesn't remember anything. So, it is a brain.
Mayank: But he doesn't remember anything.
Mayank: So it is like a Gajini
Mayank: Are we more than our brain, everyone? Like, do you have hands, memory, eyes, all these things?
Mayank: Or do you just have a break? Do you just have a break?
Mayank: I think we are having more than that, right?
Mayank: So what your AI agent is, what your AI agent is in a very, very simple sense. And believe me, it is not difficult at all.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: It is just… Brain plus memory.
Mayank: plus tools. So just like how… and I like to say it not like this, I like to say that it is like an intern.
Mayank: Just like how your intern is having a brain.
Mayank: It is having a memory. It is also having some tools like laptop, etc. Or I like to say this one more important thing, digital human.
Mayank: So your agent is nothing but a digital human.
Mayank: Now think about it. If it is having a brain, you can give it some tools like search the web and everything.
Mayank: And now I think you will be also able to recollect that why people say that, hey, can we create an agent for this thing?
Mayank: Not an AI and agent for this, because they want to replace human with agents.
Mayank: So that is why all of you are in this batch as well.
Mayank: This is what agent is. It is having a brain, it is having a memory, and it is having some access to tool, etc. as well, among other things, but yes, this is what your AI agent is.
Mayank: All of you have understood what AI is and how it works?
Mayank: Agent will maintain that, okay, it is able to maintain all the memories, and it is able to use the tool as well.
Mayank: Now, I think I will be able to see the usage as well, and how it is charged. Let me refresh…
Mayank: I hope it is not 4th July anywhere.
Mayank: So let's see this top.
Mayank: So it takes little bit of time normally. So should be fine. Let me refresh it.
Mayank: Normally, it is faster than this, but should be fine, I think. Maybe servers are overloaded or something.
Mayank: Cool.
Mayank: Great, so… Let's go back.
Mayank: Create this chat, and you will see that how we are having multiple tools here.
Mayank: Either you can add, okay, functions, or… There are no inbuilt tools.
Mayank: Give me 5.4 million.
Mayank: So, let me show you then going back.
Mayank: Let me show you the going back.
Mayank: Yeah, so this was something which I've added even now.
Mayank: Now let's try to understand a few of the things very quickly. AI, I think all of you should be clear now, that AI is a single one-shot prediction, takes a question, return an answer, remembers nothing about any call that happened before or after it.
Mayank: This is the whole capability of a raw model with no wrapping around it.
Mayank: So I hope that makes a lot of sense, everyone, now
Mayank: I hope that makes a lot of sense.
Mayank: What is happening here?
Mayank: AI is clear to each and every one of you, I cannot make it easier than this.
Mayank: But then if AI is clear, agents are very clear.
Mayank: Chatbot.
Mayank: Okay, chatbot.
Mayank: Chatbot is something which, if you think about, it is just a wrapper on top of your AI. So, if I talk about this chatbot, everyone.
Mayank: In the backend, we are using Gemini here. In the backend, we are using
Mayank: We gave it system instructions, we gave it all the previous charts and everything.
Mayank: And then we are able to get the answer. So don't you think that I can say that, hey, this is a doubt solver agent?
Mayank: Or before the advent of AI, if I would have been able to do this, this would have been some person who is solving doubts. I can make it, let's say, I can fool the people by saying that Mayank is sitting behind.
Mayank: So…
Mayank: It is having the memory, etc. as well, so chatbot is when someone tries to make a complete thing around it.
Mayank: Right, everyone? You can say chatbot as agent, not… depends on the use case.
Mayank: But, I have told you what AI is. Now, chatbot, you can give it a memory or not, it is totally on you, it doesn't matter, okay?
Mayank: So, Karthik, that understanding is wrong. That understanding is wrong. Your understanding, like, is… okay, let me frame it like this, that your understanding is not wrong, but it's a very, very wide understanding. If you want to create agent, this understanding is very, very wrong.
Mayank: When we give a task, it figure out the step and does them. No, we tell. Ideally, we control how it will be figuring out and everything.
Mayank: Ideally, we will be controlling them, so that we can create custom agents.
Mayank: And that is where most people make the mistake. They feel that agent is some this magic thing.
Mayank: Which they will give that, hey, do this, they will just have a magic point and say, like, do this, an agent will be able to do that. No, it will not be able to do that. I will give a very good example.
Mayank: Let's say that I'm creating an email replying agent. Let's say that I'm creating an agent which replies to my emails.
Mayank: If I don't give access to my emails, do you think it is of any use?
Mayank: If I don't give any tool.
Mayank: Do you think it is of any use? No, right? But it's an agent. Then what's the problem? Well, you have not configured it rightly.
Mayank: Or, let me take a relatable example.
Mayank: If I am having an intern, if I am having an intern, let's say I've hired an intern, I say that, hey, make sure that you reply to all my emails.
Mayank: So it's an agent, it's a smart person, right?
Mayank: But, if I take away the laptop from him, do you think he will be able to do that, everyone? Now, don't say my mobile is there and all these things. No.
Mayank: I hope that makes sense. Hire me lo- Divyash, if you are in college, you can just try to send me
Mayank: I might be looking someone from a freelance project.
Mayank: For my agency work, okay?
Mayank: And can I say that this, in turn, it will be having a brain, everyone?
Mayank: It will be having a blink.
Mayank: Of course.
Mayank: Ideally, a good brain, a good one should have a memory as well. It should maintain all your messages and everything.
Mayank: And can I say that his laptop is nothing but a tool for it?
Mayank: This laptop is nothing but the tool.
Mayank: If my agent is not having the right tools, if my intern is not having the right tools, will it be able to do this?
Mayank: Will you be able to do this?
Mayank: Make sense?
Mayank: Does it make sense?
Mayank: It will not be like this. Similarly, similarly, very, very important thing.
Mayank: Brain also matters.
Mayank: Let's say that, again, not promoting any child…
Mayank: employment or anything, but see. Let's say that you hire a baby as your intern. So its brain is very, very, like, its brain is very, very small and everything. You give him everything. Do you think that it will be able to then
Mayank: You give him your laptop and everything. Will he be able to reply to your emails and everything?
Mayank: Do you think that?
Mayank: No need.
Mayank: So again, very important learning here as well.
Mayank: If you say that, I will select a very, very bad model.
Mayank: I will select a very, very bad model.
Mayank: And inside it, I want it to do everything. So I hope you understand that if you use Haiku, which is cost-efficient, which is fast, but if you ask it to do a very complex thing, it will fail, because the brain is different, okay?
Mayank: And now let me showcase you the complete anatomy of agent, so that you understand without the anything, and why agent always might not be very good. Anatomy of agent.
Mayank: Aiden will be having a brain.
Mayank: Which I think I've made it very, very clear multiple times.
Mayank: And this thing is very, very important, everyone, okay? Everyone focus.
Mayank: It will be having some memory, let me use…
Mayank: This one for memory. In the real sense, memory will be your, SQL table… any way you want to save it. It can be a SQL DB,
Mayank: It can be mem zero, any of the things should not be a problem.
Mayank: Right?
Mayank: And then it will be having some tools.
Mayank: This, everyone, is what your agent is. Now, let's try to understand how things happen.
Mayank: If I say… Search for… Virat Kohli.
Mayank: latest innings, okay? So let's see what all it will do, everyone inside. Youtube will get an answer. Youtube will get an answer.
Mayank: But how it will happen inside. Pay a lot of attention.
Mayank: I hope first this question will go to Brain, everyone.
Mayank: I hope all of you agree. Each and every one of you, I want that you write focus in the chat.
Mayank: I write focus in the chat.
Mayank: F-O-C-U-S.
Mayank: So that you focus on what I'm teaching now, because it is very.
Mayank: All the framework, everyone is doing this only.
Mayank: First, I hope all of you understand that how this will go to brain. I hope all of you understand that how this will go to brain.
Mayank: Along with this, I will also send to my brain a system prompt that, hey, you are a very helpful assistant and you are having, let's say that I'm giving it three tools.
Mayank: I'm giving it 3 tools. Web search, Calculator?
Mayank: And weather.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: No pay attention, no agent, everything will catch on.
Mayank: So, in here, I will say as well, You are a helpful assistant.
Mayank: You have 3 tools.
Mayank: Pay attention now, everyone.
Mayank: So this is actually how agent works.
Mayank: Let's say this is my system prompt to my agent, because, see, at the end of the day, this brain is AI. I hope each and every one of you are clear that how the brain is an AI.
Mayank: Brain is just an AI.
Mayank: I think everyone should be clear, like, you use either OpenAI, Claude, ChatGPT, any of the brains, free open source brain as well.
Mayank: First, this request will go to the brain. It will try to see if it is having some tool.
Mayank: Then it will go and use that web search tool.
Mayank: Okay?
Mayank: It will try to see that, okay, what all my web search tool needs. Maybe the web search tool needs a
Mayank: Maybe the web search tool needs a name or what it wants to search.
Mayank: Then tool will also be.
Mayank: Called for web search, then it will give you back the results.
Mayank: Okay? Then it will give back the results.
Mayank: After getting the results, it will again use the brain. Everything now, these messages will be saved in the memory, that what
Mayank: Was asked what was said.
Mayank: All the results and everything will be sent to the brain.
Mayank: All the result and everything will be sent to the brain.
Mayank: And then I will get my final answer.
Mayank: So, in a sense, in a sense.
Mayank: This is just a to and fro between APIs. API of a brain, API of the tools, API of the…
Mayank: Memory.
Mayank: Does this make sense, what I did right now?
Mayank: What I've just done right now, does it make any sense?
Mayank: It is actually what happens.
Mayank: It is genuinely, genuinely what happens
Mayank: Genuinely, this is what all is happening, nothing else.
Mayank: Clear?
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: I am opening one more thing. Don't get confused.
Mayank: I'm opening this just for the visualization, okay? I'm just opening just for the visualization.
Mayank: Please don't get confused. Please, please don't get confused.
Mayank: So this is my latent instance, everyone, which I am using.
Mayank: So, I use this instance for client work.
Mayank: Let me create a new workflow here. You don't have to worry about what is this anything or anything, you don't have to worry about
Mayank: I'm just going to get an AI agent here. To prove my point, I'm going to get an AI
Mayank: See.
Mayank: Let's focus on this agent.
Mayank: It is having a chat model, everyone.
Mayank: It is having a chat model.
Mayank: If I click this, see the options.
Mayank: Alibaba, Anthropic, Google… OpenAI, Open AI chat model.
Mayank: I hope…
Mayank: You are clear that how this is the brain only, let me save this, the key which I gave.
Mayank: There's a problem with this. Set content type is not a function.
Mayank: So just to explain you a lot in depth, because this is the most important part, like LangChain, LangGraph, Creo AI, everything works on the similar way. Nothing else they are working. They are generally working on the same operation, nothing else.
Mayank: And don't focus that this is an intent, just focus that how Mayank is showing a visualization, because I love to teach my visualization.
Mayank: Does it got deductive?
Mayank: Cool. Meanwhile, it load is the agent clear?
Mayank: Your key was active for 1 hour only, I think. Huh, that was also the case. But I think it hasn't been 1 hour.
Mayank: What does it mean?
Mayank: So, let's see if it has loaded the other things meanwhile.
Mayank: ChatGPT page…
Mayank: Login.
Mayank: Api platform.
Mayank: Okay, let's go to usage.
Mayank: Key active… I think it is active, but I'm facing the issue, I think it is that other end.
Mayank: Let's go to usage. Let's go to API usage key.
Mayank: See everyone, it had around 45… tokens.
Mayank: Three usage, I think the last usage was from anything.
Mayank: We sent it 2 messages, I hope all of you remember this, that how we sent it 2 messages.
Mayank: Input 45, output 82.
Mayank: So, all of you are able to understand and connect these dots here, right?
Mayank: I first tell it, hi, ma'am.
Mayank: it gave me the reply, then I asked it who am I, it gave me the reply, these things.
Mayank: And of course, like, it is very, very low as of now, so there is no cost or something, but I hope you understand what it is, right? So I hope this thing is clear now that how API works.
Mayank: Now it should be clear to each and every one of you.
Mayank: how the Api works. Cool.
Mayank: Let's see if anything has started.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: Just give me a minute, everyone, okay? Just one minute.
Mayank: Because I want that you understand it. Like, once you understand it with… without a code.
Mayank: It will be easy with code as well.
Mayank: So, let me try to do one more thing, not do this. I have an Anthropic API key as well.
Mayank: Just give me a minute, everyone, okay? Just a minute, so as to not make it very difficult for all of you to…
Mayank: Have something on your screen.
Mayank: I remember I have Claude account as well, so just let me quickly, just let me get the key.
Mayank: But I will make sure that none of you get that key, because Claude credits are expensive.
Mayank: Hmm… Just give me a minute, okay? Meanwhile, you
Mayank: Enter any questions or something should be fine.
Mayank: Am I having credits? Yes, I am having credits. Let me get a key quickly.
Mayank: API… Usage and agent anatomy.
Mayank: This is what I'm explaining, all of
Mayank: Without… again, I'm doing this thing because many people were saying yesterday as well that they are from different backgrounds, so it should be fine.
Mayank: Are you able to see my messages? I was actually able to see it, but…
Mayank: For the timing, we can explain it quickly now.
Mayank: Add a new credentials, give it a key, save it, please run, please run. Yeah, cool. Great. So pay attention now, everyone, let's understand.
Mayank: Very first thing, do you feel that AI will always need a brain?
Mayank: Do you feel that AI will always need a brain?
Mayank: Your intern should always have a brain, right? Digital image should always have a brain.
Mayank: Make sense? Pretty simple?
Mayank: I gave it a name.
Mayank: Now, I think all of you do also understand that how your brain can have
Mayank: any of the provider, like, your AI is a brain, right? So, anything which you see here, OpenAI,
Mayank: Open router.
Mayank: Mistral, Grok, Azure, Anthropic, so there are… these are all nothing but AIs, right, everyone
Mayank: I hope you agree on this thing that these are all AIs only? LLMs?
Mayank: I hope you're getting this. So I'm selecting the Anthropic, which is cloud-only, as a brain, okay So…
Mayank: Let me go back, and I have selected Anthropic Claude as my brain.
Mayank: There are some options as well, I think it doesn't let you add maximum number of tokens and everything, so these are just options which you can control.
Mayank: But I hope the brain part is clear to each and every one of you.
Mayank: I hope the main part is clear.
Mayank: Yep.
Mayank: Let me send a message.
Mayank: Hi, I am Mayank. And see, this is an agent.
Mayank: It will use the brain and give me reply, hi, hi, Mike, how are you Who am I?
Mayank: Will it be able to tell that I am Mike or not? Tell me quickly in the chat.
Mayank: No.
Mayank: No. It has no memory as of now. So when I ask it this question.
Mayank: I don't know who you are, you haven't shared any information about yourself with me. I only know that what you choose to tell me in our conversation. Would you like to introduce yourself?
Mayank: So I hope this thing is clear.
Mayank: Let's fix this first thing first.
Mayank: By adding a memory.
Mayank: I'm going to add a simple memory, and don't, again, don't follow on the N8N or anything, just understand the diagram, nothing else.
Mayank: These are just nodes, nothing else. I am adding a memory. Now let's try to see the same thing.
Mayank: First, I hope this first part is clear.
Mayank: That why agent use the brain?
Mayank: But it was not having any memory, so it was not able to use that. Is this clear, everyone?
Mayank: I will remove this.
Mayank: Everyone, I hope it is clear, can I get smiley faces
Mayank: I hope you're loving the way I'm explaining in depth, rather than just starting with a
Mayank: Because then frameworks will become very easy. I will show you, like, once your basics are clear, how easy everything is. Okay.
Mayank: Cool.
Mayank: No mixing, no pay attention everyone.
Mayank: Now pay attention, everything will be clear. Don't focus that this is NA10 or something, no. Just see the visuals. For you, this is just visual.
Mayank: Now I have added a memory.
Mayank: And… What I will do, if you don't pay attention, I will send a message again. Let me z
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: Okay, let me make normal only.
Mayank: Hi, I am Mike.
Mayank: And this time, notice what will happen. This time, notice the flow. The… what I was drawing here, right? What I was drawing for all of you here.
Mayank: This all I will show you in real world.
Mayank: See.
Mayank: This time it accesses the memory, and do you see that how our memory is having two messages?
Mayank: How are memories having two messages?
Mayank: First message?
Mayank: Hi, I am Meng. Second message, hi Meng, nice to meet you, how are you doing
Mayank: Anyone has any doubt in this?
Mayank: I hope should not be.
Mayank: Let's also understand the… let's also understand how it happened, okay? And believe me, you have to focus, like, this way…
Mayank: It is… Like, the most easiest way of understanding agents, but a lot in depth.
Mayank: First, it tried to access the memory.
Mayank: Were we having any messages in our memory before everyone?
Mayank: Were we having any memory… any messages in our memory before? No.
Mayank: Then, it called the message.
Mayank: With the input, and it got the output.
Mayank: And then it saved all of that in the memory.
Mayank: Anyone has any problem in this flow? Anyone has any problem in this flow?
Mayank: If you have a problem, tell me the problem. This is not clear to me. Memory can have a limit? Yes, exactly, it can have a limit. Not a problem.
Mayank: Second step, it called the AI model.
Mayank: A bit of it called the AI model memory will be piled up. Yes, it will be piled up for sure. It will be piled
Mayank: But again, I think we save memory in a SQL or some DB. So should we find?
Mayank: How to add memory? I will teach when I teach frameworks. For the time being, just understand that I have added an Excel thing. If you want to understand, you can just think of it like an Exce
Mayank: Okay?
Mayank: What is simpler memory? What is other kind of memory? Totally out of scope. Do you understand the normal memory here?
Mayank: Do you understand the normal memory here? So, first step is always to go to memory, of course. First step is always, always to go to memory. What is this chat node for? To open the chat.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: But in ChatGPT, we are not saving the details in memory, right? Because ChatGPT is doing it Okay.
Mayank: Cool.
Mayank: Great. Let's ask the second question. Things will be much more clear to you. Let's ask the second question. Okay.
Mayank: Have a big chat.
Mayank: Let me make it a little bit smaller.
Mayank: Yeah, paid attention. Let me answer the second question.
Mayank: Who am I? Okay? I'm asking this question. I want all of you to follow. Now, please, please wait, wait, wait, everyone, wait. Please follow.
Mayank: Please follow how it will happen, okay? Please follow the full sequence.
Mayank: Please follow. People are asking different types of memory. First, memory.
Mayank: Why teach everything in a single class? Everyone, please follow how it will flow, okay? Please follow that.
Mayank: I'm asking who am I?
Mayank: First, it went to memory.
Mayank: Do you think these were the messages which I was having in my memory, everyone?
Mayank: Do you think this was the messages I was having in my memory, right or wrong?
Mayank: I think everyone will agree that this was the case. Why, how no? How no? How no?
Mayank: How no?
Mayank: These were the messages I was having in my memory, right, everyone? How can you say no to this?
Mayank: Filto, we can have Sunrise is in the east
Mayank: Sun rises in the east, no man, earth rotates. How are you seeing sun rises in the e
Mayank: These were the messages in my memory, right, everyone? I have these previous chats. That is what was saved in the memory. I showed you on the last as well, right?
Mayank: I showed you in the last as well.
Mayank: Next, and focus.
Mayank: Am I sending the complete chat history to everyone, yes or no? If you are able to focus now, I think this should be very, very clear to you. And I cannot make it easier than this. Rather, no one, I can assure you, no one can make it easier for you.
Mayank: Did I send just a single message, or I sent the previous messages as well?
Mayank: How many messages am I sending?
Mayank: All three?
Mayank: Now, I think everything is getting connected. Each and everything which I explained to you on the UI, is it getting connected or not?
Mayank: Is it getting connected or not?
Mayank: Now, do you think with all these messages.
Mayank: Chad GPT will be able to tell me who am I.
Mayank: I think, yes, that is the reason it is able to tell me who am I
Mayank: It is that easy.
Mayank: It is genuinely, genuinely that Yes, I sent one message, but from the memory, it took the previous messages.
Mayank: And it is able to read that. What is human tagging? I don't know. Fo Focus on this!
Mayank: Human tagging, actually, you were asking for here.
Mayank: It is also a message sent by human. This was given by AI, so user and assistant. I thought that you were asking that when human tags the messages or something.
Mayank: This message was sent by human. This was sent by AI. Then this was sent by human again.
Mayank: Now I want each and every one of you to give me the right answer. And please don't test my patience.
Mayank: When I will send it the next message.
Mayank: How many messages will it send to Claude?
Mayank: When I send the next message.
Mayank: Four previous messages, plus fifth one, my new one. Okay, so let's focus on this as well. Please focus. Please, please focus.
Mayank: Great!
Mayank: You remembered?
Mayank: Me. Also, one more thing, everyone, if you will notice.
Mayank: It first went to the memory to get the previous messages.
Mayank: I'm not running it as of now
Mayank: When I said that, hi, am I Mayang? And I said, who am
Mayank: First, it got the previous messages, then it hit Claude.
Mayank: Then it saved the response as well. So that is the reason you are seeing it hit two times.
Mayank: So I hope you understand why it was hit 2 times.
Mayank: I hope you understand why it was hit 2 times.
Mayank: Each and every one of you are clear on this
Mayank: And AI was hit just a single time.
Mayank: AI was hit just a single time.
Mayank: So, when I ask the question.
Mayank: It got the previous messages, it got the answer, saved the answer back to the memory. So that is why 2 times.
Mayank: If I show you what is inside the memory, as of now, it is having phone messages.
Mayank: Previous phone messages. It saved this last message as well, actually.
Mayank: Clear, everyone?
Mayank: I hope this is clear.
Mayank: I hope this thing is clear.
Mayank: The web version handles all these things for you.
Mayank: But since you will be creating these things, since you have to create these things now in this course, you need to understand how it works. That is why I'm so much talking about how the web version works.
Mayank: Actually, ChatGPT and Cloud are agents.
Mayank: They are not AI, they are actually an agent.
Mayank: Okay? Focus, everyone.
Mayank: When I ask, glad you created your member to be?
Mayank: First, it get the memory, then it hit ChatG, Claude, then it hit Claude, it got the message, and then it is
Mayank: Pay attention.
Mayank: It got, from the memory, all the previous messages.
Mayank: It hit AI with all the previous messages.
Mayank: Then, it went back to maybe… see if this came as a…
Mayank: I cannot explain it more easier than this. Another, no one can.
Mayank: No one genuinely can explain it. See?
Mayank: Five messages.
Mayank: 5 messages now.
Mayank: So it is done. Cool.
Mayank: Now, let's take things up a notch. I am starting a new chat session, just like how you do in ChatGPT. I am starting a new chat session.
Mayank: Now, do you think it will remember who am I?
Mayank: Now, do you think it will remember who am I? No, because I have started a new session. It is not having any memory.
Mayank: Unless I sent it some other focused memory, which is long-term memory, which we will talk about, like how Mayankit remembers and I am ChatGPT always remember well.
Mayank: Because you sent a separate thing along with system prompt as well, but that is not important. Let's now understand tool, everyone. So, in your internal part, now is the brain and the memory clear?
Mayank: That how your, how you will, so let's say that we are trying to replace an intern. So we are giving it a brain, we have given it a memory.
Mayank: Now comes tool.
Mayank: I will give it calculator tool.
Mayank: And I will give it one more tool, let me see which tool I can give.
Mayank: Yes.
Mayank: It is my own instance. It is my own instance. Let me try to give.
Mayank: Calendar, if I'm connected calendar will be very difficult for many people.
Mayank: Let me use one thing, which I will teach you in future, but for the timing, let me use it myself.
Mayank: So this is just a web search tool, nothing else. Weather is not default, available by default.
Mayank: Let me copy this.
Mayank: Go back.
Mayank: Let me see, Tabli should be there.
Mayank: time early.
Mayank: Now, don't understand, Meg, what is this tably? What is this? I'm not understanding. That is not my approach as well. I am not explaining you how anything works or something. That is for future classes.
Mayank: I am explaining you, Duh.
Mayank: Approach. So, I'd create a new credentials.
Mayank: Save this.
Mayank: Seems like it is working.
Mayank: And I will let AI decide.
Mayank: Good.
Mayank: Let me do it. Web search. So everyone, I have given my intern two things. I have given my intern two things.
Mayank: Two tools, calculator and web search.
Mayank: I hope all of you appeared with this and what I have given it.
Mayank: Anyone has any doubt? Very simple thing. You gave your internal calculator, and you gave him Google.
Mayank: Rajeshwari, what is not What is not clear in this?
Mayank: When you say no, also tell what is not clear.
Mayank: That's a no-no excuse Cool. So, I hope you're seeing that how we are making our agents slowly, slowly
Mayank: We gave it a brain, we gave it a memory, now we are giving it tools.
Mayank: From where you got the tooth, don't matter. I will teach you an intent separately, don Good, great.
Mayank: Now, pay attention, and this time, everything will be clear. And again, everyone, I write, I want that all of you write focus.
Mayank: In the chat.
Mayank: I wanted all of you to write focus in the chat.
Mayank: Chicken.
Mayank: Because I need all of you to focus. If you will not focus, this will never be clear. And just like I said that there are few things which I know no one can explain better than me, just like that oops Hindi video.
Mayank: This is also one of that concept.
Mayank: This is one of that concept, okay?
Mayank: Now, see, first understand what happens. First understand.
Mayank: The second you create these tools, the second you create these tools, everyone.
Mayank: Since they are all part of your agent, since they are all part of your agent.
Mayank: your intern, when you will call it the next time, it will know. It will know that, hey, I am having these two tools. It will have an idea, like, see.
Mayank: Each tool is having a description, which it sets automatically, or you can set it for it. So I can set the description.
Mayank: Search in Tavily.
Mayank: For information on the web.
Mayank: Now, pay attention.
Mayank: When you have created this tool.
Mayank: This description of the tool is going to my agent.
Mayank: Calculator description is also going to my agent.
Mayank: It is having the brain as well.
Mayank: Now, actually, your agent is just an orchestrator. Do you think that this agent by itself is having any brain, any smartness, anything?
Mayank: It is having nothing. It is just like a piece of code which takes things from here to there.
Mayank: If we focus on this seat.
Mayank: This is where it is very, very important to understand that how agent works.
Mayank: And then I will show you, like, how all the frameworks which we are going to master from the next class onwards are the same.
Mayank: These are… nothing.
Mayank: These are going to hit.
Mayank: When next time you call your agent?
Mayank: It will also be sending this information to the brain because only the brain is the main thing.
Mayank: Only brain can take the decision. Now focus, everyone. Now focus.
Mayank: I said, hi, I am… Mayank.
Mayank: See.
Mayank: Did it use any tool?
Mayank: Should it have used any tool?
Mayank: So let me tell you what would have happened inside.
Mayank: So, your response would have gone here.
Mayank: Your response would have gone here. So, let us follow the response, okay?
Mayank: Your response would have gone here.
Mayank: From there, it would have actually gone to this AI, VIN?
Mayank: Claude would have understood that, hey.
Mayank: Claude would have actually understood that, hey, the person is telling me I am Mayank.
Mayank: I am having two tools as well.
Mayank: But person is not asking me for anything. Why should I use the tool then? Let me just quickly answer this.
Mayank: Okay?
Mayank: This is what the flow happened this time. Do you see any tool being used?
Mayank: Do you see any tool being used?
Mayank: No, but memory is being used in the same manner. Memory is being used in the same manner. Okay.
Mayank: Cool.
Mayank: Great.
Mayank: Now, focus.
Mayank: Can you search about Virat Kohli?
Mayank: And tell me… Why he is exactly famous.
Mayank: Let's say that you are giving this decision to your intern, okay? Now let's first understand what it will do, okay, everyone? Let's first understand what a normal intern will do. Let's take this Vijara intern and understand what it will do.
Mayank: First, it will try to understand and use brain, everyone. I hope all of you understand that. First, it will try to use a brain to understand the question. You are a big Virat Kohli fan.
Mayank: Not really, to be honest, but I like this example because everyone can relate to it.
Mayank: If I have to use some athlete, I would use Kobe Bryant, the basketball player. But anyways, first it will use the brain, everyone. I hope everyone agree with
Mayank: That it will use the brain first.
Mayank: It will not send this complete message. If I ask you for a Virat pooling.
Mayank: Will you search this complete message on Google, everyone? Will you search this complete message?
Mayank: Morning.
Mayank: It will try to understand by using the brain that, hey, and memory will be used altogether.
Mayank: Then it will use the tool.
Mayank: Call, search… With VK?
Mayank: It will get the tool results.
Mayank: It will get the tool result.
Mayank: So, lots of things. It will get lots of results.
Mayank: Right, everyone? So if I go and search for Vinod Kohli, again on this, Virat Kohli.
Mayank: I'm getting all these results, but do you think that your intern, if he gives you these images and stuff, won't you fire him?
Mayank: If he gives that, hey, this is what Virat Kohli is, won
Mayank: Ideally, it should read through it.
Mayank: Ideally, it should read and maybe copy these all things.
Mayank: Then use it brain to give you a summarized description. I hope the normal flow without any AI or anything is clear.
Mayank: I have the normal flow.
Mayank: Without AI, anything is clear?
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: Just to make sure that my intern is not smart, I can mention as well.
Mayank: Make sure to use
Mayank: web search tool. So that he says that, no, no, no, I know who Virat Kohli is and all these things. No, no, I'm saying
Mayank: So, do you think, just by thinking, can you tell me that my brain will be used multiple times here this time?
Mayank: Do you think Bain will be used multiple times?
Mayank: First, to understand the problem, then to search and get the results, then to summarize that result.
Mayank: Okay? Great.
Mayank: Let me answer this question, and focus on the complete flow.
Mayank: Sit.
Mayank: First, it got all the message. Now it is time to understand. Next is use the web search. Now it is going back to the brain, getting the result, summarizing it, taking a bit of longer time.
Mayank: And… Okay, so it is… it's a good thing.
Mayank: Okay, I made a mistake. I hope I'm not using…
Mayank: Opus model. I genuinely hope I'm not using Opus model. Which model am I using inside? Sonnet. Should be fine. It is also expensive, but should be fine.
Mayank: Channel.
Mayank: It worked.
Mayank: Do you see how much time BrainBot used every month this time?
Mayank: How much time did Brainport used?
Mayank: How much time? 2.
Mayank: Earlier, it was always one. Earlier, it was always one, right?
Mayank: See? Pay attention. First step.
Mayank: It tried to understand what there is in the memory.
Mayank: It did use the memory, it did use the memory. Pay attention. Pay a lot of attention.
Mayank: Please pay a lot of attention.
Mayank: It uses simple memory of V1 to get all the messages.
Mayank: Then, when it made the first call, it sent everything.
Mayank: It sent all the previous messages as well.
Mayank: Make sense? How the flow is happening? In the second step here, this is the Agentic flow. People ask now, Vayan, what is the Agentic flow? This is the Agentic flow.
Mayank: This is the complete anatomy of agent.
Mayank: Is it clear, everyone? Are the first two steps clear?
Mayank: Are the first two steps clear?
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: Good.
Mayank: Next.
Mayank: It used a brief.
Mayank: It, sorry, it used a tool.
Mayank: And see, what is the query, why is Vinod Kohli famous So?
Mayank: It is just like it went to Google.
Mayank: And search wise, you're not fully famous. And it may have got this result in something.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: And pay attention, it got all these results.
Mayank: So, pay a lot of attention. It got all these results. Are you able to see the content and everything as well in the results, everyone?
Mayank: Are you able to see the content and everything as well in the result?
Mayank: Now, do you think that it should, like, your intern should give you this result?
Mayank: ChatGPT.
Mayank: Do you think that ChatGPT should give you a result like Claude, ChatGPT, will it Will it be helpful?
Mayank: No need.
Mayank: What it should do, rather?
Mayank: What it should do, rather.
Mayank: It should summarize. How will it summarize?
Mayank: It will do something like this. Chat GPT?
Mayank: Again, it is using Claude, but I'm showing you by ChatGP Summarize my research.
Mayank: See? This is kind of what you will do, everyone. Make sense?
Mayank: This is kind of what it will do.
Mayank: Does it make sense?
Mayank: Or not.
Mayank: Right?
Mayank: Pay attention.
Mayank: It is loading any memory variables, anything which is present in the end.
Mayank: See what all is being sent to Claude
Mayank: I cannot again make it easier than this.
Mayank: See?
Mayank: All the results, everything is being sent to Claude.
Mayank: Every research, everything?
Mayank: Is it sending?
Mayank: All the previous messages as well, it is sending.
Mayank: Then… Claude, by using it brain or normal brain, is it able to give you the complete result, everyone?
Mayank: Is it able to give you a much better result?
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: So that's the flow.
Mayank: And if you see the memory.
Mayank: It is having all of these things.
Mayank: And it didn't save this, I think… okay, so length, I think, is 5, so it didn't save this. We will have to check that, that why it didn't do it. Ideally, it should have saved the…
Mayank: this message as well. So, this, I mean, Android and TPR have also done the same.
Mayank: But, yeah, I hope the flow of agent is clear now.
Mayank: I hope the flow of agent is completely clear now.
Mayank: Yes or no?
Mayank: If you have not typed use web search, will it have used it? Idvs, it would have used it the same still, okay?
Mayank: Cool, everyone?
Mayank: Cool.
Mayank: How Blaynode LLM knows which tool available? It gets sent. Agent sends that these are the tools which are available.
Mayank: So, let me do it one more time.
Mayank: Tell me why Vinod… okay, now tell me about the latest FIFA, the zinc
Mayank: And also, tell me what is…
Mayank: Okay, so this time I'm giving it two questions. This time I'm giving it two questions. Understand the flow.
Mayank: First, it will try to understand the problem, so it is understanding.
Mayank: It is getting the result.
Mayank: This time, it is then using the calculator as well, because this is an Agentic flow. This is an Agentic flow.
Mayank: And… It went to the memory, there was nothing.
Mayank: It hit the model, It… Was smart that it use.
Mayank: calculator for this.
Mayank: and web search for this. So this was a smart agent. You ask him two questions, he said that, okay, calculator for this, web search for this.
Mayank: Get all the results. Got all the results. Calling web search with input.
Mayank: All the result it was able to get and give me the summary.
Mayank: And give me the summary.
Mayank: How will it decide which tool need to be used? Toollets are having a description.
Mayank: So, tools are having a description. So, in a way, it uses more than one tool. Now, tell me one thing, everyone, don't you think this is what Claude also does?
Mayank: This is what Claude also does.
Mayank: And I will show you, in front of you, Research?
Mayank: Tell me… about the latest FIFA results. See?
Mayank: I gave it a task, it understood the understanding, see?
Mayank: It is thinking, and it's saying user is asking about FIFA result. It is searching the web, so web search tool came here.
Mayank: And now it is giving me the result.
Mayank: I hope that makes a lot of sense.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: I, again, cannot make it easier, though I will still clear your questions, but I want that all of you see the recording. This same thing I've tried to explain in the code. Actually, for the class, I plan to have a complete application.
Mayank: But should we find? I don't want to unnecessarily rush it.
Mayank: Okay, if you like the explanation, do share your learnings on LinkedIn and everywhere as well, but I don't want to unnecess
Mayank: But yes, today, based on my use case, I was giving you this weather calculator and search app because that is what we plan to create an agent.
Mayank: And I wanted to, now that the agent is clear, my whole idea was that how, step by step.
Mayank: We were able to call, so decide tool.
Mayank: Ask, will it cause the AI, okay?
Mayank: Then…
Mayank: giving it a tool, all of these things I have actually made ready. I would expect that you will enjoy… you will, sorry, go through the same.
Mayank: But, yeah, this is the whole anatomy of Agent Everyone. Just to add a little bit more weightage to my…
Mayank: Explanation.
Mayank: If you go to LandChain, if you go to LandChain If you were to build, So, deep agents… Models?
Mayank: These are all the models which are supported.
Mayank: Okay, so what else?
Mayank: Tools?
Mayank: These are just some of the tools. You can either create a custom tool, I actually use Tabulae only, if you will see, I use this Tabulae tool only.
Mayank: Which was able to search the WIF for me.
Mayank: And then again, there are a few more things, but memory, more or less, these are all the things. Since you have understood the same, it will be very, very clear.
Mayank: So, yeah, I think should… like, this is, again, what every, every, every Framework teaches.
Mayank: Can you hear me?
Mayank: Let's see QA as well. Documentation.
Mayank: Documentation.
Mayank: So, if you go on agents, crafting effective agent, can you AI just tell that, hey, instead of giving a system prompt, you tell me the role, goal, and backstory?
Mayank: So, it creates that based on that, so it kind of creates a system prompt based on that.
Mayank: But then you can give it tools as well. So custom tools and everything. But yes, every framework is just helping you create this thing. Nothing else. Okay.
Mayank: So cool. Let me stop this and ask how was the experience everyone? I know there are lots of questions. I will clear them. I'm not running, but how was the learning experience of agents?
Mayank: No need to see recording. I got so much clarity. See, I feel that if I'm a teacher, I should be able to explain you the concept without any framework. Because now you will never forget it. Now your whole confidence is that you know Agent. You don't know LangChain.
Mayank: Tomorrow, if your manager comes in and says that, hey, we are not using LangChain, we are using CrewAI, you will be like.
Mayank: Cool.
Mayank: So, Padiya, Padiya, Padiya, show your love on the poll as well, and let's start. And again, I'm not turning away. Since I have to cover the ground, I have to teach. Now I will be sharing
Mayank: So don't blame me. So I'm like, now I will clear the questions.
Mayank: And of course, we are going to now build on top of these understanding by creating our agents with different frameworks.
Mayank: Okay, so if you like this explanation, because this is the core of it
Mayank: How the agent understands two questions, I will show that in ChatGPT in the next class, but it uses the brain, nothing else. Okay? Cool.
Mayank: Same thing.
Mayank: Raise your hand if you have any doubts. I will unmute people one by one in queue, so you might have to wait. If you love the class, the explanation, the visualization, everything, please give your love on the
Mayank: polls, okay?
Mayank: And if you don't have any question, you can… Just drop.
Mayank: Take care, enjoy your Sunday.
Mayank: If you are having any questions, I am there to answer every question till you… till you drop, because I'm hopeful I will not drop before that.
Mayank: Because I love to solve questions. Okay, ciao.
Mayank: Cool.
Mayank: Sahibdeep, Chitendra, and Ravikant, and Mansi.
Mayank: So, on the homework part, everyone, if I talk about the homework part.
Mayank: You have these codes and the links. Just go through them, nothing else.
Mayank: Okay.
Sahibdeep: Hi, good morning. Am I audible?
Mayank: Say Libya, say Lib.
Sahibdeep: Yeah, so I have a few questions. One thing is, since we're learning to build agents and Agentic AI, so is it necessary to remember transformer architecture and mathematics behind it for the interviews?
Mayank: No, if you are less than 5 years of experience, then yes.
Mayank: If not, then no.
Sahibdeep: So, I'm around 9 to 10 years of experience, and I'm into data analytics, slash data science field. At this point of time, it seems that the career has been saturated.
Sahibdeep: means there are no salary hikes due to AI bubble or what sort. So, what should I do? I am going through this course, and I have gone through some Krishnaic scores as well earlier. So, just want to understand what should be my next step.
Sahibdeep: Yep.
Mayank: You… what is your background data analysis?
Sahibdeep: Yeah, data analytics and data science. So I've worked on a little bit on data analytics, data science, and data engineering as well.
Mayank: I will, like, the obvious next step for you at 10 years of experience would be to jump into data engineering a little bit more.
Sahibdeep: Okay.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: So, good.
Jitendra Biswal: Okay,
Mayank: Jitendra, you can ask it out.
Jitendra Biswal: Yeah. Hi, Bank. Thanks for this session. But I have a few questions. Please bear with me.
Jitendra Biswal: My basic questions comes, like, how do you differentiate between the session and the context?
Jitendra Biswal: Because you are showing that, you know, cloud, interface. So just want to, because you are giving a session, session was having a, you have a like a.
Jitendra Biswal: Hmm.
Mayank: The session is something which session is something which Claude controls. So Claude see that he.
Mayank: Since it's a controlled buffet, you can just have, let's say, 10 chapatis in 3 hours… Okay.
Jitendra Biswal: And so.
Mayank: So session is just something which Claude controls. You will never get that session in API because there you are paying.
Mayank: Okay.
Jitendra Biswal: Okay, I see.
Mayank: And everyone, I think we'll say one more thing, one, just one quick thing as well, because Dishita is actually making a nice
Mayank: If you have any doubt related to what I teach, let's first clear out that.
Mayank: Because, even though I respected everything, many people will be having the similar doubts, so if you are having anything related to what I teach, let's first clear that, and then let's come on to the career questions.
Mayank: Okay?
Mayank: I hope this thing makes sense.
Mayank: Because that doubt many people will be having. I clear out the career questions, it takes a lot of time.
Mayank: And then people, of course, drop off, because I understand as well.
Mayank: So, let's try to focus. I was planning it after one month, but I feel that since the class and everything. So, Jitendra, Ravikant, or other anyone?
Mayank: If you have a career-related question, just wait.
Mayank: Otherwise, you can ask your question related to the class what I taught so that I can clear it out. So yes, you can do that.
Jitendra Biswal: Yeah, I have only class related questions.
Mayank: Geez.
Jitendra Biswal: So, so that means that the session that it is showing, I should ignore it?
Jitendra Biswal: on.
Jitendra Biswal: Because what I understand the context means, like, if I go to the chat, window, like, so today I have, I did a, you know, conversation on a particular subject.
Mayank: I will explain it, because I think else you will get confused. Let me explain with the example.
Mayank: the one chat which we use. And everyone, please focus, because I know many of you would be having this doubt. So, if I go on this greeting part… See, first thing.
Mayank: This session which you see here, that how much of 5 hours quota you have used, this is from Claude, you can ignore it, honestly.
Mayank: This is just like Claude saying that, hey, I will, I will let you eat only 100 chapatis in 5 hours, not more than that. So it is just kind of showing how much chapatis you have eaten, okay?
Mayank: Make sense? Okay.
Jitendra Biswal: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Mayank: Now these chats.
Mayank: They are saved in some DB, so you are not being charged for these chats. In your chat, in your chat which you are running.
Mayank: These chats, you can come after one year as well. They will be here only, because they are saved in a database.
Mayank: Is this clear?
Jitendra Biswal: Yeah, this is clear. Let's say I am asking the question about football here. Let's assume that. Then I wanted to ask about, let's say, chemistry.
Jitendra Biswal: Okay, so what I'll do, I'll create another session or maybe another, you know, the plus sign in the top, in the top left. So I will start a new chat window. I mean, new chat sessions. I'll ask you, okay, hey, as a chemistry teacher, I'll set the context.
Jitendra Biswal: Then you answered me about the, the periodic table. Okay, some question. So, so it serves in a different, chart history.
Mayank: Che.
Jitendra Biswal: Then tomorrow afternoon.
Mayank: mute.
Jitendra Biswal: Different. Yeah. So how the context is different is the context is one context or the two different context.
Mayank: No, no, no. Context. Context is by that chat.
Mayank: History. So if I run this.
Mayank: It will start a new chat with this complete new ID.
Jitendra Biswal: So is it a new context, right?
Mayank: Yes, yes, but.
Jitendra Biswal: Yeah, it's gonna.
Mayank: Yeah, yeah.
Jitendra Biswal: Okay. It is a new. So if I in this context, if I ask because let's say I have already asked the question about the football, then in this new context and I have said he was a chemistry teacher, but suppose wrongly I asked about who is Messi, will it answer or it will, you know, hallucinate?
Mayank: It will.
Jitendra Biswal: Yeah, good.
Mayank: Again, it will tie to…
Jitendra Biswal: Not give the right answer.
Mayank: Maybe it will. See, these models are not very smart.
Mayank: It is just like saying that you have told your intern, again, I will take the example of intern, or let's say me, you have told your intern that, hey, just talk to me about chemistry. But out of the view, you discuss that, hey, what is the FIFA score, or what is the sales, so it can push back. It is based on your things as well, so pay attention.
Mayank: Don't… Strictly.
Mayank: Answer me.
Mayank: Anything else?
Mayank: Push back, so I don't…
Mayank: use context. So I have now strictly asked it that, hey, just tell me about periodic tables, nothing else. So it is thinking about this like a chemistry teacher.
Jitendra Biswal: Mmh.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: It will give the answer.
Mayank: Now, it is asking me for the goal, and all these things should be fine, that I've asked Claude to always ask me. But now, if I ask it about, just, I would say, Zoom.
Mayank: Ford.
Mayank: My school.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: So it will give the answer.
Mayank: Rajinder's screen is shared.
Mayank: Okay, so it is giving me this thing.
Mayank: Now, if I ask it, what about FIFA score?
Mayank: Yesterday.
Mayank: So your question is, will it answer or not, right?
Jitendra Biswal: Yeah, my question is, will it answer properly or hallucinate?
Mayank: Ideally, it should not hallucinate unless the
Mayank: If it will answer or not depends on how you have mentioned it.
Mayank: So it is thinking about the same.
Mayank: It is thinking about this thing. It is searching the web, so it has not listened to my questions, right? It has not listened to
Mayank: See? So, maybe I was not strict enough.
Mayank: So it has answered me.
Jitendra Biswal: Okay, so is my contest ghost mixed up right now in this new.
Mayank: Yes.
Jitendra Biswal: This contest got mixed up with the football, like FIPA and the chemistry.
Mayank: It actually got mixed up.
Jitendra Biswal: Mixed up, right? Okay. So I can consider every chat window I'm starting, that is a new context.
Mayank: Yes, that is exactly the case. Every start, new video you start. That's a new context.
Jitendra Biswal: Paul.
Jitendra Biswal: Okay, okay. My next question is, if there is something called message left, what does it mean? I don't know.
Mayank: You can forget this, this is an extension which I've added from Mix Chrome store.
Mayank: So normally what happens, as your number of messages will increase here, it kind of…
Mayank: Tries to estimate that, hey, now your context has increased, so this you will not see in the normal plot,
Mayank: Oh, oh, oh.
Mayank: Let me try… like, you can ignore it, like, what it tries to give you is that, based on your chat, based on how long is your chat, how many messages are left?
Mayank: In the chat, which is very long, the messages left will be very less, because
Mayank: You have a fixed context which you can work on.
Mayank: It sends that to Claude. If it will be very, very long, then of course you will have less messages, right? If I have 1 million, example, if I have 1 million of these tokens above.
Mayank: Then I can just ID send a single message.
Mayank: Or let's say just 3 messages, because I have a limit of 3 million tokens. But you can ignore it, just understand the idea that if you have a longer context, and if there is a limit.
Mayank: If there is a longer context, and if there is a limit, then you will be able to send less messages.
Jitendra Biswal: I see, I see, I see.
Jitendra Biswal: Okay.
Mayank: You can think of it like this as well, that, let's say that, for example
Mayank: They are saying that you are allowed 100 chapatis.
Jitendra Biswal: Now…
Mayank: If you… Are already having this 90 chapatis or something in the backend and some stuff.
Mayank: It will not give you that thing very quickly, like, it will say that, hey.
Mayank: You are sending these 90s back, so I will just give you 10 now. So, something like that, but the longer the context.
Mayank: Lesser will be the message sent in a particular thing, but for our course, you don't need to focus on that. This is just something which I've added, because it helps me, but overall, it's the same thing, should not be a problem.
Jitendra Biswal: Okay. My next question is, so you mentioned that the AI calls, let's start, let's see. Yes.
Jitendra Biswal: I agree, but let's compare with this, like, our web calls.
Jitendra Biswal: So generally, let's say I'm hitting a particular website and it is all HTTP calls are stateless means like because it maintains a session in the client's cookie and every call the client cookie is sent to the server to maintain the what has things has happened.
Jitendra Biswal: So, but practically, it is just headless, okay?
Mayank: But here…
Jitendra Biswal: But here… The message is stored in the server's message store.
Jitendra Biswal: Right? All my…
Mayank: It is stored in a separate DP.
Jitendra Biswal: But, separate.
Mayank: One thing, one thing first, Jitender, if you want to understand about the stateless thing, Forget about the web.
Mayank: Because if you will compare, they have handled this thing in the web.
Jitendra Biswal: Mmhm.
Mayank: So, when you send a message, like, for example.
Mayank: Now, in this as well, when I send this next message, Great.
Mayank: You… didn't… Stop me.
Mayank: From… Going away.
Mayank: From chemistry.
Mayank: So, this message… where it will be sent to Claude.
Mayank: Claude will have no context.
Mayank: Internally, Claude will make sure that it gets this.
Jitendra Biswal: Yes.
Mayank: from the DB and send it to Claude. So that is.
Jitendra Biswal: student.
Mayank: It doesn't understand anything.
Jitendra Biswal: Okay, okay. But practical sense, it is not a stateless. I mean, it is still stateless. Yeah, technically it is a stateless, but the way overall it is managing, it is maintaining the state.
Mayank: That is where agent comes in. It is not maintaining the state still. This is actually an agent. This is not an AI agent.
Jitendra Biswal: Okay.
Mayank: is an agent.
Mayank: So, technically, we are maintaining it. If we just send this single message, the way I show you how, hi, I am Mayank, and Manit was not able to tell you.
Jitendra Biswal: Mmh.
Mayank: It is not. So, again, as I'm making it very, very clear, please, please make sure that if you are trying to understand the concept of stateless thing.
Mayank: Just apply it to API, not to web.
Jitendra Biswal: Oh, okay. Oh.
Mayank: Because web, they handle a lot of things.
Mayank: Web, if I will just start a new chat, if I ask.
Mayank: just tell my name, it will be able to tell, because it is knowing and it sends that information every time, you and Mike, see?
Jitendra Biswal: Mmhm.
Mayank: But… but… Otherwise… In a new call, it is always stateless.
Mayank: It is always, always stateless, nothing is being.
Jitendra Biswal: Yeah, yeah, yeah. Technically, it is a stateless, yeah.
Mayank: Maybe it is a sweet as.
Jitendra Biswal: Yes, yes. My next question is, see,
Jitendra Biswal: Though our previous messages are stored in the… I mean, all our histories are stored in the message DB, I can say.
Jitendra Biswal: So, when it gets processed, my next token, my next prompt is gets processed. Will it, when, because it reads also the message, all the previous messages, so that means.
Jitendra Biswal: Every, like, my number of tokens will be used more, right? Yes. It will exponentially, it will increase the more and more longer.
Mayank: Yes.
Jitendra Biswal: chart will be there, the token consumption will be exponentially increased. Is it correct?
Mayank: Yes, yes, exactly. It's totally correct.
Jitendra Biswal: Okay, okay. And my last question is, what is the reset in two hours, eight minutes?
Mayank: Again, this is from Claude, this is from Claude.
Jitendra Biswal: Yeah, I know what it'll, what it'll reset exactly.
Mayank: It will reset this to zero. So again, I have used 14%.
Mayank: If I extend
Mayank: If I keep on using it, and if it reaches 100%, Claude will stop the prime to me.
Jitendra Biswal: I see. Oh.
Mayank: So if you have ever used Claude, just try to ask it many things.
Mayank: And when your chat will go a lot ahead, in real world.
Mayank: It will stop it back to you.
Mayank: Because 100% usage is done. Similarly, Claus has a monthly… weekly usage as well, so I've used weekly 34%. So this is all from Claude, so you can ignore.
Jitendra Biswal: Oh.
Jitendra Biswal: Okay, I think I am done. I'm good. Thank you.
Mayank: Cool. Great.
Mayank: Cool. So…
Mayank: One minute. And again, anyone's doubt which I missed out in the chat, please be a gentleman or a gentlewoman, if that's the word, and ask that in the doubt session. Don't say that Mayank don't clear doubt. I'm still seeing many people are mentioning that Mayank in the feedback that Mayank is not clearing. See, I have to teach first. Okay.
Mayank: But let's focus. Anyone of Chitinder, I think, is done. People who I've talked to, please have their hands down.
Karanbir Singh: And.
Mayank: One minute, let me tell that from the queue. Pradeep, you are next, if you have a doubt related to
Mayank: Career related outs, India.
pradeep: Okay. Hey, hi, Mayank. So this is related to… I'm setting up my personal laptop. I wanted a quick, answer, in the sense, I have a, Dell laptop without any OS. Do you suggest Windows or, Linux, with respect to…
Mayank: I would suggest Linux.
pradeep: Okay.
Mayank: For development, and we are going to do development in this course, it will have terminal.
Mayank: That said, honestly, it doesn't matter. I told you in the very first class how…
pradeep: Okay.
Mayank: You can have terminated that, so it should be fine.
pradeep: Okay, thank you, Mayank. One other question with respect to the subject is that, you know, in the web, I understand that we should not be comparing, just a curious question.
pradeep: the web, it stores all the previous data, and as well, all of that. I mean, is it storing it in any some database, and then reviewing every time?
Mayank: Yes, yes, it is storing the database.
pradeep: Okay, okay.
pradeep: Thank you.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: So, Pradeep, do you have any career-related doubt.
pradeep: No.
Mayank: Shubham. Oh, sorry. Current beer. Current.
Karanbir Singh: Thanks, man. Hi, can you hear me?
Mayank: Yeah, yeah.
Karanbir Singh: But.
Karanbir Singh: Mayank, I have two questions. So the first one is that, like you said, AI agents consist of three pieces, brain, data, and tools. So who drives the flow? Is it the LLM brain drives the flow, or is it the agent separate, there is some separate component who drives the flow?
Mayank: No, no. Ideally, all of them work together, but what tools gets called… That decide by brain.
Mayank: Saving to memory and everything gets decided by agent, so it is just like us human.
Mayank: So…
Karanbir Singh: Okay.
Mayank: you have a brain, you take the decision that, okay, if I have to take up this pen or something, but subconsciously, your body maintains that, hey, I'm saving what all happened in the memory. So that is how it would be happening under this.
Karanbir Singh: Okay, thanks. So the agent has another component, like, it is…
Karanbir Singh: Taking the help of the MLM.
Mayank: Agent combines all of them.
Karanbir Singh: Okay.
Mayank: Bain will not… Take care of saving to memory, that is the agent work.
Mayank: But.
Karanbir Singh: To print the steps.
Karanbir Singh: It gives the steps to agent, and agent executes at the end. Something like that.
Mayank: No, no, I would rather say that agent orchestrates, agent…
Mayank: understand which to call when, and it is dependent as well. So, for example, if there is a task, agent first gives to LLM. If LLM or the brain says that, hey, call this tool, then agent helps in calling that tool.
Mayank: Finally, agent is saving everything in between, and it goes back, and that is how it happens.
Karanbir Singh: Okay, so the main orchestra is…
Mayank: is happening as agent. The brain is the engine.
Karanbir Singh: Okay.
Karanbir Singh: Okay, brain is just helping to perform, but everything is steps are given by aging.
Mayank: Yes, agent is orchestrating. Agent is making sure, first, I have to call brain, then I have to save this message, then I have to call this tool if brain wants it.
Mayank: Okay. So main thing is agent, like the human, complete human is the brain. Brain is just a brain in there.
Karanbir Singh: Okay, and another one is, like, when we are getting the Wikipedia data, is it getting saved again in the data back, or that old flow.
Mayank: Ideally, we don't save it, so if I have to show you again, that is what I have seen, but it is, again, totally on you, if you are defining it for your use case.
Mayank: Ideally, this will not be saved in my context.
Mayank: Now, again, it can depend if Claude wants to moderate it, he wants it to be saved, it can.
Mayank: But anything which happens in between, normally we don't save it in the memory, or the chat history. Like, chat history is a better word, not in memory.
Mayank: So, if I go and entertain as well, if I see the simple memory.
Mayank: I… okay, is this a new chat?
Mayank: So, let me say, great.
Mayank: So…
Mayank: I know that it will not be saving the tool results. Like, it is saying that calling web search, it is understanding.
Mayank: Okay, so… okay, so here it is saving it. Now again, it depends, as I said, like, it is totally on us, what we want or what we don't. So here it is saving each and everything. So, chat history…
Mayank: Afterward, it said everything, so it can be used in future. So, I think that makes sense. But it is totally on us, how we want to manage it. This is n8n version of agent.
Mayank: It is not, it is not written in stone that you have to save this or not.
Mayank: Claude, I know, doesn't handle it. Claude doesn't count towards the context.
Mayank: N8N is counting, right? So, N8N is saving all these things. So, should be fine. Let's see the next message.
Mayank: Tag you.
Mayank: And let's see, this time Anthropic.
Mayank: So, yeah, it is selling everything, which is not a good approach, because now the cost will increase very exponentially.
Mayank: So, ideally, if I would have created an agent, I would have either saved it separately, the tool desert, or I would not have saved it. So, totally on you. That is where we will learn how to create agents, right?
Karanbir Singh: Okay. Makes sense. Yeah. Thanks, man. I think I'll ask career question maybe later.
Mayank: Just keep your heads up. Once I am clear with all the things, then we can move on to that.
Mayank: Great. Let me unmute people who are unmuted. Ankit, Harshish, Shubham, Pranav, Ravi Ghant
Mayank: Anshul Rashim, Basudev, Ashish, Suheb, Shashi?
Vasudev N: I'm in.
Mayank: Yes, also deaf, yeah.
Vasudev N: Thanks a lot today. You have covered. You have cleared many doubts.
Vasudev N: So, really, big thanks to you, Mank. It's related to contest window. As I said, like, I'm a DevOps architect, so we, use many troubleshoot parts in the automation and all.
Vasudev N: So, I'm using, cloud, and, let's say when I'm working on, troubleshooting any database issue or something, I have opened a contesting window, and I keep on asking, like, the each solution, if I'm facing any issues, and I'm fixing that, and based on the answers which I'm getting.
Vasudev N: And I'm fixing that. So, and in this way, today I learned that the contest window is keep on growing for each and every query because it is for input and outputs.
Vasudev N: As you said. And, like, all questions and answers keep on growing. So, how we can control the tokens in that case? Because, if you see, let's say I have used 40K tokens.
Vasudev N: Okay, and if I again ask one question, the previous questions as well as the latest questions keep on increasing. So in this case, how we can control the tokens?
Mayank: We can summarize.
Mayank: The previous chat, that is something which happens. There's a way of handling the context, which we will see.
Mayank: So, let's say that you use AI, that, hey, I'm sending you this, just help me summarize. So, what I can do, if I have to show you here, because, like, more than memory, understand it like chat history.
Mayank: I can copy all of this memory.
Mayank: send it to any AI and say that, hey, give me a summarized version. Of course, it will lose something, but yeah, that is something which we can do. That is what Chad… Claude does as well. I think you will see Claude…
Mayank: Conversation compressing.
Mayank: Loading, something like this screen, you must have seen.
Mayank: Yeah. So, compacting our conversation so we can keep chatting. This takes 1-2 minutes. So this is Claude way of…
Mayank: Saying that, hey, context has gone a lot, let me take a step back.
Mayank: Handed me.
Mayank: do. So it's a no more mid-project context window tests. So that is, again, this is the best thing which I like when I teach things in depth. So now you will be able to understand. When the context window grows a lot.
Mayank: Claude collapses it. It summarizes the same.
Mayank: So, that's one approach. Second, unnecessarily don't have a single chat.
Mayank: Rather, if you will see… How to avoid clawed… Limits. Any article.
Mayank: it will be the very first point will be start fresh chat frequently. And now you know why that is the case as well.
Vasudev N: Agreed.
Mayank: See next. Edit your prompt instead of connecting. Like, these are so easy things once you understand the basics.
Mayank: Tell me one thing, if I will edit this out…
Mayank: See, it is having less context.
Mayank: Right? Yes. If I edit this out, it is having less context. So for people who were like the last person who was asking this that, hey, what about FIFA? Well, don't worry, let's say.
Mayank: Make it more easier.
Mayank: So this time, Because I…
Mayank: created a new… because I edited it out, only the top context is going. Anything beyond is not going, so that is a very good approach as well.
Mayank: So, yes, now your basics are clear, I think all of these things will be very, very easy, honestly. Batch your instructions, this is asking one question at a time, use Shift-Enter to combine multiple tasks.
Mayank: Use project for recurring files. Again, I think very, very simple. They are easy with that.
Mayank: Okay. Next question.
Vasudev N: Thank you so much. Thank you so much.
Mayank: Okay.
Vasudev N: And when will you last…
Asutosh: Okay.
Vasudev N: Teleph.
Mayank: One minute, one minute, everyone. Yes.
Vasudev N: And, the token cost
Vasudev N: for each iteration, for each question, the token cost keep on increasing, right? So the previous one, let's say 40K, already we are spending for the token cost, and again, when I'm asking, without this knowledge, and when I'm, again, I'm asking the question, so 40 plus the latest count.
Vasudev N: In that way, the token cost is, keep on increasing?
Mayank: Yeah, so as your chats grow, that is the reason that your number of messages will reduce, or you will see a lot higher cost.
Mayank: For example, in my current usage of N8N, when I'm asking it any question now.
Mayank: in this same chat, it will be very, very expensive. It will genuinely be very, very expensive, because
Mayank: Now, in all future chats, and this is for everyone, pay attention.
Mayank: Even though I am sending it high, and again, it is charging me, let me first see how much it has charged me, okay?
Mayank: So, because, extremely sorry, this is, like, the real money which I've onboarded into that.
Mayank: So, just a second. I can show you this as well. I can show you the charges as well.
Mayank: So I had $5, okay?
Mayank: I have around $5, let me see how many are left.
Mayank: Billing. Yeah. So I am now left with $4.9 every month. So if I show you quickly this thing.
Mayank: For anyone who is interested.
Mayank: So, actually, it was charging me 4.94. It was 5 when we started.
Mayank: Spend limits, okay, I've applied a $2 limit, so that it… I don't get, like, if anyone even gets my key.
Mayank: And if we see… if I go back.
Mayank: And I will show you this live, everyone, so please focus.
Mayank: As I said again, People will never show these things in this much depth, pay attention.
Mayank: It is 11,000… tokens out and tokens thing. The second I sent another high.
Mayank: this Anthropic key is being used. See, it is sending each and everything. So, I just sent a simple hi, which is one token.
Mayank: It is 11624.
Mayank: Okay, but let's try to guess how many tokens will be sent here.
Mayank: Because you should all be knowing about this as well. And I know that if you have focused and concentrated in the class, all of you will be following.
Mayank: So, somewhere around 1292 tokens. So, even though I sent a single token, It will increase by…
Mayank: It will go to around 12,000. Let me finish.
Mayank: If it is very fast, we can see what is subtype.
Mayank: So, it will get refreshed in some time, but I hope all of you get the idea, like, what is the problem. And it is saying I use Sonnet 4
Mayank: I'm using Sonnet 4.6 here. I can make it Haik
Mayank: And just for all of you all, for the last time, I will send a hi.
Mayank: This time, it will be Haiku.
Mayank: This time it will be Haiku.
Mayank: And yeah, everything is being sent again as well.
Mayank: So let's refresh and we will see the same.
Mayank: So, cool. I hope I should take all the notes.
Vasudev N: Yes, yes. Thank you so much, Mike. Thank you.
Mayank: Okay.
Ashish Tyagi: Hi, Mat.
Mayank: Just a minute, let me tell. Ankit, you can ask it out.
Ankit USA: Yeah, hey.
Ankit USA: Hi, Meng, thanks for offering me. Thank you so much for amazing session, actually, today, and I enjoy for the
Ankit USA: learn a lot. So my question is, like, yeah, the same question, like, Bashu asked. What's happening here? My issue is of… not issues, like, I want to understand that, like, I suppose I just start a first session, and I just say hi, right?
Ankit USA: So, what happening sometime, I object, like, okay, you have used, like, a 4K token, and sometime it's showing, like, a 30K token, right? So, my question is, like, in enterprise version, suppose we are offering any kind of solution or anything, and then client asks, like, okay.
Ankit USA: how you can optimize the cost, or how, like, suppose we are going to prepare any kind of solution, right? They're asking for, suppose, this kind of tools, if you design, what is the expectation for cost? So, how we can, like, estimate that kind of cost?
Mayank: based on tokens only. So now that you know the basics, see, cost will only depend on tokens, not on anything else, it will not depend. That is clear.
Ankit USA: Yeah, but there is any kind of tool, enterprise tool, or cloud…
Mayank: There are tools, there are tools, like, there are analytics here as well. Plus, there are some monitoring tools, so these…
Ankit USA: Hello?
Harshit Goyal: I think he's 3'd.
Ankit USA: I think I lost my…
Shashi: Yeah, New York.
Ankit USA: Yep.
Ankit USA: Bank, I actually, I lost it was, yeah.
Anshul: Let's wait, let's wait, let'.
Ankit USA: You know.
Anshul: Okay, if I understand, your question is related to how… how can we price any… any solution, right?
Ankit USA: Yeah, yeah, that's correct. It's like, I suppose that, we are part of the cloud technologies, but actually I'm part of the cloud technologies team. So suppose they are asking for any kind of estimation for infrastructure, right? So suppose we are going to deploy any kind of agent or anything. So they ask for that. Okay. Suppose we are going to use any kind of models. So how, what is the cost estimation? Like every server has some of the cost estimations.
Ankit USA: Like, I suppose we are going to use, like, that kind of infrastructures.
Ankit USA: we are estimating, like, I suppose that $1,000, $2,000, or $5,000. So, similar kind of things, like, that user ask for the, like, okay, if you're going to deploy any kind of tool, and you're going to use that models, and
Ankit USA: Definitely, that is depend on the sum of the use cases.
Anshul: I got that question. I think Mike is back.
Mayank: Yeah, sorry, sorry, everyone. I faced an issue. So Ravi, I think I was explaining you that how, yes, there are tools, which help us in handling this and which maintain. So again, we have to make sure that we understand all these things at least. now I hope you understand that.
Mayank: That is where, again, yeah, most people are not aware, and we are having lots of tools, right? This is, like, for example, AgentOps for observability.
Mayank: Leading developer platform for building agents and observability.
Anshul: Okay.
Mayank: You all do you think?
Anshul: Meg, sorry to cut you, buddy. I think… I think the question is about estimation, not about monitoring.
Mayank: No, but estimation will come after that only, no? Once you can estimate that how much cost and everything will come up.
Anshul: No, no.
Mayank: That'.
Anshul: For example, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Mayank: estimation overall.
Anshul: Yes, yes.
Mayank: Okay, so…
Mayank: Again, that is a little bit dependent on observability, but along with that, you have to see that how you have trained your agent. For example, whenever your agent is calling any tool, or whenever you are giving it, for example, you will see that there is a maximum number of tokens, 4K only, right?
Ankit USA: So, this…
Mayank: This can give me an idea that, hey, it will never go in 4K, even if the user use and ask it 4K tokens.
Mayank: Let's say it cost somewhere around… for 1 million tokens.
Ankit USA: I think it is.
Mayank: $5?
Mayank: So, at max, it can be 4K. So, in that ways, we do the estimation, and plus lots of observation that normally how it is performing.
Mayank: And whatever result you are getting. So lots of experimentation from our end is there, of course. Along with that, we can have these thing sets that, hey, so many of you must have heard about that caveman mode and everything.
Mayank: So, hey, make sure that you are not unnecessarily expanding on the question, keep it very small, ask for any context.
Mayank: And plus, all the information which is flowing in and out, the better you understand your tokens, the better you will be able to understand the cost. So that is the case.
Ankit USA: yeah so I can say that like a suppose that if I can give a estimation like the suppose you are going to call like a thousand of request per chatbot and our maximum token is like a four thousand so maximum cost going like like a one thousand multiplied by four thousand something right and that is.
Mayank: tokens.
Ankit USA: Yeah, 400K. Like, 1000 multiplied by 400K. So that token is going to…
Ankit USA: Like a cost, like that kind of estimation, so suppose the request came like a 1 million, so accordingly we can calculate the cost.
Mayank: Exactly.
Ankit USA: That is the correct understanding, right?
Mayank: That is a correct understanding, but along with that, a little bit of monitoring we will add, because not all the chats will be of 4K, right? Not every output will be of 4K.
Mayank: For example, in here, this was just, what, 5, 7 tokens. So the input, input was high.
Mayank: And I think I'm showing you this here as well, that it didn't increase much, it increased a lot.
Mayank: But yes, that is how you estimate the cost for your AI solutions. By understanding the token economics.
Ankit USA: But Mayank here, one thing, suppose we just optimize our token, like a maximum context is like a 4,000 or 5,000 token kind of things, right? So once we give that context, suppose our context window reach to like a 4,000 or 4K, like that particular tokens.
Ankit USA: then definitely AI is not going to…
Ankit USA: Help, or, like, we have to reset that context or something like that, right?
Mayank: Either we will have to summarize the context, either we will have to leave out the context. So you will say that, hey, I will just send 20K of the latest context.
Mayank: I will not send everything, so that is how we will handle it then.
Ankit USA: Okay, and second question, I got it, thank you so much. And second question is like a, like a, that, like a currently, we are working with like a ChatGPT Claude models, right? So can we download that model and internally install on the servers or something? No. No?
Mayank: Why will people purchase clothes?
Ankit USA: Okay, but I heard about that, it's like a China-related, lot of.
Mayank: No, no, no, so they should be then open source. Companies should provide So…
Ankit USA: No, I think a lot of stuff.
Mayank: I've heard about, Manus, GLM,
Mayank: So there are models which you can still download, but companies provide them. Like, for example, GPT has just given one open source model till now, GPT-OSS.
Mayank: Okay. This you can download, but not GPT-5 Claude Haiku Claude for it. No, you cannot download that.
Mayank: I think Claude is not even… it is a single model as of now for the public.
Mayank: Okay, so that is, again,
Mayank: If I show you, like, now, for even another, how the things will connect, see?
Mayank: Okay, this is context, let me show you, yeah. So, see, deep-sea carbon, which caused that trillion-do
Mayank: How it is having a different version. 1.5 billion parameters, 7 billion parameters, all the way to 671 billion parameters.
Mayank: 671 billion parameter is 4.04 GB in size.
Ankit USA: Okay.
Mayank: So this you can self force, this you can have on a hardware. You should need a good hardware, not these things.
Mayank: Cool.
Ankit USA: And, one last question is, like,
Mayank: Totally quick, yeah.
Ankit USA: first.st O, yeah, yeah.
Mayank: I'll get a little quick because other people are also waiting.
Ankit USA: Yeah, yeah. I'm done now, I think so.
Mayank: Okay, good, no fear.
Mayank: If you ever need to edit it out, keep your hands up.
Mayank: Shashi… sorry, one second. Shashi, you are next.
Shashi: Yeah,
Asutosh: Oh.
Shashi: Yeah, I, in a, in a multi-user environment where we have, multiple, users and multiple contacts in enterprise client server environment, who is responsible to store this, contacts per users? Is it, is it someone?
Mayank: No problem.
Shashi: Who does it?
Mayank: So, Freddie Laput, you as an AI engineer, or an Agentic AI engineer.
Shashi: Yeah, but it's in… it's… where it's stored, it's in the API server, or it.
Mayank: DB, you will get your own database.
Shashi: Okay.
Mayank: So you will get either SQL DB, NoSQL DB, MongoDB, PostgreSQL.
Shashi: Okay, okay, all right, all right, thank you.
Mayank: One minute, one minute. Ashutosh?
Asutosh: Yeah, hello, so… so you have said, like, agent means it's a LLM memory plus tools, right?
Mayank: Yes.
Asutosh: But, actually I saw, in a link chain, so when the code you have shown on link chain code, so, there we have, like, a create agent.
Asutosh: And then we have tools.
Asutosh: So there are… and model and tools, both we have. Like, we can connect to some models, then we have some tools, but there is no memory there.
Mayank: It is there. It is addressed separately, actually.
Asutosh: Actually, so because I have some.
Mayank: I believe.
Asutosh: Antenna is different and here it's different.
Mayank: Does it.
Asutosh: The region is different, so…
Mayank: Doesn't matter, what I've taught you.
Asutosh: Click.
Mayank: What I've taught you is the
Mayank: It will never happen that any agent will not have MV.
Mayank: It can never happen. What I've taught you is irrespective of anything, irrespective of LangChain, GUI.
Asutosh: Okay. So, okay, so this code I want to understand, actually.
Mayank: So this we will start covering from the next week, now we will understand Nanshin then.
Asutosh: Okay.
Mayank: So we will start now with the frameworks that your basics are clear, because otherwise I will have to explain this memories and all these things, but now everything will connect. So yeah.
Asutosh: Okay. And another thing, actually, in Agent, can we have multiple LLMs also? Can we integrate? So if so, then how they will coordinate or how they orchestrate to work?
Mayank: You would like to tell me?
Mayank: You have to tell.
Asutosh: So that agent will do that, means…
Mayank: Agent will.
Asutosh: Tech flow will work.
Mayank: agent will do, but you have to tell that. For example, In this…
Asutosh: For example, I have a multiple LLM cloud, I open AI, I have connected like almost year, year and night and.
Mayank: There is a there is.
Asutosh: Right, right.
Mayank: Enable fallback model.
Asutosh: Mmm.
Mayank: So now I can have a fallback model as well. And let's say that I select OpenAI here.
Mayank: So whenever my Anthropic will fail, the request will go to OpenAI.
Asutosh: So that logic, we have to write it, or is it, no, no, no, I mean, it will do automatic.
Mayank: It is on you. If you are creating your agent, you will have to define it. In an agent, they have defined it like
Mayank: I feel that it is… also has a…
Mayank: fallback engine, but you have to define, like, how you want to use that. You have to define that logic. Is it, like, when the first one
Mayank: Is it like both of them?
Asutosh: Oh.
Mayank: Can you repeat the version?
Mayank: See? Automatically fall back to alternative model when the primary model fails. So it is the same logic here.
Mayank: So exactly the same.
Asutosh: So, if it is failed, it will go to another LLMs.
Mayank: Yes.
Asutosh: Okay.
Mayank: You can give it, like, ideally…
Asutosh: Oh, okay.
Mayank: You can give any number of models. It's totally on you. You can give any number of brains to your agent.
Asutosh: But here we are not writing logic now, so no more.
Mayank: We will know later.
Asutosh: So it will done by the framework means length chain automatically.
Mayank: See, all these frameworks do.
Mayank: is what I've taught you. So they just help you to do the same thing. But I wanted to make sure that you should not feel that framework helps you to do these things. Rather, in the code which I've shared with all of you.
Mayank: I'm able to do all of these things just via, python.
Mayank: Nothing else.
Asutosh: Okay.
Mayank: So you can create your own framework as well, if you are able to handle these things properly. So that.
Asutosh: Okay, so are you covering this RAG agent, means how to integrate RAG with agents also? Yes.
Mayank: Yeah, yeah, yeah, there will be proper RAG in-depth knowledge, everything will.
Asutosh: How about this multi-agent, actually? There is a sir, like, you know?
Mayank: You you don't.
Asutosh: Related to 8 to 8, okay.
Mayank: Everything will be covered, but you will have to give me time. Now we will start with the coding part, with the frameworks. I think I will just showcase this thing to you once. I will expect that you run through it. As in the next class, I will showcase and quickly do a project, and then we will start with LangChain.
Mayank: So that…
Asutosh: For agent development, so on the length chain, which we can do in any framework you choose.
Mayank: Teamwork.
Asutosh: but you will be cover online chain or.
Mayank: No, no, I will cover.
Asutosh: Everything.
Mayank: I will cover like few of them which were mentioned in your course, but more or less, once you understand the basics, we will do a project assisted learning.
Mayank: Where rather than actually going on every framework, I will show that, hey, let's create a project and you will understand because then it will be just a syntax change, honestly.
Asutosh: Okay.
Mayank: Okay? But all famous will do this only, nothing else.
Asutosh: Okay, so yeah, that's pretty much from my side.
Asutosh: And yeah, Lama index is there another framework, as I believe.
Mayank: See, there can be hundreds of frameworks. As I said, that is what I don't want you to think about. That is my only.
Asutosh: Okay, for anything, I mean, so if you want FMR we're doing, so replicate like that, we can do in other, like that you are saying.
Mayank: You know what a pizza.
Asutosh: Sorry?
Mayank: You know what a pizza is?
Asutosh: I don't.
Mayank: There are hundreds of chains of pizza. Pizza.
Asutosh: Good job. Okay.
Mayank: So, I'm teaching you what Pizz.
Asutosh: No, you.
Mayank: Hundreds of these.
Asutosh: Of course.
Mayank: Okay.
Asutosh: Okay, fine. So that's all from my side.
Mayank: Thank you, thank you, thank you, thank
Mayank: Rashim Suhaib… sorry, Rashim is first.
Rashim: Yes. Yes, ma'am.
Ashish Tyagi: Hello.
Mayank: Ask it out. Yeah, yeah, sure.
Rashim: Hi, Mayank. Thank you for explaining it very well. So, Mayank, what I…
Ashish Tyagi: So…
Rashim: I, I just need to just clarify my understanding. So the, initially you explained those, web interfaces for, chat, GPT and Claude, and then you explain using an API which is stateless.
Rashim: Then you jumped on to the agent, so agent is working like the web chat GPT with tool calling and the memory management. So that is why these agents are getting so much popular these days.
Mayank: Claude is an agent, it is not Claude.ai or Claude.ai website or ChatGPT, they are agents, they are not AI
Mayank: Go ahead and everything now, yeah.
Rashim: Okay, okay. And, Mayank, if I can visualize, because,
Rashim: First time I'm able to understand it and able to visualize it. So when I visualize, I understand things better. So agent is like an external code which calls, LLM model, which calls, which, which calls tool, which calls, the memory. It's, it's, it's actually orchestrate everything. So agent is an external code.
Mayank: I would not say it's an external code, I would say that it's a comb.
Rashim: So, combination karne geli hai, wo kuch koch.
Mayank: No, external polygons. No, external polyg.
Rashim: Hello, external lover, can you please give me an extract? Code leaker.
Mayank: Oh, that's where you're.
Rashim: Baswahi hai, na. Aur, aur, maiin jo, web search ka result aata hai, uska summarize sevo na chahiye, because jo, LLM n.
Mayank: Before I open it.
Rashim: Okay.
Mayank: The way you define it. That is why Claude is doing so good, right?
Rashim: Right.
Mayank: So, you can batch here, you can use this kind of system. So, you can pass it to agents, but now you can use it. So, you can send a message, or you can make a decision. Dependent on the use case, right?
Mayank: So, akan mai lagta hai gin ini aa saara sev karna chahiye kuch hwar bhi poo sakta hai. Toh saara kar lagta hai ini aa kya fajda hai tai na bhai baad na.
Rashim: I mean, one small question. Just like, when I, send an input, like, tell me about Sachin or Virat Kohli, it will first go to my agent, agent will hit LLM, and then LLM,
Rashim: you know, it will… first DB, it will… from DB, it will collect all the chats, and then it will give to LL.
Mayank: Yeah, so it will first get all the chats.
Rashim: Correct. Collect all the checks.
Mayank: Send the message with all the chats and your current message to LLM.
Mayank: Sir LLM bata hai ga. Ansat deh deh ga, toh ansat deh deh ya. Agar mu bolta hai tool call karo toh fae agent deh ga, chai LLM tool call aur nahi kele.
Rashim: Aur beech mein foo last mein memory mein wo chat se.
Mayank: Kumalo akin deko ye saree components hai, wo akyu pada pukba. Saad kisan se.
Rashim: Okay.
Mayank: It can be depended on framework as well, but…
Rashim: Aur mein jo memory mein seh wa, wo actually context window ka size hai.
Mayank: Madam, yaar pe jo memory aus ko mein chat history bona chaungga.
Rashim: Okay, okay. I'm not sure if it's the same model, but obviously, there is a difference on the… on the parameters and the… on the chat… chat, and, like, the context window. So, your models are different LLMs, are…
Mayank: So, OpenAI has given me ChatGPT 2, ChatGPT 5, Sonnet, Anthropic has given me Sonnet 2, Haiku 2, Opus 2, Stronger, Jada D
Mayank: So jada first libi hai. Jada chajd Yes.
Rashim: LLMs in this area.
Mayank: LLMs, sorry, LLMs, large language models.
Rashim: Okay. Thank you, Meng. Now I'm confident at least I can write some code to make an agent.
Mayank: I am pretty sure that everyone will be comfortable. I didn't start. That is the reason I'm not starting with LangChain directly.
Rashim: Thank you, man.
Mayank: Thank you.
Mayank: Suhab.
Mohamed Suhaib: Yeah, I… I might. So, based on the user query, LLM is the one deciding which agent to route that user query or to call, right? So, LLM is the.
Mayank: One minute, one minute, one minute LLM is part of agent.
Mayank: If you have a multi-agent setup, then you can have a case that if you're getting a query, then which agent should be called.
Mohamed Suhaib: Yeah, yeah, my question is that only. If we have multi-agent, so LLM is deciding, based on the user query, which agent to call, correct?
Mayank: If you… again, see, that architecture is on you, but normally, yes, we take an LLM.
Mohamed Suhaib: Okay, one more question. If we have multiple queries, and, what is the use of the, orchestrated reagent? If we have multiple queries, which, query should, address first, like that, there will be, like,
Mayank: We define it, we give it the system instructions, no? For example, I can tell my AI, That he…
Mayank: If there is any request related to… if there is any urgent request related to ticket solving or something, take that first. So then your agent will perform…
Mayank: Over there. Dependent.
Mohamed Suhaib: So, what is the orchest.
Mayank: You can do those things.
Mohamed Suhaib: Orchestrate region.
Mayank: Orchestrator is just orchestrating. First, this, that, this, like, that is what the main, that was the definition of orchestration is. And don't get confused. What I've told
Mayank: If it orchestrates something tomorrow, you will call it orchestrator agent. If it solves some problem, you will call it customer agent. So don't get confused. I will highly, highly request. Please stay with my definitions.
Mayank: If you think that, man, what is this orchestration agent, what is this customer support agent, no.
Mayank: Just…
Mayank: Make sure that what I'm explaining you, the way I'm explaining you, keep it like that. It will be a long and very good journey.
Mayank: If you're confused with all these terms which are coming around that.
Mayank: You will get confused. You understand what Agent is today?
Mohamed Suhaib: Yeah, I understand.
Mayank: That is.
Mohamed Suhaib: The routing mechanism based on the user query is decided by the, like, the… yeah, LLM, right?
Mayank: Ideally, yes, but you can have a if statement as well. You can simply have a if, not if, if else statement as well. It's totally on you.
Mohamed Suhaib: Like, particular which agent to, take the action? Like, which agent to route that part? There is nothing.
Mayank: Again, see, I have not discussed about multi-agent, let's.
Mohamed Suhaib: Okay.
Mayank: clear this out, where I will talk about multi-agent, then we can discuss it.
Mohamed Suhaib: Thank you.
Mayank: Thank you.
Mayank: Anshul, you are next. Hakan, I understand I normally keep it in English, but if someone is comfortable in Hindi, then my main aim or priority is to clear that out. So, if he's able to understand in Hindi or any language, any other language which I know, I will explain in that.
Mayank: If you want, I can summarize the same in English towards the end, but my aim is that the person should get that out clear, but otherwise, I think 99% everything is in English.
Mayank: Anshul.
Anshul: Amen.
Mayank: Bye.
Anshul: Hi. So, I have a few questions. Number one is, you showed that, platform.openai, the dashboard, right? Yeah. And, when we call the API,
Anshul: the tokens got refreshed, right? And then you showed us that, the number of tokens, input and output tokens consumed, right?
Anshul: So, the tokens was very less, it's just because that was a stateless API call, is that correct?
Mayank: Really, I didn't use it. Stateless has nothing to do.
Mayank: The two…
Anshul: Oh no.
Mayank: That's.
Anshul: Lindse.
Mayank: Pause.
Anshul: See, when I call, let's say, when I call OpenAI API, let's say, from any time.
Anshul: And I… I'm not attaching any memory, and they are simply right high, right?
Mayank: Yep.
Anshul: So… It's a stateless call, right?
Anshul: Let's suppose there's no memory, there's no memory.
Mayank: This one was.
Anshul: Different
Anshul: So, it's a stateless call. There are no… let's say, there are no agent instructions and anything. So, in that case, I simply ask a question, the LLM replies.
Anshul: Then I ask a next question, then LLM reply. In that case, the input-output tokens are very less, because it's a stateless code, right?
Mayank: Yes.
Anshul: Yeah, I just wanted to,
Mayank: It's a wrong understanding. It's the wrong basics
Mayank: Malab, every call is a status call only, no?
Anshul: No, I… that I understand. Every call is a stateless call.
Mayank: You should say it like the tokens were less because we were not sending previous context or chat history. That's a much better framing of your concept doesn't mixed up.
Anshul: Yes, yes, it's actually, I wanted to understand the actual stateless call, but I now understand that you have memory, it takes everything.
Anshul: It brings everything, stores in memory, and then it develops a context in the.
Mayank: Yep.
Anshul: In the chat history, right? Yeah. Second thing is, I wanted to ask you a question about the branching concept in ChatGPT, and why I'm asking is because I was having a conversation with my
Anshul: agent, you know, in, ChatGPT, and, I was learning something, and the chat became very long, you know? And then I remember somewhere I read that I can branch it, because I could see that, I could see that it was taking a lot of time in replying.
Anshul: And then I branched it, and then I created a few branches as my conversation went on. So, my question is that when I branch a conversation in ChatGPT,
Anshul: Does it squeeze my context window? it removes.
Mayank: I will have to read how ChatGPT handles it, but let me still explain how the branching works.
Mayank: Oh.
Mayank: Let me have this. See, the whole idea of branching is that you can just branch it in a new chat, so everything down will be kind of gone.
Mayank: Okay?
Mayank: I think it does the summarization when you do the branching. How can I say? I think, see, many things these people don't say out loud or don't just tell. These are very simple. Now, don't you think that if ChatGPT has implemented and it will tell how it has implemented, Claude will also copy it?
Mayank: Right?
Mayank: I hope that makes sense.
Anshul: Yes, yes, yes.
Mayank: So, in that case, but I have also used branching on a very, very long chart.
Mayank: And I have seen the results improve, so I feel that, yes, in that case, it tries to summarize your previous chart. So it does a compact of your context, so it is able to tell you a better answer.
Mayank: So, when your chart becomes a lot long, when you branch it out.
Mayank: It makes sure that it is summarizing the previous one so that you will keep on chatting longer with the less context. So that is the idea.
Anshul: So, it provides me, it excuses my chat history and then my context… it gives me additional context window.
Mayank: So that is the case. Like, see, it is very simple to understand. Let's say that you have around 50 messages, somewhere around 50 messages.
Mayank: When you do a branching.
Mayank: Okay, so these are the messages. When you say that, hey, I'm going to br
Mayank: So, what happens when you branch it out? Let's say you're going to branch it out
Mayank: ChatGPT will take all these chat.
Mayank: And say that this is the final context which I'm getting.
Mayank: This is the final context which I'm getting. Of course, it will lose out on many things and everything, but at least it saved your context window. Now, it was, let's say, somewhere around…
Mayank: All these messages were somewhere around 200k tokens. Let's say at least it made it 250k tokens.
Mayank: So now, of course, you have lots of context window, and…
Mayank: It will be pretty good at answering, and it will not be slow as well.
Mayank: Good.
Anshul: Yeah, it's Salesforce. And I have a
Anshul: Another question. I asked it in the chat, probably I couldn't frame it properly.
Mayank: You can tell again, chat and get lots of messages, so…
Anshul: Yeah, no problem. So, so, when, when I, when I pass a prompt, you showed tokenizer, right? So I can actually prompt and see how many tokens are there in the prompt.
Mayank: Rightly, yes. That is more or less right, yeah.
Anshul: Yeah, so if I enter a prompt there, and it gives me the number of tokens. So I was looking at the… because it colors out one token, right? You can see exactly, okay, if I pass my MA, then MA is one token.
Mayank: Anyone here.
Anshul: So, I could notice that, okay, a token is having two characters, let's say, another token is having four, another token is having three. So, is this the, is this the, is this, is this decided by the, that, that, tokenizing?
Mayank: And there are tokenizer models, we are having tokenizer.
Anshul: Yeah, so they decided not to.
Mayank: Yeah, yeah, so they decide, like, see, it is not based on the character length, so here This… able…
Mayank: is having lots of things, rather this un is just a single one. So normally, if you will notice.
Mayank: And is used a lot, right? Unbelievable…
Mayank: Unmatched. So, in its learning, it's understood that, hey, this un has to be treated separately. Whenever this un comes above in front of us of somewhere.
Mayank: It changes the meaning. So that is how the learning has happened, and that has actually been a years of process now. But yeah, that is the way it kind of handles these things.
Anshul: Okay, okay.
Anshul: Okay. I have one last question. I'm sorry.
Anshul: So this is, again, I think a lot of people had asked this question about orchestration part, and I…
Anshul: Oh, okay.
Mayank: Orchestration by definition means that you are orchestrating something like what should happen. This, then this, then this, then that. So step by step thing just.
Anshul: So, can you just go back to that entertain screen once? Just once, I'll quickly finish it. And this, you can remove that fallback metal, sorry, waterproof, that's not required. So, let's say, whenever I prompt this agent.
Anshul: So, now, there's something called agent instructions, right? So, there's a lot of agent instructions stored in the agent, right? What agent will… what kind of an agent it is, right? So, let's say, when I say, tell me, something about Virat Kohli.
Mayank: Okay.
Anshul: And this agent is connected to two tools, it is connected to memory, it's connected to an LLM. And then we can also define tools as well, right?
Mayank: All these…
Anshul: So, all the definition about tools and everything is stored at the agent level. So, agent knows that what tools I have. Yeah.
Anshul: So, when I say that, okay, tell me something about Virat Kohli, so,
Mayank: The agent will collect all the things, previous messages, tool description.
Anshul: Okay.
Mayank: Is that correct?
Anshul: Pass it to L.
Mayank: It's, oh yeah, it will then pass it to LL.
Anshul: And then LLM will decide what to do with that.
Mayank: Yes, yes, yes. Brain to enemy, you know. Brain is a.
Anshul: Yes.
Mayank: So that is how, that is how it internally works.
Anshul: Okay, okay.
Anshul: Okay, fine. So, whenever we're going to work on agents in, let's say, LangGraph or LangChain, so this agent part, as one of our friends asked, this is a separate piece of code, which, you know, kind of, you know, decides what will happen, how it's going to happen.
Mayank: Honestly, it's pretty simple if you show how to create an agent.
Mayank: You just tell it, so agent, create deep agent, you give it the model, you give it the tool, you give it the system prompt.
Mayank: So…
Anshul: Yeah, but even LangChain, LangChain has, since we are calling this LangChain library here, but LangChain in background must be having a Python code and how it's going to work, right?
Mayank: Yes, yes, that is what this is. Like, we can see the Python code, like, I thought
Mayank: Comfortable. If you go on LangChain SDK,
Mayank: Then, like, you can see all the things, like, how it is written as well, if you want.
Mayank: you can easily just see the complete, complete guides as well, Vatlab, how it is so LangChain, ABI references…
Mayank: It is all nothing but code written in the backend, nothing else.
Mayank: So, now again, it becomes a little difficult to follow.
Anshul: Brilliant.
Mayank: It is all code, nothing else. It is.
Anshul: I don't want to go. I'm a no coder. So today's session was like for me.
Mayank: Honey, that was the idea. Like today's session was rather for everyone because many people were not from the any background. This is helpful. So that is what I made sure because see if I would have jumped here.
Mayank: Basics, we are new to, like, this is good for basics. Now you know that, okay, yeah, model, tools, system prompt is there, model tool is just that, so same thing, nothing else.
Anshul: No, very good session, ma'am. Thank you.
Mayank: Thank you. Ashish, you're next.
Ashish Tyagi: Go hard, man.
Mayank: Hi.
Ashish Tyagi: I have a small question that we have a… And,
Ashish Tyagi: There's two other sites, like.
Mayank: Ashish, your voice is getting cut a little, can you repeat?
Ashish Tyagi: Hi, hi, whatever.
Mayank: Yes, yes, you're.
Ashish Tyagi: So, my question is that we are doing an element one, two chat window, website, and two APIs.
Ashish Tyagi: Bye.
Mayank: Yep.
Ashish Tyagi: So will the detail of during certain other things like the prompt will keep.
Ashish Tyagi: Adding my last prompt.
Mayank: In ChatGPT web, yes.
Ashish Tyagi: Right? So the behavior of this is going to remain same in Api.
Mayank: No, API, you have to handle those things.
Mayank: API is stateless.
Mayank: API, you have to send previous messages if you want the reply, you have to handle all those things. Basically, what ChatGPT is doing, you have to do it yourself.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: Wait, one minute.
Mayank: So… I think it was Harshith, right? Harsh.
Harshit Goyal: Yeah, hi. Hi, ma'.
Mayank: Just one minute, Rashid. I think you were the one, right? After that, I muted Forward it, Hardik.
Mayank: Okay, you can ask. I think Harshita and Haldika was confused.
Harshit Goyal: So, Mayank, couple of things, right? One is, we used Heather tool, and then…
Harshit Goyal: The tool that you showed in N8N is something that creates the subscription and something you need the key.
Harshit Goyal: Yeah. So we… we need to… so if we need to… I mean, either… there are two options, like, we can… we can have our… find our own tool, or use any existing tools, right? Yes. And here as well, we have to… I mean, like, there will be a chart to our enterprise, right?
Mayank: Yeah, sure.
Harshit Goyal: Okay, and
Harshit Goyal: Okay. like, just coming back to the previous question, when somebody was asking about the cost estimation.
Harshit Goyal: Like if you go to any of the CSP, right, maybe GCP or Azure, they give us like a pricing calculator. You can estimate the things and share it with the stakeholders, right? Yeah. Do we have any such thing like available probably from the platform perspective where we talk about these old things and do it?
Mayank: Oh.
Mayank: Like, see, when you're creating our own agents, the way we will create in this class.
Mayank: It will not be just possible by a tool, because we will be controlling multiple things. So on that note, it's not that, yeah, this is the tool, it will tell you everything. That wouldn't be possible that easily.
Mayank: We have observation and monitoring tools which tells that, hey, this is how it is helping and everything. So that is there.
Mayank: But not… but not…
Mayank: Like, okay, you have created anything, or you're thinking of creating anything, and it can give you the cost.
Mayank: That estimation you will be able to do after lots of practice and everything.
Harshit Goyal: Yeah, I mean, this conversation come because every time, if we reach out to client, and then in some other conversation, they were saying that LLM is expensive, right? Yeah. Definitely, they're talking about B2B, not these chatbots, or let's say, right? One more thing, on my end.
Harshit Goyal: So we have, like, we have got so… there's so many frameworks.
Harshit Goyal: Langchain, LangGraph, and we have A2A as well, which basically…
Mayank: Oh, yeah, it's a protocol.
Harshit Goyal: Protable, yeah, yeah. Why… I mean, are we going to cover this merits and demerits about this framework, whatever we'll learn? And another question to link to this, why we have so many frameworks?
Mayank: Just the reason we have so many languages.
Mayank: Actually, that's the reason, like, people are creating it, some people liked it, Microsoft, Google, Amazon, everyone is trying to create their own framework, because, just like how we have so many languages, nothing else.
Mayank: Mother, you can do it…
Harshit Goyal: In languages, the main criteria is something like, let's go to the, let's focus on the open source stuff, like, in the tools and language, like, for example, if I talk about Spark, right? Spark is open source, but if you talk about any, for, for example, if you talk about Foundry, it's not open source, right? Yeah. So, is it the same theory?
Harshit Goyal: We should think more on the framework side.
Mayank: Not really, like, people just… no, no, so there are frameworks which… all of them are, I think, open.
Harshit Goyal: Okay.
Mayank: about this, which one is closed source? Like, LangChain, everything is open source. Yeah, they are having their paid version as well.
Mayank: So the whole idea is that how…
Mayank: There are frameworks, like, people just started creating them, and companies are creating them, and we are picking it up as we like, so that is the case.
Harshit Goyal: Okay, last, one last question. Yeah, we know that we are going to cover this, probably, in the, in the upcoming sessions, but do we have any, any, you can say,
Harshit Goyal: like, the best practice, stuff, right? For what? To do a custom agent. To do the custom agent, which…
Mayank: It will depend on framework and your understanding, so not like…
Mayank: Like, what will be the best practice? To handle context better, to make sure that you provide the right tools, to give the proper instructions?
Mayank: So, once we understand the same in little bit much more depth.
Mayank: Then, I think it will be clear, but…
Mayank: Once, I think, yeah, once you understand this, then I think it should be clear only, there should not be a problem.
Harshit Goyal: Yeah, basically, this question comes because, see, we… something that I understand, but, you know, you are under such a position wherein you need to convince the business stakeholder, technical stakeholder, and so many other people, right?
Harshit Goyal: And there, if we have some kind of a best practices somewhere, you can reference them. And it's very easy for, because, you know, this trust also comes in the picture, but then this helps, when we do the solutioning, right?
Mayank: So, best practices are those only, like, see, you… best practices always all come to cost and everything, that when… when we do projects in here, I will show you that, hey, how every project is supported by a complete,
Mayank: Let's say support for… your…
Mayank: Observability, monitoring, cost handling, all these things. So those are the best practices, and along with that, the best practice is how you define an agent, which we will discuss, but…
Mayank: The list will be very generic kind of a list, like, that is not something. I would experimentation, and once you create projects, that would be much better in
Mayank: making stakeholders believe in you. So when you can showcase that, yeah, this is what I will do, that is way much, like, a.
Harshit Goyal: Yeah, okay, okay, yeah, thanks, thanks, Mayo.
Mayank: Hardik?
Hardik Vora: Hey, Mike. Hi.
Hardik Vora: Thanks, appreciated on clarifying many of those things.
Hardik Vora: Questions I also got clarified.
Mayank: Thank you.
Hardik Vora: So, Mike, if you can just share your screen for a minute, I had one doubt, on that,
Hardik Vora: Anytime.
Mayank: Any debits I would win.
Hardik Vora: Yeah, yeah.
Mayank: Yeah. Is it visible?
Mayank: Okay, not this.
Mayank: What are you seeing?
Mayank: Judy.
Hardik Vora: doing that started screen sharing, but it is blank for now.
Mayank: It is blank.
Mayank: That's right.
Mayank: One minute.
Hardik Vora: Yeah, lines and docs page I am.
Mayank: Now it is able to see. Yeah, cool. Sorry.
Mayank: So I was flip-cut open on another while I was trying to shop something, but it'll be fine.
Hardik Vora: Mmhm.
Mayank: Yep.
Hardik Vora: Yeah, just open the chat section.
Hardik Vora: The last conversation which you did, no? Yeah. So, see, last… yeah, wait, wait, wait. So, here.
Hardik Vora: You flipped the model, with the…
Mayank: But…
Hardik Vora: Execution haiku. And if you see in our input any which ways you have already mentioned that. Hi, Mayank, how are you? And all right in the input section, we already have given the context to Llm.
Hardik Vora: In the.
Mayank: Where in the, where exactly the…
Hardik Vora: column in the chat.
Hardik Vora: Third column in the chat.
Hardik Vora: Personally.
Mayank: On this, this one.
Hardik Vora: Yeah, yeah, in the input side, yes.
Mayank: Yep.
Hardik Vora: So, I hope it is already, if you can just scroll, I think you have already mentioned, hi, Mayank, correct? Actually, it is not known. No, no.
Mayank: No, no, no, I will tell evidence. I will tell why it turned on. This simple memory.
Hardik Vora: Okay.
Balaji Sundararaman: It just that's true.
Mayank: 5.
Mayank: So, though it is having all the messages, it will just send 5.
Mayank: To maintain the context length.
Mayank: So, the reason it has not sent this is that it is just sending these till 8.
Mayank: So, from here onwards, we will be seeing this, not the first one.
Mayank: So, you make it 15…
Hardik Vora: And…
Mayank: 300?
Hardik Vora: So this way we can optimize, but we will lose, the.
Mayank: Yes, yes, yes, exactly. This is what ChatGPT does. This is what happens. So if I will ask it, just let's try it out. Who am I?
Mayank: Let's.
Hardik Vora: He will not answer because he doesn't.
Mayank: It is having the milk, I don't think.
Hardik Vora: No, he's not having. Yeah, that is what.
Mayank: Thank you for talking.
Mayank: A fallback model…
Hardik Vora: Feel like you have removed, no? You have not sa.
Mayank: That helps.
Mayank: Let me just post.
Mayank: Oops, sorry.
Mayank: That's the best example of context.
Hardik Vora: Okay, got it.
Mayank: Because in my chat history I'm not sending it, so it lost it.
Hardik Vora: Yeah, so, in memory, I have understood, Mayank, that what you were saying. But one basic question, I mean, instead of sending all
Hardik Vora: you have mentioned simple memory for now, I understand, we will work on conversation memory and all, I mean, other types of long-term, short-term memory in future, but just a basic question, if I want to create a simple chatbot which goes to a web search, and I want to optimize it in a way that all the contact doesn't go there.
Hardik Vora: So, one thing is context, the length which you've mentioned, that 5 and all, that we can do.
Hardik Vora: Yeah. But I want to, save all the previous conversations, so I.
Mayank: You can.
Hardik Vora: have a summarization model, I can ask it to maximum summarize and then take it in a next conversation. So that context, but we will lose some of those. I can also understand everything it cannot save. Yeah. So is there a way? Okay, my question is directly, I will reframe my question.
Hardik Vora: In the earlier question, you've mentioned FIFA as well as calculator, correct?
Mayank: Well.
Hardik Vora: What if I want, to mention it that focus on only on the specific topics.
Hardik Vora: Okay, so that… we also know that we can mention it specifically in system.
Mayank: Mmh.
Hardik Vora: So that it has a context, but…
Hardik Vora: I want all those, whatever system I have created.
Mayank: I think what you're mentioning, let me, let me, I think I.
Mayank: You were saying that how can I make sure that all the messages which are saved, I could just send the relevant one, right?
Hardik Vora: Correct, correct.
Mayank: So, as an example, Mayank, if… In Claude.
Mayank: Let's say that you are having this conversation.
Mayank: periodic table.
Hardik Vora: Goodie.
Mayank: I don't want to do that FIFA Wala thing.
Hardik Vora: Correct.
Mayank: I'll answer the next question. Don't send this message, send just these two messages.
Mayank: How will you take that call?
Mayank: How do you do that, Colin?
Hardik Vora: Can we… okay, I'm just trying to understand, from implementation perspective, can we specifically mention it in our system message, that this is what we need to focus on? Other questions, if it is there, you can politely ask them to…
Mayank: Sure, sure, just one minute, okay.
Mayank: One minute, one minute. Yeah, let me ask that question to you. It will clear… I got your question, I will explain that out as well, see.
Mayank: So, I will tell you what the fundamental problem with your doubt is, and how can we solve it.
Hardik Vora: Sure.
Mayank: You just have to focus on the blue, points.
Mayank: But tell me that.
Mayank: No, I think it.
Hardik Vora: It's not getting displayed, Ming. I think I'm just able to see that. Sorry, sorry.
Mayank: No, no, no worries. Actually, I didn't share the complete screen because I disconnected my machine. See?
Mayank: I'm saying that, just tell me, just tell me, Okay.
Mayank: Focus just on the green things.
Hardik Vora: Okay.
Mayank: But tell me if it is large, if the squares are greater in red or green.
Hardik Vora: Squares are written in red.
Mayank: So you have to see the red one.
Hardik Vora: Mmm.
Mayank: Now, if you go here, you say that, hey, just focus… you ask it that, hey, just focus…
Mayank: On the… previous messages related Two chemistry.
Mayank: Right?
Hardik Vora: Then…
Mayank: Then also this message will be sent out because it will take a call that is not related to chemistry.
Mayank: So I'll be back at square one.
Hardik Vora: Okay, okay, okay.
Mayank: Elizabeth?
Hardik Vora: Okay.
Mayank: Take the call if it is relevant or not as well. We need to pass it through a brain.
Hardik Vora: -H.
Mayank: Now even, it will be passed, and see, it doesn't care, it's clear that this is a message, this is a complete message.
Mayank: You are saying, I just want to see if it is relevant or not, but that is hidden here.
Mayank: If you want to write everything around Morocco, Canada, it will do that as well, but you are sending this message. One thing can be, we can tag it when we are reading it. Previous messages, memory can tag. Wait, this is related to FIFA.
Mayank: This other ability to do memory, then we can do it, but then again, it is also complex, because who…
Mayank: Today, it is fever, tomorrow it can be.
Hardik Vora: Okay.
Mayank: Book it.
Mayank: The more you think about this, in terms of saving.
Mayank: And that is where, again, people are doing this in the memory. There are frameworks. But yeah, the problem, the fundamental problem remains. To do something, you have to pass it to a brain.
Hardik Vora: It will pass, okay.
Mayank: Text only.
Hardik Vora: Really.
Mayank: Yeah, I'm glad I was.
Hardik Vora: Okay.
Mayank: cush.
Hardik Vora: Yeah, yeah, I was thinking from output in the semantics, I mean the cosine similarity, the close vector, dense vector, where it goes. I was thinking from that angle that I can only restrict to those conversation and politely ask them not to.
Mayank: That is RAG, that is a different concept, which is RAG, which I will explain as well, but that is a completely different thing.
Hardik Vora: Huh? But that way we can at least manage, right? I mean, what I'm trying to understand.
Mayank: Oh, for the Debbie, that's all these other pictures of Christmas.
Mayank: So there you go.
Hardik Vora: Your last voice.
Mayank: Sorry, one minute. I'm saying that that is, yeah, that is how we do context management and make sure that things work fine.
Hardik Vora: I mean, that way we can manage.
Mayank: Exactly.
Hardik Vora: And Mike, one more thing, I mean, as any which ways people have asked for the cost, and I understand what we have already answered, but.
Hardik Vora: So, overall, if we want to have an estimation on the LLM calls, one is clearly that whatever tokens we do R&D in, in the n number of,
Hardik Vora: Validations or testing with the chat history or whatever application we have built. There we will get some token usage and all in the tentative estimations can be provided with conditions applied that the more conversation or the more context you have that will reflect in your cost, correct?
Mayank: Yep.
Mayank: Yeah, so the better you will understand, the better you will understand these basics with me.
Mayank: the better you will be able to do that, because if you just think about it, it is nothing but that only, right? So…
Hardik Vora: Correct.
Mayank: It is related to context, tokens. People have made it very difficult. I totally give it to people that they have made it genuinely very difficult.
Mayank: But I feel that if you know the basics and you do it, then I think it's easily doable.
Hardik Vora: Okay, okay. Got it, got it. Thanks, man. Thanks.
Mayank: Fuck.
Mayank: One minute. Balaji, you are next.
Hemlata: Bye.
Balaji Sundararaman: Yeah.
Balaji Sundararaman: Hi, am I audible?
Mayank: Yes.
Balaji Sundararaman: Yeah, okay, so I have a question regarding not exactly what you're taught, but how you're taught it, so I'll make it quick. The way you explain in the Excalibur with all those diagrams really makes it very easy to understand the concept. I wanted to know, how do you pull in that image from that mini browser kind of thing that opens?
Mayank: to the next…
Balaji Sundararaman: Albert…
Mayank: I have connected my Google image via the Google Cloud account.
Mayank: to an application in Mac, which is Xcanny Draw.
Balaji Sundararaman: Let me just take.
Mayank: which is recast.
Balaji Sundararaman: Oh, okay, okay.
Mayank: So it's a little complex, because, again, I was… I love to teach by visualization, and I was.
Balaji Sundararaman: Yeah, that really helps, yes.
Mayank: 2-3 days I spent on this setup, where.
Balaji Sundararaman: Okay.
Mayank: Whenever I type something, it goes to the Google Images API.
Mayank: All that.
Mayank: Then I can copy it.
Mayank: And I have a raycast, which is there in Mac, which can help me to call this.
Balaji Sundararaman: Oh, okay.
Mayank: That is what I've.
Balaji Sundararaman: Okay, thank you.
Balaji Sundararaman: Thanks. Bye.
Mayank: Good.
Mayank: One minute. Hemlatha, you are next.
Hemlata: Yes, hi, Meng. Thank you for this extensive session. Thank you. First of all, this is my first session, so previous, like, before session already happened, which I missed, so from how do I start, from where should I start, what should I…
Mayank: Nathan?
Hemlata: No idea.
Mayank: Device, just device, take the classes, nothing else. For the Python, in the very first class, so there is a link which I've shared from everyone and asked you to bookmark it.
Hemlata: Yes.
Mayank: Just everything is there in that link.
Hemlata: Can you share in the chat, because I don't.
Mayank: I'm sharing, I'm sharing, I'm sharing it. So, that's the reason, like, everything, if you will try
Mayank: Each and everything, you will see that link.
Mayank: Class.
Mayank: any PDF, the Mayan GPT, which I referred to, GitHub, so everything is there.
Hemlata: Okay, so in the main GPT, we can ask the question.
Mayank: If I ask any question, it will explain the way I do with analogies, examples, line by line.
Mayank: So rather than chat GPT, it is also having context. When you ask it something, it will tell that why it is useful for Agentic AI and AI, rather than just generic.
Hemlata: Okay. Also, can you show… can you tell me the specification for new laptop? I want to purchase one personal laptop.
Mayank: I'm the worst person for that. I am kind of now a Mac guy, so I say Mac, but Mac has recently become expensive.
Mayank: Windows, I genuinely have no idea that how Windows, like, what is working in Windows.
Hemlata: If you need extra memory or processing.
Mayank: So honestly, I'm the best worst person for that. Just, I would highly suggest to ask someone else. I don't know about the GPU, et cetera. And hopefully if Mac becomes affordable, I will use Mac for life.
Hemlata: Okay, okay, maybe I can… on the chat group,
Mayank: Yeah, just ask in the chat group. I actually, because many people are asking, so I've also started now to research on this. Once I get an idea, I will create either a video.
Mayank: I'll try to showcase that with you, but as of now, honestly, I'm not the right person for this.
Hemlata: Okay, thank you. Also, if somebody's not from the IT industry, if they want to start with the AIC, since now AIC is a bubble and where new jobs are also coming, so can somebody who has a 10 years experience in different industry and can start with the AIC, so what course do you suggest, if any Krish Academy course is available?
Mayank: There is a course which I'm taking…
Mayank: It is on night, so every weekend I take the classes from 8pm to 11pm as well.
Mayank: it is AI for everyone, modern route. So there, we teach without any… so I'm not teaching these concepts without any coding or anything. Plus, there I'm teaching that how can you, like, yesterday I had a class where I taught them how to create avatars, these custom GPTs.
Mayank: How to… so, again, it is not technical. You are still creating projects, products, everything, voice agents.
Mayank: Without writing a code. So that you know when you sit in a room that, hey, what is RAG, what is
Mayank: And since I've taught that to a genuinely more than 50K plus professionals now, I think that is the best one for anyone who is not in the coding background.
Hemlata: But after learning that how one can start the career, like.
Mayank: So it will be, again, based on your current career only, plus you will have all the idea about how coding works, so how, sorry, how AI works. So let's say whatever field you are in.
Mayank: You will be able to do?
Mayank: I'll just take it.
Mayank: Yeah, you will be able to do a much better job, and you will know that how AI works and integrating AI, so that is the whole case.
Hemlata: Okay, okay.
Mayank: Okay, I think the link is sent to just a single person, I'm sending it again, just one minute.
Mayank: Actually, I have the person, single person selected.
Hemlata: Yeah, that's fine.
Mayank: Oh, it should be.
Hemlata: Thank you. Thank you. That's all for now.
Mayank: Thank you.
Mayank: Gopal, Krishan, you are next.
Gopikrishnan N: Hey? Hey, Mike? Thanks for the wonderful session.
Gopikrishnan N: Thank you. …understand it, really. And, one thing I want to understand, like, so you mentioned that, that, context, from different chats, basically, if you start a new chat,
Gopikrishnan N: we will be, starting that context first. We won't be keeping that context, but not sure, like, whether it is something specific to ChatGPT, but what I noticed is, like, if I am putting a chat
Gopikrishnan N: And after two days, I'm opening a new chat, but the subject is somewhat the same thing. So it is just remembering that you have already, as per your old conversation.
Mayank: Also, ChatGPT as a software has handled that, where it understands and where it sends your previous chat, as you'll see.
Mayank: ChatGPT.com is also an agent.
Mayank: Along with sending your request, it sends the previous chapter maybe in two, three lines around that. Let's say that it's sending the…
Mayank: Title of your chat.
Mayank: So, on that, it is able to tell, and see, that is where ChatGPT Claude, they are making it a lot better for the general audience.
Mayank: But as developers, we don't have to use them, we have to build them, right?
Gopikrishnan N: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Mayank: So, we can do that as well, like, we can build it easily, not a problem. When we build this project, I will showcase that, that how can we maybe create the same thing.
Mayank: But yeah, it should be doable, not a problem at.
Gopikrishnan N: But in that case, this, context, if you're following those also, that,
Mayank: No, it doesn't send the complete chat history, it just sends a summary or some title or summary.
Mayank: It doesn't… it never sends that, then. That is why your new charts are faster and cheaper overall.
Mayank: It doesn't say that, hey, I will be sending the complete, complete chat history, no. It sends us the context that, hey, what happened, maybe a summarization
Mayank: Or what you were doing, everything like that.
Gopikrishnan N: Okay, that is… that is fine, that is fine. And also, one last question, like, if you mentioned that we can put that memory, simple memory, or whatever, that new DB, whatever, whatever.
Gopikrishnan N: So, usually, then do we need to… usually, for our projects that what we are doing, similarly, do we need to design these tables and all, or will it automatically…
Mayank: Yeah. No, no, we have to define it.
Gopikrishnan N: Everything we need to do.
Mayank: Everything, each and everything.
Gopikrishnan N: Got it, okay.
Mayank: Okay.
Gopikrishnan N: Thank you.
Mayank: Oh.
Mayank: Until your next dental punch.
Mayank: People who I've talked to, please have your hands down
Mayank: I think Hemnutta Kopak is left out. Anshul Subhanch.
shubhansh: Hi, Ming.
Mayank: Thank you so much.
shubhansh: This is it.
shubhansh: Actually, my doubts have already been asked by Hardik regarding management. I have another, just a basic query, like, in our course, will we cover any… I mean,
shubhansh: will we, quantify the results? Like, for example, if we use different models for creating embedding.
shubhansh: or, or different LLM models we use, will we quantify the results so that we can show that to the interviewer or in our resume, like that?
Mayank: Yes, yes, in the projects we will be doing, where we will be using multiple different things and all that.
Mayank: So that… Wouldn't be.
shubhansh: Okay, okay.
Mayank: In the projects, we will do that. We will rather have a very, very good overall approach, like, where we will have
Mayank: A complete… Complete, complete.
Mayank: Let's see… Way of having multiple agents and all these things, so that should all be there.
shubhansh: Okay. And, I was just going through the difference between web and API.
Mayank: OK. Yeah.
shubhansh: So, let's say if I ask some questions which, let's say I ask to give some abusive kind of questions, query I have given, so…
shubhansh: In ePay, I'm getting the same result that it will not answer. And in web also, I'm getting the same. So there is some restriction in the model level itself, right, regarding securities and other things.
Mayank: It is majorly there in the API and in the… in the web, both.
Mayank: Web, I think it will be more there.
Mayank: No, sorry, it will be… it will be, I think, more there in both of them.
Mayank: So, few things it checks. Of course, it quickly checks the output many times than what it is getting.
Mayank: So, yeah, that is the case. But overall, yeah, it's a different, similar kind of a brain only.
Mayank: ChatGPT brain only, so it is giving you the answer, so that is the case, nothing else.
shubhansh: So we won't get any raw LLM there. So, I mean.
Mayank: You get up.
shubhansh: Be any of this.
Mayank: X.com, the Grok one, I think Elon must say that, hey, we don't have any limits or something.
shubhansh: Okay, okay.
Mayank: So, there are companies, there are open source ones as well.
Mayank: But then how good they are for other things, people have to test it out and everything. There's Venice AI, which is without any restriction.
Mayank: I can ping that link. So, you can ask it anything. It tries not to block your answers.
shubhansh: Okay, okay.
Mayank: But, yeah, like, for official use case, we normally go with these foundational models only.
shubhansh: Okay, okay, got it. That's it, man, thank you.
Fahd: I mean, can I jump in?
Mayank: When we retired, and you.
Fahd: Yeah, okay.
Mayank: Ancient.
Mayank: Okay, fine. You can ask your note.
Fahd: Okay okay thank you so much. Just one question around I think you may have already answered it in some capacity but this was around the toolings that you explained today. So you added a calculator and then you added a web search but just talking let's say specifically about the calculator can't the LLM
Fahd: do that, 2 plus 2, for example, rather than calling the calculator, or because the tool is added, it will call the calculator. Just, yeah, just a dumb question, but yeah, thank you for answering.
Mayank: Not a dumb question. See, ideally.
Mayank: LLMs are not very good with… Calculations.
Fahd: Right.
Mayank: The reason is very simple. They learn patterns.
Mayank: We learn patterns. Now, if you remember, in the initial days of ChatGPT, now ChatGPT also have a tool, so it will give a right answer.
Fahd: Right.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: If I showcase as well…
Mayank: Don't use any tool or calculator or anything.
Mayank: Strictly answer yourself.
Fahd: Right.
Mayank: So even though now they are smarter, but let's see still.
Mayank: I think it will use.
Fahd: I see.
Mayank: Okay, so one minute, let me change it.
Mayank: Okay. That's D.
Mayank: But yeah, normally the idea is that they are not very good, because they will predict the token. But how can you predict the calculation? Like, it is something which it is never seen, right?
Mayank: So now, I think it will give the right answer, because honestly, now they have gone a lot better.
Fahd: Right.
Mayank: But earlier that was not the case. So, inherently it has used some tool there, like, we can see that.
Fahd: Okay, okay, okay.
Mayank: Yes.
Fahd: Okay.
Mayank: It just used to be, like… so, you remember that how many are in strawberry, which many people test out, right.
Fahd: Yep.
Mayank: So, again, it has just seen the patterns, nothing else. So that is why we provide these tools, and normally as well, tools are needed.
Fahd: Got it, okay, thank you so much.
Mayank: Okay, whoop.
Mayank: Kian… Amit?
KiaanAAmit: Thank you.
Mayank: Hi.
KiaanAAmit: Yeah, thanks for your good session. I have one question, like, we use the GitHub Copilot, right? So, can we say, like, GitHub Copilot is also an agent?
Mayank: Yes, it is an agent.
KiaanAAmit: Okay. So like in agent, right? Like it, whenever we run the agent in GitHub Copilot, we give the prompt in that time we have the code, right? Code is in like in our IDE, correct? So it run and scan our code as well. Then only it given the code and apply on that, right?
Mayank: Yep.
KiaanAAmit: So, like, if you run separately, agent, so we are not giving the code. Then how we both work together? Same way.
Mayank: GitHub Copilot is having tools via which it can connect to your code and VS Code.
Mayank: Do they have that?
KiaanAAmit: Reference of my code, correct?
Mayank: Yeah, yeah, they have the tools by which they can read your files.
KiaanAAmit: And if, like, in my organization, right, people, like, senior people are creating the agent and providing us, let's use this agent and do such kind of task, right? So they don't have our code.
KiaanAAmit: But, that agent, when we run it, apply in our code as well. How that is work, actually?
Mayank: Really? So, what do you mean that they apply in your code? Like, if it is giving you, like, maybe it is having your company's code and the way it is written, so maybe it.
KiaanAAmit: Yes.
Mayank: read a little bit on that, or it understands it has an access to the GitHub, et
Mayank: So then it will.
KiaanAAmit: But not my code. Maybe, yeah, definitely, they,
KiaanAAmit: I think they create the knowledge base, right, and based on the code only, but my code is… was not when we… they created the agent.
Mayank: So, but what the agent is doing, which you feel that it is knowing about your code?
KiaanAAmit: See, like, I will give the exact example, right? Like, we do the functional test cases we are writing for our application, right? So for that, they created the agent. When I run that agent in my code, using my code, they create the functional test cases.
Mayank: Oh, so it can do that. See, it already knows that how you… it already knows how to write code.
Mayank: When you used it, it also got access to your code.
Mayank: So just as an example, Chad Mem GPT, which I've created, it knows how to code and everything. If you will give it some code, which you have written.
Mayank: Then…
Mayank: If you ask it to generate code, it will generate the code in a similar manner, the way you have given it earlier. So that is all possible, that is not an issue at all.
KiaanAAmit: Okay, so based on the knowledge…
Mayank: Not everything, no.
KiaanAAmit: Okay, yeah, yeah, I got it. Like, so based on the pattern they have, and same pattern apply to my code as well.
Mayank: Yeah, exactly. So it knows how to code, it quickly sees how you have written the code.
Mayank: And let's just make sure that going forward, it will just use the way you have written the code, so that's why it is a bit easy overall.
KiaanAAmit: Correct. Last question, like, that isn't, like, they shared, right? So that can be, like, a small file, and that we can use it.
KiaanAAmit: Like, I have created one agent.
Mayank: Instructions, yeah, agent, it is totally a new agent, can be just instructions.
Mayank: For Agent… for Copilot, it is just an AgentMD file, which tells that, hey, this is the tool. Normally, Copilot tools will be related to your, this thing, right? All related to your…
Mayank: excess of the files and everything. So, yeah, it's a simple tool, then. It's a simple file. It can be anything which you want, like, it can be a proper application like Hermes.
Mayank: It can be a simple file as well.
Mayank: Just, it should know which tool it has access to, it should have instructions or a brain.
Mayank: And it should have some memory, does that.
KiaanAAmit: So, like, I can also create one agent, which can be used for any other team, right? They can apply…
KiaanAAmit: Okay, I'm too…
Mayank: Just think of your agent like an intern. Just think of your agent like an intern.
Mayank: Seems like you're hiring a new intern. Just tell him what all you feel, and once you are able to tell him, then he will be able to do that. Just that, nothing.
KiaanAAmit: Okay, got it.
Mayank: Thank you. Thank you. Thank you. Yeah.
KiaanAAmit: Thanks.
Jitendra Biswal: Hi, Ginny.
Mayank: One minute. Yes, you can go.
Jitendra Biswal: Yeah, so regarding the agent, so is there any way I can understand the performance of an agent. It's like how the agent will know the whether it is calling to the right tool or not, right LLM or not, if I have multiple LLMs are there.
Jitendra Biswal: So, because why I'm asking these questions, I… in my company, they are using… because agent deployment happens in Databricks, and Databricks has an inherent capability to measure the… all the matrices of the agent.
Mayank: -H.
Jitendra Biswal: So I don't know how they do it. So I'm just asking because, because I'm learning agent, so I just want to ask this fundamental question.
Mayank: Yeah, nobody's going to see
Mayank: I think you're asking how you will rank, or how will you, like, judge your agent, right?
Jitendra Biswal: Exactly, because because there is a lot of like, you know.
Mayank: Let me.
Jitendra Biswal: You can download the agents, okay, or I can create my custom agent. So, how do I rank?
Mayank: Yep.
Jitendra Biswal: Origin from multiple vendors, also.
Mayank: Let's say that you have had two people, two intern.
Jitendra Biswal: Yeah, exactly.
Mayank: Forget agent, forget agent.
Jitendra Biswal: Yeah, I'.
Mayank: You have given them some work.
Jitendra Biswal: Mmhm.
Mayank: How will you judge them?
Jitendra Biswal: Yeah, best is their output.
Mayank: Exactly. Yeah. How they are working, how many tools are they using, are they calling the right tools? And you told that, hey, write me an email, it is not going to calendar.
Mayank: Yeah. So even though it seems magical and people think that it is all magic, no, just think of them like interns. The way you are trying to judge normally.
Jitendra Biswal: Mmhm.
Mayank: The way you're trying to judge your intern, that is what the same thing you will apply for.
Jitendra Biswal: Yeah, I mean, like, to measure it, do you have any other measuring.
Mayank: We have tools as well, we have tools as well, but you will have to still define what is good, what is bad. The tools will tell that how fast it is.
Mayank: How… What all it is doing, how much cost you're incurring, but the output and everything.
Mayank: You will have to define. So, for example, if I create an agent for writing code.
Jitendra Biswal: Mmhm.
Mayank: At the end of the day, any of the tool will tell that, hey, this is all good, it is the cost and everything, but…
Mayank: The final call, if the agent is good or not, will depend on me. If I define that, hey, it should always write in a modular coding, it should always give me Python with commented lines. So those are all things I will be able to then measure and handle, and then tell the agent. So just think of agent like an intern and see how will you judge him. Just that.
Jitendra Biswal: Okay, I mean, like, it means, like, I can create an agent, like, monitoring agent of agents.
Mayank: Yeah, so that is LLM as a judge. That concept is known as LLM as a jud.
Jitendra Biswal: 11…
Mayank: Yeah, where you use an LLM to check other agent or other LLM.
Mayank: So that is a concept which is known, which we will also learn because see, when the output is fuzzy, fuzzy means that it cannot like sticky. It is not a number or something which we can quantify.
Mayank: But if it is giving a code, it is not something which you can quantify, right?
Mayank: So, then we use LLM as a judge. It's a criteria via which we do this. So, we will learn LangF.
Jitendra Biswal: Mmh.
Mayank: And that would be very helpful in that.
Jitendra Biswal: Okay, okay.
Mayank: Okay, so everything will be there, just you will have to give me.
Jitendra Biswal: Yes.
Mayank: We'll be short.
Jitendra Biswal: Trying to understand the scope, I mean, whether.
Mayank: No, no, no. Totally makes sense. Totally makes.
Jitendra Biswal: Okay.
Mayank: Good.
Mayank: I'm sure… Anshul, Anshul, Anshul. Siddiq.
Anshul: Mayank, I don't have a question, I'm sorry. I think I'll probably hit the, raise.
Mayank: Yeah, yeah, you will, you will.
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: Hello Mayang, Devanya.
Mayank: Here's the window.
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: Yeah, so, well, I don't have any particular question, but, I joined this, class today, well, I, I mean, just a while ago, I missed the class, actually.
Mayank: Okay.
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: Whatever resources you have shared in the class,
Mayank: All in that link. So see, I create that link for all of my classes. It helps me to share the files and everything. And it's a very good page as well. So that is why actually I pay for this software.
Mayank: So, yeah, you can just go to that link and everything will be present. Images, PDF,
Mayank: Any prompt, most of these things will be present for you to easily go through that.
Mayank: And yeah, then you can use it.
Debanjan Mani_Laptop: I'll wait for you.
Mayank: Okay.
Siddiq: Hi, Monk.
Mayank: One minute. I have lost the window.
Mayank: So yes, it'd be higher.
Siddiq: Yeah, hi. Mayank, one thing is, like, let's say I just… I mean, I want to be, like, in terms of, like, freelancing.
Siddiq: So, I mean, what is that, that, you know, like, let's say, for example, you want me to…
Siddiq: take, like, ChatGPT subscription or, like, Claude subscription. So, what is the best resource? Like, you know, I want to build some agents or apps.
Siddiq: Because it's not.
Mayank: It's not based on any subscription, it is not based on any subscription.
Siddiq: Yeah, yeah, that's right. So the thing is, like, how you want me to proceed in this area? Like, let's say, what are the resources that…
Mayank: Okay, and it depends on what type of
Mayank: Consulting you are saying you want to do, right?
Siddiq: Yeah.
Mayank: So it depends, like, do you want to do heavy code based softwares, or you want to see, majorly you will be solving problems. Now, do you want to do it via no code approaches? Do you want to create software things? So whatever you want to create, you should have an idea about that. If you're saying that, hey, I will add AI to your solutions.
Mayank: Okay, in your tech solutions, in your non-tech solutions, to help you, like, let's say if you have a sales, I will create a
Mayank: So all those things you will have to define exactly, right?
Siddiq: Yeah, right.
Mayank: So, yeah, that is just the case, nothing else. So, whatever you want to do, you should have skills for that.
Siddiq: Any… yeah, yeah, like, skills, like, I feel like I already have, like, in terms of coding, like, data engineering and AI skills. A bit less in terms of, like, app building and, like, software designing side I have.
Siddiq: Like, less skills, and, like, how would you say, like, where do I need to start that thing? Like, what is the resource? Anything that you want to suggest?
Mayank: I don't have a single resource as such, to be honest. Like, it is all the learning part only, because it is not like that.
Mayank: We are having…
Mayank: we are… like, these things are not fixed, right? So, in India, it depends on the project. Like, for some example, you might have
Mayank: let's say… if a use case is regarding data engineering, then you should know about data engineering. The basic skill which I would want is that, yes, you are aware about what this AI agents and everything is, plus how a software basically works, any software for that matter. So that would be the basic level of skills which I would expect that all of you are having.
Siddiq: Okay, so I thought, like, for this help, like, the subscription, like, whatever I'm asking, like.
Mayank: Anyways, subscription, I think I.
Siddiq: Could help in any way.
Mayank: Then you see, it is not going to help that as such directly. If you have to still take an AI, I think right now, Claude is the best.
Mayank: That is what I feel. If you have to still purchase it, Claude is just the best.
Mayank: So, yeah.
Siddiq: Yeah, yeah, got you, yeah.
Mayank: Okay, thank you. Thank you.
Mayank: Aditi Harshitol… Aditya should… Awesome bunch.
Aditi Prakash: Amen.
Mayank: Wash, I think we talked, yeah.
Aditi Prakash: Yes. Yes. So, Meng, I'm actually very new to this AI.
Mayank: Okay.
Aditi Prakash: So, I just… I'm just a bit confused about the difference between Gen AI and Agentic AI. Like, for what I understand, Gen AI, we can also have features like tool calling memory, and certain multi-step workflows, and what makes a difference.
Mayank: Not really, actually, that is agentic, so see, GenAI now is… see, GenAI is a whole thing where you generate something.
Mayank: Osmi, you can have agent as well, but if I have to make it very easy, just think of GenAI as the brain.
Aditi Prakash: Okay.
Mayank: Agents as brain plus tools plus memory.
Mayank: Agentic AI when you're using agent to solve something. Just that.
Mayank: Simple, nothing difficult, just that. Don't make it difficult, that is the case, just…
Aditi Prakash: Okay, okay, thank you, thank you, Mike.
Mayank: Don't complex it else. Don't ever please get mixed up in the definitions. Understand how things work, and it should be fine. We don't have to write down any paper, right?
Aditi Prakash: Yes.
Mayank: So that is the case. Good.
Mayank: Shubharish, how's.
Harshit Goyal: Yeah, hi Meg, Harshit again. Just, just quick question I have. So, now we see that, this enterprise
Harshit Goyal: also provides some endpoints. For example, we see that Databricks providing, now Snowflakes is also providing, and these are also providing these, like, if you see GitHub Copilot, it also.
Mayank: Mmm.
Harshit Goyal: gives all those models. So, what is… I mean, these are the same thing, right? I mean,
Harshit Goyal: Is there any difference, or…
Mayank: No, it's wrapper on top of them. So, when you see Haiku in Claude in that, it is the same one.
Harshit Goyal: Yeah, it is, it is as same as, like, Olama is basically also giving us these.
Harshit Goyal: And, it has.
Mayank: Olama is for open source models. It's a different thing. Olama is for open source model.
Mayank: But yes, Olama is having lots of AIs which you can install and then run.
Mayank: Similarly, this GitHub Copilot, when you click on it and it shows you GPT, Claude, and all these Gemini, so it is exactly the same way we are using it, nothing else.
Harshit Goyal: Okay, and I think, from the… and it may differ from organization to organization, and then we should, from a org perspective, we should follow, whatever organization says that this is what you have to use, right, to you.
Mayank: Like, don't limit your learning based on organization.
Mayank: But try to use the tools which are there for whom your organization the best.
Mayank: Huh?
Mayank: Ramakr.
Harshit Goyal: One thing I…
Mayank: You know.
Mayank: Okay.
Harshit Goyal: Maybe, maybe I will discuss next time, no worries.
Mayank: You can ask, you can ask, it might take a.
Harshit Goyal: No, simply, I agree. Actually, we were doing some experiment, and this is about, we are trying to…
Harshit Goyal: checked some drugs, right? And so there are new trucks are coming, we are trying to
Harshit Goyal: there's a, there's a webpage where we, like, we have this drugs information, they're testing information, and what happens that, it has, it has gender-specific questions, and you know, the response comes is very, it's like a wrong website comes as a response.
Harshit Goyal: So…
Mayank: Oh my god.
Harshit Goyal: And.
Mayank: Instructions better, the brain better.
Harshit Goyal: Yeah, that's… that's what, we thought, so… okay, yeah.
Harshit Goyal: We'll discuss this later, maybe not…
Mayank: Let me, let me move and move to projects and things, and then it will be not clear.
Harshit Goyal: Right, right, exactly, exactly. Okay, thank you.
Mayank: Mamak.
Harshit Goyal: Previously.
Ramakrishna P: Hi, Mayang. I, I just wanted to know, you have created, the wrapper around the GPT, right? Yes, yes, yes.
Mayank: Yes, yes.
Ramakrishna P: So what is the process that you have followed?
Mayank: I will show that, I will show that, it's very easy, it's like hardly 10 minutes, I will show that maybe in the next class or.
Ramakrishna P: Okay, further do we need to buy, I mean,
Mayank: I think you should have at least one version of ChatGPT, Go Pro or something, not the free one, I think it is not allowed.
Ramakrishna P: Okay, okay, that is what I was trying to…
Mayank: So in the free version, I think you will not see it.
Ramakrishna P: Okay, okay. Okay. Okay, ma'am, that's…
Mayank: Quick addiction, heartache.
Mayank: You have any notes?
Hardik Vora: Thank you. Yeah, yeah. Final question. I missed it. So.
Hardik Vora: in the part which I was expecting on the semantics part. Right? So we usually have skills dot Md file as well. Right? So what exactly is required? Only the
Hardik Vora: What process of how?
Hardik Vora: The application which we have built, So, what is exactly,
Hardik Vora: In skills.md file, which we should write, so it can be reused every time, and
Mayank: Scale.md just prompt. Scale.md just.
Hardik Vora: April.
Mayank: Yeah, so rather than telling every time that, hey, do this, do that, skills.md is kind of done in that.
Mayank: In Claude, there is a skill creator skill.
Hardik Vora: Mmhm.
Mayank: Just read through it, it explains that how do you have to write, what exactly are the best practices.
Hardik Vora: Okay.
Mayank: But overall, skill.md is just prompt, in a way. It is just that, instead of
Mayank: Us going again and again and explaining things by steps, it is just having the completed, like, a blueprint, or, like, step-by-step process of doing something, nothing else.
Hardik Vora: Nothing else, right?
Mayank: Yep.
Hardik Vora: Because I had created an application where I have specifically mentioned architecture.md file separate.
Hardik Vora: Analyzing the code, I mean, readme.md files separate.
Hardik Vora: So, every time when I… I mean, the next day when I come, I just ensure that in his memory, in the context of agent, it already knows. So, I just ask him, go read the architecture and go read the README.MD file, so that you are aware, and then we can move on to the feature intake. I mean, this is…
Hardik Vora: fine, or should I specifically write skill.md.
Mayank: No, it's fine, it's fine. See, we just have to give the context. Doesn't matter from how or where it is going. Just.
Hardik Vora: That way is it also fine, right?
Mayank: Yeah.
Hardik Vora: Okay, and it will optimize its overall usage, right?
Hardik Vora: for understanding.
Mayank: Yes, of course. The better context you give in the starting, the better it will be able to give you the answer.
Hardik Vora: Got it. Thanks, yeah, yeah.
Mayank: I didn't even ask at.
Aditya Katiyar: Thank you, Mike. Mike, just a small query regarding, the server's configuration. So, suppose, I want to, configure, multiple in-house servers. So, the scenario's like, I mean, I want to just collect the…
Aditya Katiyar: different servers log and just, dump the logs into the models and, create some analysis. So, the authentication part, would…
Aditya Katiyar: I mean, where we need to… when we add the tools and… and… I mean, I just wanted to…
Mayank: Authentication with respect to keys or something?
Aditya Katiyar: Yes, not keys.
Aditya Katiyar: Our server configuration, how… Our servers…
Aditya Katiyar: get connect… I mean, that connection part, I, I'm missing…
Mayank: Where do you want to connect it.
Aditya Katiyar: so suppose I have a agent, right? So… so in the agent, we need to configure, right? So when we… when I ask, give me the, logs, insights from these four AWS servers, or some in-house servers, Linux boxes.
Aditya Katiyar: So…
Mayank: So you will have to make sure that either you are having some API or you are connecting to those servers, so that connections will be handled, right?
Aditya Katiyar: Hmm. Yeah.
Mayank: That thing, idly though DevOps people or someone from the server side does, like, idly AI engineer will not be doing it.
Aditya Katiyar: Okay.
Mayank: But it will just around the access, that what all you like to do access, for example, if you want that, hey, just go through my email, so it should be able to access your email, then keys comes into picture, or the authentic
Mayank: So that's a normal process, madam. That's how it has been always done. How do you connect different machines and everything? Nothing else.
Aditya Katiyar: So, I mean, these things we don't need to take care of is, I mean, as a part of…
Mayank: I'm really designing the.
Aditya Katiyar: agents workflow. So that's what I mean. I just.
Mayank: Tools, yes. How different servers connect and everything, not really. Because that, though, is the job of people who are in…
Aditya Katiyar: Admin and DevOps.
Mayank: Admin and DevOps idea
Mayank: Madhav, see, though I know that people want to do everything, but doing everything is also.
Aditya Katiyar: Yes.
Mayank: So I just always limit.
Mayank: If it is in a project, we will see, but unnecessarily, we will not.
Aditya Katiyar: As I said, OK.
Aditya Katiyar: Okay. Okay, fine. Thanks. Thanks. Thanks.
Mayank: Okay, thanks a lot.
Mayank: Great. So thanks a lot, everyone. That was all the doubts. Very good thing. Happy to see all the people asking doubts. I hope that with all that effort I am putting in carrying all the doubts, all of you actually spend the time and learn things in depth now.
Mayank: Let's meet in the next weekend class and start with the coding part. Most probably we will first get an easy using Python and then we will want to link in a graph. Great. Thank you.